[
    {
        "id": 1,
        "Question": "How many grams of NaCl represent 1 mole?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t23",
            "b)\t35.5",
            "c)\t58.5",
            "d)\t69.5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Molecular weight of NaCl is 58.5 grams, => 1 mole represent 58.5 grams of NaCl."
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "Question": "How many atoms of carbon represent 1.5 mole?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t6.022 X 1023",
            "b)\t1.2044 X 1023",
            "c)\t3.011 X 1023",
            "d)\t9.033 X 1023"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Number of moles = number of atoms/Avogadro’s number, => 1.5 = n/6.022 X 1023, => n = 9.033 X 1023."
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "Question": "Calculate the number of moles in 42 grams of NaHCO3?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.5",
            "b)\t1",
            "c)\t1.5",
            "d)\t2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Molecular weight of NaHCO3 = 84 grams, => number of moles = 42/84 = 0.5."
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "Question": "Calculate the number of moles in 369 grams of CaOCl2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Molecular weight of CaOCl2 = 127, => number of moles = 369/127 = 3."
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "Question": "Which of the following has the same number of moles as in 398 grams of CuSO4?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 grams of hydrogen",
            "b)\t40 grams of oxygen",
            "c)\t35 grams of nitrogen",
            "d)\t58.5 grams of Sodium chloride"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Number of moles of CuSO4 = 398/ 159 ≈ 2.5, and number of moles of oxygen = 40/16 = 2.5."
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "Question": "What are the number of atoms of chlorine in 250.5 grams of Cl2O6?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1.806 X 1024",
            "b)\t2.408 X 1024",
            "c)\t9.033 X 1023",
            "d)\t6.022 X 1023"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Number of moles of Cl2O6 = 250.5/167 = 1.5, => number of atoms of chlorine = 2*1.5*(6.022 X 1023) = 1.806 X 1024."
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "Question": "What are the number of moles of Hydrogen in 158 grams of Ammonium Bicarbonate?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5",
            "b)\t10",
            "c)\t15",
            "d)\t20"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Molecular Weight of ammonium bicarbonate (NH4HCO3) = 79 grams, => moles = 158/79 = 2, => Number of moles of hydrogen = 2* 5 = 10."
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "Question": "What are the number of moles of nitrogen in 274 grams of (NH4)2Ce(NO3)6?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t16",
            "b)\t8",
            "c)\t6",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Molecular Weight of (NH4)2Ce(NO3)6 = 548 grams, => moles of (NH4)2Ce(NO3)6 = 274/548 = 0.5, => number of moles of nitrogen = 0.5*8 = 4."
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "Question": "What are the number of moles of hydrogen in NH4[Cr(SCN)4(NH3)2] if the weight of nitrogen in it is 49 grams?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3.5",
            "b)\t5",
            "c)\t7",
            "d)\t10"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Moles of nitrogen = 49/14 = 3.5, => moles of  NH4[Cr(SCN)4(NH3)2] = 3.5/7 = 0.5, => moles of hydrogen = 0.5*10 = 5."
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "Question": "What are the number of molecules of water in CuSO4•5H2O, if the weight of oxygen in it is 36 grams?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3.25 X 1023",
            "b)\t5.25 X 1023",
            "c)\t7.52 X 1023",
            "d)\t9.52 X 1023"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Number of moles of oxygen = 36/16 =2.25, => number of moles of CuSO4•5H2O = 2.25/9 = 0.25, => number of molecules of water = 0.25*5*(6.022 X 1023) = 7.52 X 1023."
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a unit of density?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tKg/m3",
            "b)\tN/m3",
            "c)\tN.s2/m4",
            "d)\tg/cm3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Dimensions of density are M1L-3, which is not the dimension of N/m3, so N/m3 is not the unit of density."
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "Question": "What is the density of a substance of mass 10 grams and volume 5 liters?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 kg/m3",
            "b)\t20 kg/m3",
            "c)\t200 kg/m3",
            "d)\t2000 kg/m3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Density = (10*10-3)/(5*10-3) = 2 kg/m3."
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "Question": "A solid of density d is dropped in a liquid of density D, if d>D then,",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tSolid will completely sink",
            "b)\tSolid will completely float",
            "c)\tSolid will partially sink",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since the density of solid is greater than that of liquid, this means that the weight of the solid will be higher than its buoyancy force so it will completely sink."
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "Question": "A liquid of mass 10 kg is enclosed in a cylinder of radius 1 m and length 5 m, what is the density of liquid?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.54 kg/m3",
            "b)\t0.44 kg/m3",
            "c)\t0.63 kg/m3",
            "d)\t0.83 kg/m3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Volume of cylinder = π(12)5 = 5π m3, => Density = 10/5π = 0.63 kg/m3."
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "Question": "What is the density of a liquid of mass 20 kg, enclosed in a cuboid of surface areas of three sides as 1 m2, 2 m2, 5 m2, and one of its sides is 2 m?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 kg/m3",
            "b)\t2 kg/m3",
            "c)\t3 kg/m3",
            "d)\t4 kg/m3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Sides of the cuboid are 1m, 2m and 5m, => volume = 10 m3, density = 20/10 = 2 kg/m3."
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "Question": "What is the density of a liquid of mass 10 kg and contained in a cylinder of radius 5 m and surface area (excluding top and bottom) of 10π m2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.2π kg/m3",
            "b)\t0.4π kg/m3",
            "c)\t0.5π kg/m3",
            "d)\t0.6π kg/m3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Height of cylinder = 10π/(2π*5) = 1 m, => volume of cylinder = π(52)1 = 25π, => density of liquid = 10/25π = 0.4π kg/m3."
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "Question": "What is the mass of a liquid having density 20 kg/m3, enclosed in a sphere of radius 1 m?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t80.7 kg",
            "b)\t83.7 kg",
            "c)\t85.7 kg",
            "d)\t88.7 kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Volume of liquid = (4/3)π13 = 4.18 m3, => mass of liquid = 20*4.18 = 83.7 kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "Question": "What is the mass of a cube having surface area 24 m2, and density 1 kg/m3?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 kg",
            "b)\t2 kg",
            "c)\t4 kg",
            "d)\t8 kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Side of the cube = (24/6)0.5 = 2 m, => mass of cube = 1*23 = 8 kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "Question": "An empty vessel has with mass 5 kg with volume 0.1 m3, is now completely filled with a liquid of density 100 kg/m3, what is the final density of the cylinder?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t50 kg/m3",
            "b)\t100 kg/m3",
            "c)\t150 kg/m3",
            "d)\t200 kg/m3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Mass of liquid = 100*0.1 = 10 kg, => total mass of cylinder = 10 + 5 = 15 kg, => final density of liquid = 15/0.1 = 150 kg/m3."
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "Question": "A cylinder completely filled with water has density = 10 kg/m3 and volume 5 m3 , now a cube with side 1 m and density 25 kg/m3 is dipped into the cylinder with some water dropping out, what is the final density of cylinder?(neglect the mass of cylinder)",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t13 kg/m3",
            "b)\t15 kg/m3",
            "c)\t17 kg/m3",
            "d)\t19 kg/m3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Initial mass of cylinder = 10*5 = 50 kg, mass of cube = 25*1 = 25 kg, => mass of water coming out = 10*1 = 10 kg, => final density of cylinder = (50 + 25 – 10)/5 = 13 kg/m3."
    },
    {
        "id": 21,
        "Question": "What is the unit of specific gravity?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tKg/m3",
            "b)\tN/m3",
            "c)\tm/s2",
            "d)\tDimensionless"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Specific gravity of a substance is the ratio of density of the substance and density of a reference substance, so it is dimensionless."
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "Question": "What is the specific gravity of a substance with density 100 kg/m3 with respect to reference substance of density 100 lb/m3?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1.1",
            "b)\t2.2",
            "c)\t3.3",
            "d)\t4.4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Density of the substance = 100*2.2 = 220 lb/m3, Specific gravity = (100*2.2)/100 = 2.2."
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "Question": "It is necessary to mention the temperature at which specific gravity is calculated, because",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tMass of the substance changes with temperature",
            "b)\tRigidity of the substance changes with temperature",
            "c)\tDensity of the substance changes with temperature",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Since the volume of the substance changes with temperature, which means density of the substance changes with temperature, that’s why it is required to mention the temperature at which specific gravity is calculated."
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "Question": "What is the specific gravity of a substance with mass 10 kg and volume 2 m3, with respect to the reference density 50 g/m3?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.1",
            "b)\t0.2",
            "c)\t0.3",
            "d)\t0.4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Density of the substance = 10/2 = 5 kg/m3, => Specific gravity = 5/50 = 0.1."
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "Question": "What is the mass of a cone of radius 1 m and height 3 m having specific gravity 0.1? (Density of water = 1000 kg/m3)",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t314.16 kg",
            "b)\t425.24 kg",
            "c)\t136.16 kg",
            "d)\t325.24 kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Volume of cone = (1/3) π12*3 = 3.1416 m3, density of cone = 0.1*1000 = 100 kg/m3, => mass of cone = 100*3.1416 = 314.16 kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 26,
        "Question": "API gravity is measured in,",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tGravity meter scale",
            "b)\tHydrometer scale",
            "c)\tRicher scale",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: API gravity is measured in Hydrometer scale."
    },
    {
        "id": 27,
        "Question": "API gravity is necessary for the calculation of specific gravity of petroleum products, because",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tVolume of the petroleum products changes with temperature",
            "b)\tMass of petroleum products changes with temperature",
            "c)\tPotential energy of petroleum products changes with temperature",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since volume of petroleum products changes significantly with temperature, that means density of petroleum products changes significantly with temperature, so that’s why specific gravity of petroleum products changes with temperature, and that’s why API gravity is required."
    },
    {
        "id": 28,
        "Question": "What is the API gravity of a substance with specific gravity 1?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t131.5",
            "b)\t141.5",
            "c)\t10",
            "d)\t50"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: API = (141.5/sp.gr) – 131.5 = 141.5/1 – 131.5 = 10."
    },
    {
        "id": 29,
        "Question": "What is the average mass of a substance with specific gravity 10, and its volume varies with time as V = t/500, from t = 2, to t = 0 seconds? (Density of water = 1000 kg/m3)",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25",
            "b)\t20",
            "c)\t40",
            "d)\t75"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Density of substance = 10 * 1000 = 10000 kg/m3, => mass of substance = 10000*t/500 = 20t, => average mass = (1/2)∫20t = 5t2 = 5(22 – 02) = 20."
    },
    {
        "id": 30,
        "Question": "Mass of a substance is changing with respect to its volume as m = -v3 + 3v2 -2v, what is the maximum specific gravity of the substance between v = 1 m3 and v = 2 m3? (Density of reference substance = 0.25 kg/m3)",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Density of substance D = m/v = -v2 + 3v – 2, => Specific gravity of substance S = D/0.25 = 4(-v2 + 3v – 2), => dS/dv = 4(-2v + 3) = 0, => v = 1.5, => S is maximum at v = 1.5, => maximum specific gravity = 4(-1.52 + 3*1.5 – 2) = 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 31,
        "Question": "What is the specific gravity of 10 Kg of water occupied in 10 m3 with respect to 200 g/m3?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.2",
            "b)\t0.5",
            "c)\t1",
            "d)\t5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Specific gravity = (10/10)/0.2 = 5."
    },
    {
        "id": 32,
        "Question": "What is the specific gravity of 5 Kg of water occupied in 10 m3 with respect to 500 g/m3?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.5",
            "b)\t1",
            "c)\t2",
            "d)\t5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Specific gravity = (5/10)/0.5 = 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 33,
        "Question": "What is the specific gravity of 10 Kg of water occupied in 5 m3 with respect to 100 g/m3?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t5",
            "c)\t10",
            "d)\t20"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Specific gravity = (10/5)/0.1 = 20."
    },
    {
        "id": 34,
        "Question": "What is the specific gravity of O2 at 27oC and 60 Pa with respect to 1 Kg/m3?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.15",
            "b)\t0.28",
            "c)\t0.54",
            "d)\t0.76"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Specific gravity = (60*32/8.314*300)/1 = 0.76."
    },
    {
        "id": 35,
        "Question": "What is the specific gravity of N2 at 27oC and 6 Pa with respect to 0.1 Kg/m3?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.16",
            "b)\t0.33",
            "c)\t0.51",
            "d)\t0.89"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Specific gravity = (6*14/8.314*300)/0.1 = 0.33."
    },
    {
        "id": 36,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the unit of flow rate?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tKg/s",
            "b)\tLiters/s",
            "c)\tMoles/s",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Mass flow rate = m/t, => unit = kg/s, volumetric flow rate = V/t, => unit = Liters/s, molar rate = n/t, => unit = moles/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 37,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not conserved for the flow of an incompressible liquid in a pipe with variable area?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tMass",
            "b)\tVolume",
            "c)\tVelocity",
            "d)\tFlow Rate"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: According to the equation of continuity, the product of area and velocity remains constant throughout the pipe, since the area of the pipe is variable, so the velocity if the liquid is variable."
    },
    {
        "id": 38,
        "Question": "What is the mass flow rate of a liquid flowing through a pipe of which 100 grams of water was collected in 10 seconds?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.01 kg/s",
            "b)\t0.05 kg/s",
            "c)\t0.1 kg/s",
            "d)\t0.5 kg/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: mass flow rate = 0.1/ 10 = 0.01 kg/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 39,
        "Question": "What is the volumetric flow rate if 100 kg of water is collected in 10 seconds? (Density of water = 1000 kg/m3)",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.1 m3/s",
            "b)\t0.2 m3/s",
            "c)\t0.01 m3/s",
            "d)\t0.02 m3/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: volume of water collected = 100/1000 = 0.1 m3, => volumetric flow rate = 0.1/10 = 0.01 m3/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 40,
        "Question": "A liquid is flowing through a pipe of cross section 4 m2 at a rate of 4 kg/s, at a point pipe is divided into two pipes of areas of equal areas, what will be the ratio of flow rate in both the pipes?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1:3",
            "b)\t1:1",
            "c)\t1:2",
            "d)\t2:3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since areas of the pipes are equal, by continuity equation flow will divide equally in the pipes, so their ratio will be 1:1."
    },
    {
        "id": 41,
        "Question": "The velocity of water in a pipe of area 5 m2 is 10 m/s, what will be the flow rate of water?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25 m3/s",
            "b)\t50 m3/s",
            "c)\t75 m3/s",
            "d)\t100 m3/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Flow rate = area*velocity = 5*10 = 50 m3/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 42,
        "Question": "A liquid of density 0.1 kg/m3 is flowing through a pipe at a rate of 15 kg/s, what will be the area of the pipe if the fluid velocity is 5 m/s?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t30 m2",
            "b)\t45 m2",
            "c)\t75 m2",
            "d)\t90 m2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Volumetric flow rate of the liquid = 15/0.1 = 150 m3/s, => Area of pipe = 150/5 = 30 m2."
    },
    {
        "id": 43,
        "Question": "1 mole of Carbon dioxide enters in a reactor at a rate of 0.25 kg/s and leaves it at the rate of 1 kg/s, what are the number of moles of carbon dioxide leaves the reactor?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.25",
            "b)\t0.5",
            "c)\t0.75",
            "d)\t1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Applying reaction equilibrium equation, 1*0.25 = n*1, => n = 0.25."
    },
    {
        "id": 44,
        "Question": "A Composition of carbon dioxide, oxygen and nitrogen with mole ratio 1:2:5 with 4 moles of oxygen, enters a reactor with a flow rate of 100 kg/s, the ratio of rates of leaving the reactor of the three is 5:2:1, and 5 moles of nitrogen leaves the reactor, what is the total number of moles leaving the reactor?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t6.1",
            "b)\t6.2",
            "c)\t6.3",
            "d)\t6.4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: number of moles of carbon dioxide, oxygen and nitrogen are 2, 4 and 10 respectively, let the leaving flow rates of carbon dioxide, oxygen and nitrogen are 5y, 2y and y respectively, => for nitrogen, 10*100 = y*5 => y = 200 kg/s, => for oxygen, 4*100 = 400*n => n = 1, for carbon dioxide, 2*100 = 1000*n => n = 0.2, => total number of moles leaving the reactor = 5 + 1 + 0.2 = 6.2."
    },
    {
        "id": 45,
        "Question": "10 moles of oxygen divides and enters two reactors flow rate 45 kg/s and leaves the reactors at the flow rates of 6 kg/s and 9 kg/s, what are number of moles of oxygen that leaves the reactor with 9 kg/s?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t180",
            "b)\t450",
            "c)\t60",
            "d)\t90"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Let number of moles entering and leaving the second reactor be n1 and n2 respectively, applying reaction equilibrium equation to whole system, => 10*45 = n*(6 + 9), => n = 30, => Applying reaction equilibrium equation to both the reactors separately, => n1*45 = n2*9 => n2 = 5n1, and (10 – n1)*45 = (30 – n2)*6, Solving both equations we get n2 = 90."
    },
    {
        "id": 46,
        "Question": "10 Kg/s of a fluid with density 10 Kg/m3 is passed into a tank of capacity 50 m3, how much time will it take to fill the tank?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 Second",
            "b)\t50 Second",
            "c)\t500 Second",
            "d)\t5000 Second"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Flow rate of fluid = 10/10 = 1 m3/s, => Time = 50/1 = 50 second."
    },
    {
        "id": 47,
        "Question": "15 Kg/s of a fluid with density 5 Kg/m3 is passed into a tank of capacity 30 m3, how much time will it take to fill the tank?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3 Second",
            "b)\t10 Second",
            "c)\t30 Second",
            "d)\t100 Second"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Flow rate of fluid = 15/5 = 3 m3/s, => Time = 30/3 = 10 second."
    },
    {
        "id": 48,
        "Question": "20 Kg/s of a fluid with density 5 Kg/m3 is passed into a tank of capacity 60 m3, how much time will it take to fill the tank?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 Second",
            "b)\t10 Second",
            "c)\t15 Second",
            "d)\t20 Second"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Flow rate of fluid = 20/5 = 4 m3/s, => Time = 60/4 = 15 second."
    },
    {
        "id": 49,
        "Question": "16 grams of oxygen is passed in the process in 5 minutes, what is the molar flow rate?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.1 mole/min",
            "b)\t1 mole/min",
            "c)\t10 mole/min",
            "d)\t16 mole/min"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Flow rate of fluid = (16/32)/5 = 0.1 mole/min."
    },
    {
        "id": 50,
        "Question": "24 grams of CH4 is passed in the process in 3 minutes, what is the molar flow rate?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.1 mole/min",
            "b)\t0.3 mole/min",
            "c)\t0.5 mole/min",
            "d)\t0.7 mole/min"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Flow rate of fluid = (24/16)/3 = 0.5 mole/min."
    },
    {
        "id": 51,
        "Question": "What is the mole fraction of sodium with moles n in a solution with moles of solvent N?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tN/n",
            "b)\tn/N",
            "c)\tn/(n + N)",
            "d)\tN/(n + N)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Mole fraction is the ratio of moles of solvent and the total number of moles of solution, => mole fraction = n/(n + N)."
    },
    {
        "id": 52,
        "Question": "What is the unit of mole fraction?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tKg/m3",
            "b)\tN/m3",
            "c)\tm-2",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Since the mole fraction is ratio of the moles of solute and the moles of solution, it has no unit."
    },
    {
        "id": 53,
        "Question": "If the mole fraction of 4.5 moles of solute is 0.5, what is the number of moles of solvent?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t9",
            "b)\t4.5",
            "c)\t1.5",
            "d)\t3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 0.5 = 4.5/(4.5 + n), => n = 4.5."
    },
    {
        "id": 54,
        "Question": "What is the mass fraction of 4 moles of Sodium in 8 moles of Hydrogen chloride?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.24",
            "b)\t0.48",
            "c)\t0.56",
            "d)\t0.72"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Mass of sodium = 4*23 = 92 g, mass of hydrogen chloride = 8*36.5 = 292 g, => mass fraction of sodium = 92/(92 + 292) = 0.24."
    },
    {
        "id": 55,
        "Question": "If the mole fraction of sodium is 0.25 in 9 moles of liquid carbon dioxide, what is the mass fraction of sodium?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.10",
            "b)\t0.15",
            "c)\t0.20",
            "d)\t0.25"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 0.25 = n/(n + 9), => n = 3, => mass of sodium = 3*23/(3*23 + 9*44) = 0.15."
    },
    {
        "id": 56,
        "Question": "A solution has 25% w/w solution of Sodium Chloride in 10 grams of water what is the mole fraction of Sodium Chloride?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.05",
            "b)\t0.06",
            "c)\t0.07",
            "d)\t0.08"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Mass of sodium chloride = 10*25/100 = 2.5 grams, => moles of sodium chloride = 2.5/58.5 = 0.0427, moles of water = 10/18 = 0.555, => mole fraction = 0.0427/(0.0427 + 0.555) = 0.07."
    },
    {
        "id": 57,
        "Question": "If the mole fraction of SO2 in H2SO4 is 0.2, what is the ratio of mass of sulfur and oxygen in the solution?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.166",
            "b)\t6",
            "c)\t1.8",
            "d)\t0.555"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Let moles of SO2 and H2SO4 be x and y respectively, => x/(x + y) = 0.2, => y/x = 4, => ratio of mass of sulfur and oxygen in solution = (x*32 + y*32)/ (x*2(16) + y*4(16)) = 0.555."
    },
    {
        "id": 58,
        "Question": "A mixture of gases SO2, O2 and 4 g of N2 and total mass of mixture is 10 g, what is the sum of mole fraction of SO2 and O2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.25",
            "b)\t0.5",
            "c)\t0.75",
            "d)\t1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Sum of the mole fraction of all gases = 1, => sum of mole fraction of SO2 and O2 = 1 – 4/10 = 0.75."
    },
    {
        "id": 59,
        "Question": "A neutral gas that is made of nitrogen and hydrogen only contains 7 g of nitrogen is in a mixture of with total mass 17 g, what is the mass fraction of the gas?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.5",
            "b)\t0.25",
            "c)\t0.45",
            "d)\t0.8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The neutral gas that is made of nitrogen and hydrogen is NH3, => moles of nitrogen = moles of NH3 = 7/14 = 0.5, => mass of hydrogen = 1.5*1 = 1.5 g => total mass of NH3 = 7 + 1.5 = 8.5 g, => mass fraction = 8.5/17 = 0.5."
    },
    {
        "id": 60,
        "Question": "A mixture contains 23 g of ethanol and 36 g of water, some acetic acid is added to the mixture and its mole fraction becomes 0.5, how much acetic acid was added?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25 g",
            "b)\t75 g",
            "c)\t100 g",
            "d)\t150 g"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Let m grams of acetic acid was added, => 0.5 = (m/60)/{(23/46) + (36/18) + (m/60)}, => m = 150 g."
    },
    {
        "id": 61,
        "Question": "A mixture contains 9 gram each of H2O and NaCl, what is the mole fraction of NaCl?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.15",
            "b)\t0.23",
            "c)\t0.45",
            "d)\t0.64"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Mole fraction of NaCl = (9/58.5)/[9/58.5 + 9/18] = 0.23."
    },
    {
        "id": 62,
        "Question": "A mixture contains 10 grams each of CH4, H2O, and SO2, what is the mole fraction of CH4?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.14",
            "b)\t0.31",
            "c)\t0.46",
            "d)\t0.67"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Mole fraction of CH4 = (10/16)/[(10/16) + (10/18) + (10/64)] = 0.46."
    },
    {
        "id": 63,
        "Question": "A mixture contains 80% of HCl and 20% H2O by weight, what is the mole fraction of HCl?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.15",
            "b)\t0.29",
            "c)\t0.45",
            "d)\t0.66"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Mole fraction of HCl = (80/36.5)/[(80/36.5) + (20/18)] = 0.66."
    },
    {
        "id": 64,
        "Question": "A mixture contains 80% of NaOH and 20% H2O by weight, what is the mole fraction of NaOH?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.24",
            "b)\t0.42",
            "c)\t0.64",
            "d)\t0.78"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Mole fraction of HCl = (80/40)[(80/40) + (20/18)] = 0.64."
    },
    {
        "id": 65,
        "Question": "A compound contains 40% of Sulphur and 60% of Oxygen, what is the empirical formula of the compound?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tSO2",
            "b)\tSO3",
            "c)\tSO4",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Mole fraction of Sulphur = (40/32)[(40/32) + (60/16)] = 0.25, => Mole fraction of oxygen = 0.75, => Empirical formula of compound is SO3."
    },
    {
        "id": 66,
        "Question": "What is the molecular weight of a mixture that contains 25% CO2, 40% O2 and 35% N2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t11.2 g",
            "b)\t22.4 g",
            "c)\t33.6 g",
            "d)\t44.8 g"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Molecular weight = (25*44 + 40*32 + 35*28)/100 = 33.6 g."
    },
    {
        "id": 67,
        "Question": "What is the weight of 10 moles of a mixture with composition 15% O2, 25% SO2, 30% COCl2, 25% SO3 and 5% N2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t124",
            "b)\t345",
            "c)\t507",
            "d)\t719"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Molecular weight of mixture = (15*32 + 25*64 + 30*99 + 25*80 + 5*28)/100 = 71.9, => Weight of mixture = 71.9*10 = 719."
    },
    {
        "id": 68,
        "Question": "If a compound contains 48% of Carbon, 48% of oxygen and 8% of hydrogen by weight, then what is the possible molecular formula of the compound?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tC2H4O",
            "b)\tCH4O3",
            "c)\tC4H4O3",
            "d)\tC4H8O3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Ratio of number of atoms, Carbon: Hydrogen: Oxygen = 48/12: 8/1: 48/16 = 4:8:3."
    },
    {
        "id": 69,
        "Question": "A compound contain 12% of carbon, 16% of oxygen, 28% of nitrogen, 4% of hydrogen and 40% calcium by weight, then what can be the possible formula of the compound?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tC2H3N2Ca(OH)",
            "b)\tCH4N4Ca2(OH)",
            "c)\tCH3N2Ca2(OH)",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Ration of number of atoms, carbon: hydrogen: oxygen: nitrogen: calcium = 12/12: 4/1: 16/16: 28/14: 40/20 = 1:4:1:2:2."
    },
    {
        "id": 70,
        "Question": "What is the value of x in C2H8(OH)x if the percentage by weight of hydrogen is 12%?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Let the total weight of the compound be 100 g, => weight of hydrogen in the compound is 12 g, => x = 12 – 8 = 4."
    },
    {
        "id": 71,
        "Question": "If hydrogen is 14% by weight in CH3(OH)x(NH3)y, then what is the possible value of x*y?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t6",
            "b)\t12",
            "c)\t18",
            "d)\t24"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Let the weight of compound be 100 g, => weight of hydrogen = 14 g, => 3y + x + 3 = 14 => 3y + x = 11, => and 12 + 14 + 16x + 14y = 100, => 8x + 7y = 37, solving both equations we get x = 2 and y = 3, => x*y = 6."
    },
    {
        "id": 72,
        "Question": "A liquid mixture of O2, CH4 and CO has the composition 32% O2, 16% CH4 and 52% CO, then what is the mole fraction of CH4?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.1",
            "b)\t0.2",
            "c)\t0.25",
            "d)\t0.5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Let the total weight of the mixture be 100 g, => weight of each component are 32 g, 16 g and 52 g respectively, => moles of O2 = 32/16 = 2, moles of CH4 = 16/16 = 1, moles of CO = 52/26 = 2 g, => mole fraction of CH4 = 1/5 = 0.2."
    },
    {
        "id": 73,
        "Question": "A gaseous mixture is composed of 20% CO2, 40% O2 and 40% N2. What is the mass fraction of N2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.307",
            "b)\t0.416",
            "c)\t0.529",
            "d)\t0.784"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Let the total moles of the mixture be 100, => mass of CO2 = 20*44 = 880 g, mass of ¬O2 = 40*16 = 640 g, mass of N2 = 40*14 = 560 g, => mass fraction of N2 = 560/(880 + 640 + 560) = 0.307."
    },
    {
        "id": 74,
        "Question": "A liquid mixture composed of 20% CH4, 30% C2H4, 35% C2H2, and 15% C2H2O. What is the average molecular weight of the mixture?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20",
            "b)\t25",
            "c)\t6.75",
            "d)\t9.25"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since it is a liquid mixture so the percentages are by weight, => average molecular weight of mixture = (20 + 30 + 35 + 15)/4 =25."
    },
    {
        "id": 75,
        "Question": "A gaseous mixture composed of 20% CH4, 30% C2H4, 35% C2H2, and 15% C2H2O. What is the average molecular weight of the mixture?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20",
            "b)\t25",
            "c)\t6.75",
            "d)\t9.25"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Since it is a gaseous mixture so the percentages are by mole, => average molecular weight of mixture = {(20/100)*16 + (30/100)*28 + (35/100)*26 + (15/100)*42}/4 = 6.75."
    },
    {
        "id": 76,
        "Question": "The mole percent of H2 and N2 in a mixture is 50% each, what is the mass percentage of H2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12.5",
            "b)\t25",
            "c)\t50",
            "d)\t87.5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Let the moles be 50 each, => Mass of H2 = 100, Mass of N2 = 700, => Mass percentage of H2 = 100/(100 + 700)*100 = 12.5%."
    },
    {
        "id": 77,
        "Question": "The mole percent of CO2 and H2O in a mixture is 40% and 60% respectively, what is the mass percent of CO2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t24.1",
            "b)\t47.2",
            "c)\t61.9",
            "d)\t78.5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Let the moles be 40 and 60, => mass of CO2 = 40*44 = 1760, mass of H2O = 1080, => mass percent of CO2 = 61.9%."
    },
    {
        "id": 78,
        "Question": "A mixture contains 20% CO2, 30% SO2 and 50% H2O, what is the mass percent of CO2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t23",
            "b)\t45",
            "c)\t66",
            "d)\t87"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Let the moles be 20, 30 and 50, => mass percent of CO2 = (20*44)/[20*44 + 30*64 + 50*18] = 23%."
    },
    {
        "id": 79,
        "Question": "A mixture contains 20% NaCl, 30% CH4 and 50% H2O, what is the mass percent of NaCl?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t21",
            "b)\t34",
            "c)\t45",
            "d)\t68"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Mass percent of NaCl = 20*35.5/[20*35.5 + 30*16 + 50*18] = 34%."
    },
    {
        "id": 80,
        "Question": "A mixture contains 10% CO, 40% CO2 and 50% H2O, what is the mass percent of CO2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t9.5",
            "b)\t15.4",
            "c)\t39.5",
            "d)\t74.1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Mass percent of CO2 = 10*28/[10*28 + 40*44 + 50*18] = 9.5%."
    },
    {
        "id": 81,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not the unit of concentration?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tMole/m3",
            "b)\tMolar",
            "c)\tN/m3",
            "d)\tppm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Concentration is moles per unit volume or mass per unit volume, so N/m3 cannot be a unit of concentration."
    },
    {
        "id": 82,
        "Question": "What is the concentration of a 22 grams of carbon dioxide occupying 0.5 m3 volume?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 mole/m3",
            "b)\t2 mole/m3",
            "c)\t11 mole/m3",
            "d)\t22 mole/m3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Moles of carbon dioxide = 22/44 = 0.5, => concentration = 0.5/0.5 = 1 mole/m3."
    },
    {
        "id": 83,
        "Question": "What is the concentration of 100 lbs. of solution occupying 25 m3 of volume?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1.8 Kg/m3",
            "b)\t2.7 Kg/m3",
            "c)\t4 Kg/m3",
            "d)\t8 Kg/m3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Mass of solution = 100*0.453 = 45.3 kg, => Concentration of solution = 45.3/25 = 1.8 kg/m3."
    },
    {
        "id": 84,
        "Question": "What is the molarity of a solution with a mass of solute 10 kg mass and 100 liter volume?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.1 molar",
            "b)\t1 molar",
            "c)\t10 molar",
            "d)\t100 molar"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Molarity = 10/100 = 0.1 molar."
    },
    {
        "id": 85,
        "Question": "What is the concentration of a solution with 10 grams of calcium in 1000 m3 of water?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t150 ppm",
            "b)\t250 ppm",
            "c)\t800 ppm",
            "d)\t1000 ppm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Moles of calcium = 10/40 =0.25, => concentration in ppm = (0.25/1000)*106 = 250 ppm."
    },
    {
        "id": 86,
        "Question": "How much Sodium is there in a solution with 10 Kg of solvent (Density = 5 Kg/m3) and concentration 4 molar?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t23 grams",
            "b)\t92 grams",
            "c)\t184 grams",
            "d)\t276 grams"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Volume of solvent = 10/5 = 2 m3, => moles of sodium = 4*2 = 8 moles, => mass of sodium = 8*23 = 184 grams."
    },
    {
        "id": 87,
        "Question": "A 5 molar solution is 27.75% CaCl2 by mass, what is the density of the solution?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 g/cm3",
            "b)\t2 g/cm3",
            "c)\t3 g/cm3",
            "d)\t4 g/cm3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Let the mass of Solution be 100 grams, => moles of CaCl2 = 27.75/111 = 0.25, Density of solution = 5*(100/0.25) = 2000 kg/m3 = 2 g/cm3."
    },
    {
        "id": 88,
        "Question": "A solution with density 1 g/cm3 has 98 grams of H2SO4 in 402 grams of water, what is the concentration of solution?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 molar",
            "b)\t2 molar",
            "c)\t3 molar",
            "d)\t4 molar"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Moles of H2SO4 = 98/98 = 1, => concentration of solution = 1/(500/1) = 2*10-6 mole/cm3 = 2 molar."
    },
    {
        "id": 89,
        "Question": "A solution with density 2 g/cm3, concentration 1 molar and weight 500 grams, then what is the mass of HNO3 in the solution?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t63 grams",
            "b)\t126 grams",
            "c)\t189 grams",
            "d)\t252 grams"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Moles of HNO3 = 1/(500/2000) = 4, = > mass of HNO3 = 4*63 = 252 grams."
    },
    {
        "id": 90,
        "Question": "What is the molarity of the mixture of two solution, first solution 4 M and 10 liter and second solution 2 M and 40 liter?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1.2 M",
            "b)\t2.4 M",
            "c)\t4.8 M",
            "d)\t9.2 M"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Molarity of mixture = (M1V1 + M2V2)/(V1 + V2) = (4*10 + 2*40)/ (10 + 40) = 2.4 M."
    },
    {
        "id": 91,
        "Question": "What is the molar concentration of a solution with 40 gram of NaOH in 1 liter solution?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 mole/liter",
            "b)\t2 mole/liter",
            "c)\t3 mole/liter",
            "d)\t4 mole/liter"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Molar concentration = (40/40)/1 = 1 mole/liter."
    },
    {
        "id": 92,
        "Question": "What is the molar concentration of a solution with 32 grams of CH4 in 1 liter solution?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 mole/liter",
            "b)\t2 mole/liter",
            "c)\t3 mole/liter",
            "d)\t4 mole/liter"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Molar concentration = (32/16)/1 = 2 mole/liter."
    },
    {
        "id": 93,
        "Question": "What is the molar concentration of a solution with 44 grams of CO2 in 0.5 liter solution?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 mole/liter",
            "b)\t2 mole/liter",
            "c)\t3 mole/liter",
            "d)\t4 mole/liter"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Molar concentration = (44/44)/0.5 = 2 mole/liter."
    },
    {
        "id": 94,
        "Question": "What is the molar concentration of a solution with 32 grams of SO2 in 0.5 liter solution?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 mole/liter",
            "b)\t2 mole/liter",
            "c)\t3 mole/liter",
            "d)\t4 mole/liter"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Molar concentration = (32/64)/0.5 = 1 mole/liter."
    },
    {
        "id": 95,
        "Question": "What is the molar concentration of a solution with 49 grams of H2SO4 in 0.5 liter solution?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 mole/liter",
            "b)\t2 mole/liter",
            "c)\t3 mole/liter",
            "d)\t4 mole/liter"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Molar concentration = (49/98)/0.5 = 1 mole/liter."
    },
    {
        "id": 96,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a unit of temperature?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tCelsius",
            "b)\tFahrenheit",
            "c)\tTherm",
            "d)\tRankine"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Them is a unit of energy, 1 therm = 105 BTU."
    },
    {
        "id": 97,
        "Question": "Which of the following is greatest?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10oC",
            "b)\t10oR",
            "c)\t10oF",
            "d)\t10 K"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: 10oC = 283 K = 50oF = 510oR, => 10oC is greatest."
    },
    {
        "id": 98,
        "Question": "Absolute zero temperature is approximately equal to?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-160oR",
            "b)\t-273oR",
            "c)\t-373oR",
            "d)\t-460oR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Absolute zero temperature = 0 K = -273oC = -460oR."
    },
    {
        "id": 99,
        "Question": "If change in temperate is 212 degree Fahrenheit, what is the change in temperature in degree Rankine?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t100oR",
            "b)\t212oR",
            "c)\t273oR",
            "d)\t460oR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since ∆TR = ∆TF, => 212oF = 212oR."
    },
    {
        "id": 100,
        "Question": "If change in temperate is 180 degree Rankine, what is the change in temperature in degree Celsius?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t100oC",
            "b)\t180oC",
            "c)\t212oC",
            "d)\t273oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ∆TR = 1.8∆TC, => Change in temperature = 180/1.8 = 100oC."
    },
    {
        "id": 101,
        "Question": "Let us say temperature of a body in degree Celsius and degree Rankine are related as TC = 50 + 3TR, what is the change in temperature in Kelvin, if the change in temperature in degree Rankine is 100oR?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t300 K",
            "b)\t180 K",
            "c)\t100 K",
            "d)\t90 K"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ∆TC = 3∆TR, => ∆TC = 3*100 = 300oC, => ∆TK = ∆TC = 300 K."
    },
    {
        "id": 102,
        "Question": "What is the value of 100oC in degree Fahrenheit?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t212oF",
            "b)\t460oF",
            "c)\t672oF",
            "d)\t884oF"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: TF = (9/5)100 + 32 = 212oF."
    },
    {
        "id": 103,
        "Question": "What is the value of 273 K in degree Rankine?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0oR",
            "b)\t32oR",
            "c)\t492oR",
            "d)\t672oR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: TR = (9/5)(273 – 273) + 492 = 492oR."
    },
    {
        "id": 104,
        "Question": "Volume of an object is dependent upon its temperature in degree Celsius as V = a + bTC, what is the dependence of volume upon temperature in degree Rankine?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tV = a + 32b + 9bTR/5",
            "b)\tV = a + 492b + 9bTR/5",
            "c)\tV = a + 492b + 5bTR/9",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: TC = 492 + 9TR/5, => V = a + b(492 + 9TR/5), => V = a + 492b + 9bTR/5."
    },
    {
        "id": 105,
        "Question": "Mass and volume of an object is dependent on its temperature in kelvin as m = 5t2 kg and v = (400 + 600t) m3 respectively, then what is the density of the object at t = 27oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t 5 kg/m3",
            "b)\t10 kg/m3",
            "c)\t15 kg/m3",
            "d)\t20 kg/m3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Density of object = dm/dv = (dm/dt)/(dv/dt) = 10t/600 = t/60, => density of object at t = 27oC = 300 K is D = 300/60 = 5 kg/m3."
    },
    {
        "id": 106,
        "Question": "Heat capacity of a substance is given by C = 800 – 1600T + 25T2, where T is temperature in degree Fahrenheit, what is the heat capacity if temperature is in degree Celsius?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t81T2 + 24800",
            "b)\t81T2 – 24800",
            "c)\t25T2 + 24800",
            "d)\t25T2 – 24800"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Temperature in degree Fahrenheit, TF = (9/5)TC + 32, replacing TF in C, => C = 81T2 – 24800."
    },
    {
        "id": 107,
        "Question": "Heat capacity of a substance is given by C = BT2, where T is in degree Fahrenheit and the value of B is 50, what is the value of B if T is in degree Celsius?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t81",
            "b)\t25",
            "c)\t162",
            "d)\t100"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: TF = 9TF/5 + 32 => coefficient of T2 in C will be B*(9/5)2 = 50*81/25 = 162."
    },
    {
        "id": 108,
        "Question": "What is the temperature 100oC in degree Rankine?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t100oR",
            "b)\t212oR",
            "c)\t560oC",
            "d)\t672oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Temperature = 9(100)/5 + 32 + 460 = 672oR."
    },
    {
        "id": 109,
        "Question": "What is the 100oC in degree Fahrenheit?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0oF",
            "b)\t100oF",
            "c)\t212oF",
            "d)\t460oF"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Temperature = 9(100)/5 + 32 = 212oF."
    },
    {
        "id": 110,
        "Question": "What is the 40oF in degree Rankine?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t313oR",
            "b)\t460oR",
            "c)\t500oR",
            "d)\t672oR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Temperature = 40 + 460 = 500oR."
    },
    {
        "id": 111,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a unit of pressure?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tBar",
            "b)\tN/m2",
            "c)\tKg/m2",
            "d)\tTorr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Pressure is force per unit area so Kg/m2 cannot be a unit of pressure."
    },
    {
        "id": 112,
        "Question": "What is the value of 760 Torr in Pascal?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1.01325 X 105",
            "b)\t6.025 X 105",
            "c)\t12.05 X 104",
            "d)\t3.0125 X 105"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: 760 Torr = 1 atm = 1.01325 X 105."
    },
    {
        "id": 113,
        "Question": "How many Pascal does 1 bar have?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t104",
            "b)\t105",
            "c)\t106",
            "d)\t107"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 1 bar = 100 kPa = 105 Pa."
    },
    {
        "id": 114,
        "Question": "Which of the following equals 760 mm of Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 atm",
            "b)\t1 Pa",
            "c)\t1 bar",
            "d)\t1 torr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: 760 mm of Hg = 101.325 kPa = 1 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 115,
        "Question": "1 psi equals how many kilopascal?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5.249",
            "b)\t6.894",
            "c)\t7.489",
            "d)\t8.846"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 1 psi = 6894 Pa = 6.894 kPa."
    },
    {
        "id": 116,
        "Question": "What is the pressure of 50 kPa in bars?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.25",
            "b)\t0.5",
            "c)\t1",
            "d)\t2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Pressure = 50/100 = 0.5 bar."
    },
    {
        "id": 117,
        "Question": "What is the pressure of 200 kPa in bars?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.25",
            "b)\t0.5",
            "c)\t1",
            "d)\t2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Pressure = 200/100 = 2 bar."
    },
    {
        "id": 118,
        "Question": "What is the pressure of 380 torr in atm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.5",
            "b)\t1",
            "c)\t2",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Pressure = 380/760 = 0.5 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 119,
        "Question": "What is the pressure of 190 torr in atm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.25",
            "b)\t0.5",
            "c)\t0.8",
            "d)\t1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Pressure = 190/760 = 0.25 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 120,
        "Question": "What is the pressure of 38 mm Hg in atm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.05",
            "b)\t0.5",
            "c)\t1",
            "d)\t5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Pressure = 38/760 = 0.05 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 121,
        "Question": "What is the pressure of 1900 mm Hg in atm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.5",
            "b)\t1",
            "c)\t1.5",
            "d)\t2.5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Pressure = 1900/760 = 2.5 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 122,
        "Question": "What is the pressure of 19 mm Hg in pascal?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1012",
            "b)\t2533",
            "c)\t3654",
            "d)\t6412"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Pressure = 19/760*101325 = 2533 Pa."
    },
    {
        "id": 123,
        "Question": "What is the pressure of 38 mm Hg in Torr?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.05",
            "b)\t0.5",
            "c)\t1",
            "d)\t38"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Pressure = 38 Torr."
    },
    {
        "id": 124,
        "Question": "What is the pressure of 380 Torr in bar?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.13",
            "b)\t0.49",
            "c)\t0.5",
            "d)\t1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Pressure = 380/760*100000/101325 = 0.49 bar."
    },
    {
        "id": 125,
        "Question": "What is the pressure of 1900 Torr in bar?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2.1",
            "b)\t2.3",
            "c)\t2.4",
            "d)\t2.5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Pressure = 1900/760*100000/101325 = 2.4 bar."
    },
    {
        "id": 126,
        "Question": "What is the pressure if 10 N of force is acting normally on 5 m2 surface area?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 Pa",
            "b)\t4 Pa",
            "c)\t8 Pa",
            "d)\t10 Pa"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Pressure = 10/5 = 2Pa."
    },
    {
        "id": 127,
        "Question": "What is the pressure if 10 N of force acts at 60 degrees from the normal of a 5 m2 surface?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.5 Pa",
            "b)\t1 Pa",
            "c)\t2 Pa",
            "d)\t4 Pa"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Normal component of the force = 10cos60o = 10*0.5 = 5 N, => Pressure = 5/5 = 1 Pa."
    },
    {
        "id": 128,
        "Question": "What is the pressure if 10 N of force acts at 30 degrees from the surface of area 5 m2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 Pa",
            "b)\t2 Pa",
            "c)\t5 Pa",
            "d)\t10 Pa"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Normal component of the force = 10sin30o = 10*0.5 = 5 N, => Pressure = 5/5 = 1 Pa."
    },
    {
        "id": 129,
        "Question": "What is the pressure of 1 mole of an ideal gas at 27oC occupying 1 Liter of volume?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12.31 atm",
            "b)\t24.63 atm",
            "c)\t36.95 atm",
            "d)\t48.94 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For ideal gas PV = nRT, => P = 1*0.0821*300/1 = 24.63 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 130,
        "Question": "An open tank 10 m deep is completely filled with a liquid of density 5 kg/m3, what is the pressure difference at the top and bottom?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t100 N/m2",
            "b)\t250 N/m2",
            "c)\t500 N/m2",
            "d)\t1000 N/m2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Pressure difference = dgh = 5*10*10 = 500 N/m2."
    },
    {
        "id": 131,
        "Question": "10 mm of water (density = 1000 kg/m3) and 5 mm of a liquid has the same pressure drop, what is the density of liquid?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t500 kg/m3",
            "b)\t1000 kg/m3",
            "c)\t1500 kg/m3",
            "d)\t2000 kg/m3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: pressure of water = pressure of liquid, => d1h1 = d2h2, => 10*1000 = 5*d2, => d = 2000 kg/m3."
    },
    {
        "id": 132,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a pressure measuring device?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tManometer",
            "b)\tBarometer",
            "c)\tGalvanometer",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Galvanometer is used to measure current."
    },
    {
        "id": 133,
        "Question": "Bernoulli’s Equation is the conservation of?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tEnergy",
            "b)\tMomentum",
            "c)\tPressure",
            "d)\tMass"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Bernoulli’s equation is modified form of conservation of energy equation."
    },
    {
        "id": 134,
        "Question": "What is the pressure difference of the ends of a U-tube manometer filled with liquid (density = 10 kg/m3) the difference in the height of the liquid in the tubes is 5 cm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 N/m2",
            "b)\t10 N/m2",
            "c)\t15 N/m2",
            "d)\t20 N/m2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Pressure difference = dgh = 10*10*0.05 = 5 N/m2."
    },
    {
        "id": 135,
        "Question": "A hydraulic lever has input surface area 2 m2, and output surface area 10 m2, if the input force is 5 N, then what is the output force?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 N",
            "b)\t2 N",
            "c)\t5 N",
            "d)\t10 N"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Hydraulic lever works on the Pascal’s principle, => F1A1 = F2A2, => 5*2 = F2*10, => F2 = 1 N."
    },
    {
        "id": 136,
        "Question": "A Closed U-tube manometer has a gas at one end and vacuum at other end, if the height difference of the liquid (density = 10 kg/m3) in the manometer in 5 cm, what is the pressure of the gas?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 N/m2",
            "b)\t5 N/m2",
            "c)\t2.5 N/m2",
            "d)\t1 N/m2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Pressure of the gas = dgh = 10*10*0.05 = 5 N/m2."
    },
    {
        "id": 137,
        "Question": "Archimedes’ principle describes which of the following quantities?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tPressure",
            "b)\tBuoyancy",
            "c)\tVelocity",
            "d)\tMass"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Archimedes’ principle states that buoyant force on a body is equal to the weight of the body."
    },
    {
        "id": 138,
        "Question": "An object is dipped in water, if the weight of the object measured by spring balance is 10 g and buoyancy force acting on the object is 0.1 N then what is the actual mass of the object?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 g",
            "b)\t20 g",
            "c)\t30 g",
            "d)\t40 g"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Weight of the object = (10*10–3)*10 + 0.1 = 0.2 N, => actual mass of the object = 0.2/10 = 0.02 kg = 20 g."
    },
    {
        "id": 139,
        "Question": "An open end manometer is filled with a gas on one end and other end is open to atmosphere with height difference of liquid (density = 10000 Kg/m3) 10 cm, what is the pressure of gas?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 atm",
            "b)\t1.1 atm",
            "c)\t1.2 atm",
            "d)\t1.3 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Pressure = 1 + 10000*10*0.1/101325 = 1.1 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 140,
        "Question": "A closed end manometer is filled with a gas on one end and other end is close with vacuum, height difference of liquid (density = 10000 Kg/m3) 25 cm, what is the pressure of gas?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.1 atm",
            "b)\t0.24 atm",
            "c)\t0.36 atm",
            "d)\t0.9 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Pressure = 10000*10*0.25/101325 = 0.24 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 141,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used for the pressure measurement of only liquid?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tManometer",
            "b)\tPiezometer",
            "c)\tDifferential Manometer",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Piezometer is a pressure measuring device used to measure the pressure of liquid only."
    },
    {
        "id": 142,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used to measure a pressure of only gas?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tU-tube manometer",
            "b)\tPiezometer",
            "c)\tDifferential Manometer",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: U-tube manometer is used to measure the pressure of gas only."
    },
    {
        "id": 143,
        "Question": "What is the difference between manometer and differential manometer?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tDifferential manometer has gas in empty space",
            "b)\tManometer has gas in empty space",
            "c)\tDifferential manometer has liquid in empty space",
            "d)\tManometer has liquid in empty space"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Differential manometer has gas in empty space while manometer has a vacuum."
    },
    {
        "id": 144,
        "Question": "Which of the following device is used to measure the velocity of flow?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tManometer",
            "b)\tVenturi meter",
            "c)\tPitot tube",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Pitot tube is used to measure the velocity of flow."
    },
    {
        "id": 145,
        "Question": "A U-tube manometer is open at one end and has a gas at the other end if the level of the mercury in both legs of the manometer is equal then what is the temperature of the gas?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 Pa",
            "b)\t1 Torr",
            "c)\t1 mm Hg",
            "d)\t1 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Since the level of mercury in both legs are equal, this means that pressure is equal on both ends, => pressure of gas = pressure of atmosphere = 1 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 146,
        "Question": "A U-tube manometer is closed at both ends one end is vacuum and other end has a gas, if the difference in level of mercury is h = 10 mm, what is the pressure of gas?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1.33 Pa",
            "b)\t1.45 Pa",
            "c)\t1.56 Pa",
            "d)\t1.75 Pa"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since the other end of the manometer has vacuum, this means the pressure of gas is equal to the difference in pressure of mercury in both ends, => Pressure of gas = d*g*h = 13.6*9.8*0.01 = 1.33 Pa."
    },
    {
        "id": 147,
        "Question": "A closed U-tube manometer has a gas on one end with pressure 10 Pa and other end has vacuum, what is the approximate density of the liquid if the height difference of the liquid is 10 cm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 Kg/m3",
            "b)\t10 Kg/m3",
            "c)\t100 Kg/m3",
            "d)\t1000 Kg/m3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Pressure of gas = Pressure due to height difference of liquid = d*g*h, => 10 = d*10*0.1, => d = 10 Kg/m3."
    },
    {
        "id": 148,
        "Question": "A closed U-tube manometer has a gas on one end with pressure 5 Pa and other end has vacuum, what is the approximate height difference of the liquid if the density of liquid is 10 Kg/m3?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 mm",
            "b)\t10 mm",
            "c)\t50 mm",
            "d)\t100 mm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Pressure of gas = Pressure due to height difference of liquid = d*g*h, => 5 = 10*10*h => h = 0.05 m = 50 mm."
    },
    {
        "id": 149,
        "Question": "A closed manometer is filled with 3 fluids first on the left leg with density 8 kg/m3 and length 10 cm, middle one with density 10 kg/m3 and height difference 5 cm more on right leg and the third on the right leg with density 15 kg/m3, what is the length of the third liquid?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 cm",
            "b)\t2 cm",
            "c)\t3 cm",
            "d)\t4 cm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Pressure on both legs should be equal, => 8*10 = 10*5 + 15*x, => x = 2 cm."
    },
    {
        "id": 150,
        "Question": "A barometer has liquid level 10 cm above the outside level and the gas captured inside has the pressure of 0.5 atm, what is the density of liquid?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.5 atm-s2/m2",
            "b)\t1 atm-s2/m2",
            "c)\t1.5 atm-s2/m2",
            "d)\t2 atm-s2/m2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Pressure of gas + Pressure of liquid = atmospheric pressure, => 0.5 atm + d*10*0.1 = 1 atm, => d = 0.5 atm-s2/m2."
    },
    {
        "id": 151,
        "Question": "A barometer has liquid of density 1 kg/m3 of level 5 cm below the outside level, what is the pressure of the gas captured inside?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.5 atm + 1 Pa",
            "b)\t1 atm + 0.5 Pa",
            "c)\t1.5 atm + 1 Pa",
            "d)\t2 atm + 0.5 Pa"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Pressure of gas = Pressure of liquid + atmospheric pressure = 1*10*0.05 Pa + 1 atm = 0.5 Pa + 1 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 152,
        "Question": "A barometer has liquid with density 1 Kg/m3, and the gas has pressure 0.5 atm, what is the height of liquid level?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.01 atm-m2-s2/kg",
            "b)\t0.05 atm-m2-s2/kg",
            "c)\t0.1 atm-m2-s2/kg",
            "d)\t0.5 atm-m2-s2/kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Pressure of gas + Pressure of Liquid = atmospheric pressure, => 0.5 atm + 1*10*h = 1 atm, => h = 0.05 atm-m2-s2/kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 153,
        "Question": "A barometer the liquid-1 with density 2 Kg/m3 and height 5 cm below the outside level and above that liquid-2 with density 0.5 Kg/m3 and length 10 cm, what is the gauge pressure of the gas?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.01 Pa",
            "b)\t0.05 Pa",
            "c)\t0.1 Pa",
            "d)\t0.5 Pa"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Gauge pressure of gas + Pressure of liquid-2 = Pressure of liquid-1, => Gauge pressure of gas = 2*10*0.05– 0.5*10*0.1 = 0.5 Pa."
    },
    {
        "id": 154,
        "Question": "A barometer has liquid-1 with density 5 Kg/m3 and height 10 cm below the outside level above that there is liquid-2 of length 5 cm, if the gauge pressure of the gas is 1 Pa, what is the density of liquid-2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 Kg/m3",
            "b)\t4 Kg/m3",
            "c)\t6 Kg/m3",
            "d)\t8 Kg/m3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Gauge pressure of gas + Pressure of liquid-2 = Pressure of liquid-1, => 1 + d*10*0.05 = 5*10*0.1, => d = 8 Kg/m3."
    },
    {
        "id": 155,
        "Question": "A barometer has liquid-1 with density 1 Kg/m3 and height 10 cm below the outside level above that a liquid-2, if the gauge pressure of gas is 0.5 Pa, what is the pressure liquid-2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.5 Pa",
            "b)\t1 Pa",
            "c)\t1.5 Pa",
            "d)\t2 Pa"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Gauge pressure of gas + Pressure of liquid-2 = Pressure of liquid-1, => Pressure of liquid-2 = 1*10*0.1 – 0.5 = 0.5 Pa."
    },
    {
        "id": 156,
        "Question": "Which of the following does the concept of material balance based upon?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tConservation of mass",
            "b)\tConservation of energy",
            "c)\tConservation of momentum",
            "d)\tConservation of Volume"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Material is simply conservation of mass."
    },
    {
        "id": 157,
        "Question": "The equation of material balance, (Final condition + Sum of outputs) is equal to which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tInitial condition – Sum of inputs",
            "b)\tInitial condition + Sum of inputs",
            "c)\tSum of inputs – Initial condition",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Equation of material balance is Final condition – Initial condition = Sum of inputs – Sum of outputs, => Final condition + Sum of outputs = Initial condition + Sum of inputs."
    },
    {
        "id": 158,
        "Question": "A container has 10 grams of water 5 grams of water is added and 2 grams of water is taken out, what is the final amount of water?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t7 grams",
            "b)\t10 grams",
            "c)\t13 grams",
            "d)\t15 grams"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Final condition = Initial condition + sum of inputs – sum of outputs = 10 + 5 – 2 = 13 grams."
    },
    {
        "id": 159,
        "Question": "10 moles of O2 is added to 10 moles of H2, how many moles of H2O will it produce?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5",
            "b)\t10",
            "c)\t15",
            "d)\t20"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Balanced equation is 2H2 + O2 -> 2H2O, => Moles of H2O = Moles of H2 = 10."
    },
    {
        "id": 160,
        "Question": "A combustion reaction has reactants 1 mole of CxHy and 2 moles of O2 and products 1 mole of CO2 and 2 mole of H2O, what is x + y?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t3",
            "c)\t4",
            "d)\t5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Moles of C, H and O in reactants = Moles of C, H and O in products, => C: 1*x = 1*1 => x = 1, H: 1*y = 2*2 => x + y = 5."
    },
    {
        "id": 161,
        "Question": "In a random reaction 2 mole of CH4 and 1 mole of C2H4 are reacted, and 1 mole of C3H8 and 1 mole of CxHy are produced, what is x*y?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2",
            "b)\t4",
            "c)\t8",
            "d)\t12"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Material balance for C: 2*1 + 1*2 =1*3 +1*x, => x = 1, for H: 2*4 + 1*4 = 1*8 + 1*y, => y = 4, => x*y = 4."
    },
    {
        "id": 162,
        "Question": "A reaction has reactants 2 moles of NaOH and 1 mole of H2SO4, and products Na2SO4 and H2O, what are the total moles of products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Material Balance for Na: 2*1 = n1*2 => n1 = 1, for H: 2*1 + 1*2 = n2*2 => n2 = 2, => total moles of products = 1 + 2 = 3."
    },
    {
        "id": 163,
        "Question": "A reaction is A + 2B -> 3C, if 2 moles of A and 4 moles of B entered the system, what are the number of moles of C formed?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2",
            "b)\t4",
            "c)\t6",
            "d)\t8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Moles of C = 3*2 = 6."
    },
    {
        "id": 164,
        "Question": "10 moles of A were present in a system initially, and 10 moles are added to it, it follows the reaction 4A -> B, what are the number of moles of B produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5",
            "b)\t10",
            "c)\t15",
            "d)\t20"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Moles of B = (10 + 10)/4 = 5."
    },
    {
        "id": 165,
        "Question": " 10 moles of A were present in a system initially, and 10 moles of C are added to it, it follows the reaction 2A + C -> 5B, what is the number of moles of B produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5",
            "b)\t10",
            "c)\t25",
            "d)\t50"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Mole of B = 5*5 = 25."
    },
    {
        "id": 166,
        "Question": "There were 10 moles of a substance present initially in a system, 5 moles were added to it and a reaction occurred so that its moles are reduced by 20%, what are the final moles of a substance in the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10",
            "b)\t12",
            "c)\t15",
            "d)\t18"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Final moles of substance = (10 + 5)*80/100 = 12."
    },
    {
        "id": 167,
        "Question": "There were 15 moles of a substance present initially in a system, 25 moles were added to it and a reaction occurred so that its moles are reduced by 50%, what are the final moles of a substance in the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10",
            "b)\t15",
            "c)\t20",
            "d)\t40"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Final moles of substance = (15 + 25)*50/100 = 20."
    },
    {
        "id": 168,
        "Question": "10 moles of A were present in a system initially, and 12 moles of C are added to it, it undergoes the reaction 2A + 3C -> 2B, what are number of moles of B produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4",
            "b)\t5",
            "c)\t8",
            "d)\t12"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Moles of B = 2*4 = 8."
    },
    {
        "id": 169,
        "Question": "10 moles of A were present in a system initially, and 8 moles of C are added to it, it undergoes the reaction 5A + 3C -> 4B, what are number of moles of B produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4",
            "b)\t6",
            "c)\t8",
            "d)\t10"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Moles of B = 4*2 = 8."
    },
    {
        "id": 170,
        "Question": "8 moles of A were present in a system initially, and 24 moles of B are added to it, it undergoes the reaction 2A + 3B -> 4C + 5D, what are the number of moles of D produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10",
            "b)\t20",
            "c)\t30",
            "d)\t40"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Moles of D = 5*4 = 20."
    },
    {
        "id": 171,
        "Question": "Which of the following is constant in a closed system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tEnergy",
            "b)\tMass",
            "c)\tTemperature",
            "d)\tMomentum"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A material neither leaves nor enters a closed system."
    },
    {
        "id": 172,
        "Question": "How is the boundary wall of a closed system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tImpermeable",
            "b)\tPermeable",
            "c)\tRigid",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since the matter is not allowed to cross the boundary wall of a closed system, so the wall is impermeable."
    },
    {
        "id": 173,
        "Question": "Desert Cooler is an example of which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tClosed System",
            "b)\tOpen System",
            "c)\tIsolated System",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since water is filled and then it vaporizes in desert cooler, this means the material is flowing in and out of the system, so it is an open system."
    },
    {
        "id": 174,
        "Question": "A jar filled with water is an example of which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tClosed System",
            "b)\tOpen System",
            "c)\tIsolated System",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since water is neither leaving nor entering the jar, this means it is a closed system."
    },
    {
        "id": 175,
        "Question": "A pressure cooker is an example of which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tClosed System",
            "b)\tOpen System",
            "c)\tIsolated System",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since steam is expelled outside in the cooker as the temperature increase, it is an open system."
    },
    {
        "id": 176,
        "Question": "A country is an example of which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tClosed System",
            "b)\tOpen System",
            "c)\tIsolated System",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since a man can leave or enter a country it is an example of an open system."
    },
    {
        "id": 177,
        "Question": "An egg is an example of which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tClosed System",
            "b)\tOpen System",
            "c)\tIsolated System",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since matter is neither entering nor leaving an egg, it’s a closed system."
    },
    {
        "id": 178,
        "Question": "The human body is an example of which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tClosed System",
            "b)\tOpen System",
            "c)\tIsolated System",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since air, water and food are going in and out of a human body, it’s an open system."
    },
    {
        "id": 179,
        "Question": "What is the accumulation in the system after 10 second if the out flow and in flow rates are 10 g/s and 15 g/s?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 g",
            "b)\t10 g",
            "c)\t50 g",
            "d)\t100 g"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Accumulation = 10*(15 – 10) = 50 g."
    },
    {
        "id": 180,
        "Question": "What is the accumulation in the system after 4 second if the out flow and in flow rates are 3 g/s and 8 g/s?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12 g",
            "b)\t20 g",
            "c)\t32 g",
            "d)\t40 g"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Accumulation = 4*(8 – 3) = 20 g."
    },
    {
        "id": 181,
        "Question": "The flow in rate of A is 5 mole/s, it undergoes a reaction A -> 2B, what are the moles of B that comes out after 5 seconds?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5",
            "b)\t10",
            "c)\t25",
            "d)\t50"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Moles of B = 5*5*2 = 50."
    },
    {
        "id": 182,
        "Question": "The flow in rate of A is 8 mole/s, it undergoes a reaction 3A -> B, what are the moles of B that comes out after 6 seconds?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5",
            "b)\t8",
            "c)\t10",
            "d)\t16"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Moles of B = 8*6/3 = 16."
    },
    {
        "id": 183,
        "Question": "The flow in rate of A and B are 5 mole/s and 10 mole/s respectively, which under goes reaction A + 2B -> 3C, what is the flow out rate of C?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 mole/s",
            "b)\t10 mole/s",
            "c)\t15 mole/s",
            "d)\t20 mole/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Rate of C = 3*5 = 15 mole/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 184,
        "Question": "The flow in rate of A and B are 4 mole/s and 8 mole/s respectively, which under goes reaction A + B -> 3C, what is the flow out rate of C?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4 mole/s",
            "b)\t8 mole/s",
            "c)\t12 mole/s",
            "d)\t24 mole/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Rate of C = 4*3 = 12 mole/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 185,
        "Question": "The flow in rate of A and B are 8 mole/s and 10 mole/s respectively, which under goes reaction 4A + 5B -> 3C, what is the flow out rate of C?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4 mole/s",
            "b)\t6 mole/s",
            "c)\t8 mole/s",
            "d)\t10 mole/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Flow out rate of C = 3*2 = 6 mole/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 186,
        "Question": "Which of the following remains constant in the steady state system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tMass",
            "b)\tEnergy",
            "c)\tMomentum",
            "d)\tDensity"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In a steady state system what amount of material goes in the same amount comes out, so the overall mass remains constant."
    },
    {
        "id": 187,
        "Question": "A reaction occurs in a vessel such that its mass does not change but its temperature is increased, then the system is which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tSteady-state",
            "b)\tUnsteady-state",
            "c)\tCannot say",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For a steady-state system all the properties temperature, pressure, mass should remain constant with respect to time, so it is an unsteady-state process."
    },
    {
        "id": 188,
        "Question": "A fluid enters a vessel at the rate of 10 liters/s, and leaves in two pathways one with 7 liters/s and other with 3 liters/s, then what type of flow it is?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tSteady-state",
            "b)\tUnsteady-state",
            "c)\tCannot say",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since the flow in rate and flow out rate of the fluid are equal, the system is in steady-state."
    },
    {
        "id": 189,
        "Question": "A fluid enters a vessel at the rate of 10 liters/s, and leaves in two pathways one with 5 liters/s and other with 3 liters/s, then what type of flow it is?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tSteady-state",
            "b)\tUnsteady-state",
            "c)\tCannot say",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since the flow in rate and flow out rate of the fluid are unequal, the system is in unsteady-state."
    },
    {
        "id": 190,
        "Question": "The rate flow in and flow out in an unsteady state process are now increased by 10 Kg/s, which will be the change in accumulation?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t5 Kg/s",
            "c)\t10 Kg/s",
            "d)\t20 Kg/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Initial accumulation = rate of flow out – rate of flow in, => Final accumulation = (rate of flow out + 10) – (rate of flow in + 10) = Initial accumulation, => Change in accumulation = 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 191,
        "Question": "An unsteady-state system, with 10 liters as initial amount of water in the vessel, water flow in rate is 8 liters/ s and flow out rate is 5 liters/s, what will be the amount of water in the vessel after 10 seconds?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 liters",
            "b)\t20 liters",
            "c)\t30 liters",
            "d)\t40 liters"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Amount of water added to the vessel in 10 seconds = (8 – 5)*10 = 30 liters, => Final amount of water = 10 + 30 = 40 liters."
    },
    {
        "id": 192,
        "Question": "An unsteady-state system, with 6 liters as initial amount of water in the vessel, water flow in rate is 2 liters/ s and flow out rate is 4 liters/s, what will be the amount of water in the vessel after 1 second?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 liters",
            "b)\t4 liters",
            "c)\t6 liters",
            "d)\t8 liters"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Total amount of water reduced from the vessel in 1 second = (4 – 2)*1 = 2 liters, => Final amount of water = 6 – 2 = 4 liters."
    },
    {
        "id": 193,
        "Question": "What is the final amount of fluid in the vessel if the system is in steady state?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tSame as the initial amount",
            "b)\tTwice the initial amount",
            "c)\tZero",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since in steady-state the rate of flow in is equal to the rate of flow out, so final amount of fluid in the vessel is same as the initial amount."
    },
    {
        "id": 194,
        "Question": "In what ratio 57 octane and 63 octane should be mixed to obtain 59 octane?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1:1",
            "b)\t2:1",
            "c)\t3:1",
            "d)\t4:1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 59*1 = 63*x + 57*(1 – x), => x= 1/3, => 1 – x = 2/3, => ratio of 57 octane: 63 octane = 2/3:1/3 = 2:1."
    },
    {
        "id": 195,
        "Question": "What amount of 57 octane should be mixed with 3 liters of 63 octane to obtain 4 liters of 59 octane?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 liter",
            "b)\t2 liters",
            "c)\t2.5 liters",
            "d)\t4.5 liters"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: 59*1 = 63*x + 57*(1 – x), => x = 1/3, now 4 = (1/3)*3 + (2/3)*w, => w = 4.5 liters."
    },
    {
        "id": 196,
        "Question": "An unsteady state system, the flow in rate of A is 10 mole/s, what is the flow out rate of B if the accumulation was 10 mole in 2 seconds?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 mole/s",
            "b)\t10 mole/s",
            "c)\t15 mole/s",
            "d)\t20 mole/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Flow rate of B = 10 – 10/2 = 5 mole/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 197,
        "Question": "An unsteady state system, the flow in the rate of A is 12 mole/s, what is the flow out rate of B if the accumulation was 18 mole in 3 seconds?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4 mole/s",
            "b)\t6 mole/s",
            "c)\t8 mole/s",
            "d)\t9 mole/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Flow rate of B = 12 – 18/3 = 6 mole/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 198,
        "Question": "An unsteady state system, the flow in rate of A is 5 mole/s, what is the flow out rate of B if the accumulation was 10 mole in 5 seconds?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 mole/s",
            "b)\t2 mole/s",
            "c)\t3 mole/s",
            "d)\t5 mole/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Flow rate of B = 5 – 10/5 = 3 mole/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 199,
        "Question": "An unsteady state system, the flow in rate of A is 8 mole/s, what is the flow out rate of B if the accumulation was 6 mole in 2 seconds?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 mole/s",
            "b)\t2 mole/s",
            "c)\t3 mole/s",
            "d)\t5 mole/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Flow rate of B = 8 – 6/2 = 5 mole/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 200,
        "Question": "An unsteady state system, the flow in the rate of A is 6 mole/s, what is the flow out rate of B if the accumulation was 18 mole in 9 seconds?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 mole/s",
            "b)\t2 mole/s",
            "c)\t3 mole/s",
            "d)\t4 mole/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Flow rate of B = 6 – 18/9 = 4 mole/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 201,
        "Question": "Feed of a reactor has 0.25 mass fraction of H2O and 0.75 mass fraction of CO2 with rate 4 g/hr, if the product rate is 20 g/hr what is the mass of CO2 in the product side?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3 grams",
            "b)\t9 grams",
            "c)\t15 grams",
            "d)\t21 grams"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Mass fraction of CO2 will be same on both sides, => mass of CO2 in the product side = 20*0.75 = 15 grams."
    },
    {
        "id": 202,
        "Question": "A reactor has feed of two streams, stream 1 has CO2 and H2O with mass fraction of 0.4 and 0.6 and rate 10 kg/hr, and stream 2 has CO2 and H2O with mass fraction 0.1 and 0.9 and rate 40 Kg/hr, what the mass fraction of CO2 in the product stream?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.08",
            "b)\t0.16",
            "c)\t0.24",
            "d)\t0.32"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Mass fraction of CO2 in product stream = (0.4*10 + 0.1*40)/(10 + 40) = 0.16."
    },
    {
        "id": 203,
        "Question": "A reactor has feed from 2 streams, one with rate 10 Kg/hr and other with 30 Kg/hr, and product side also has 2 streams one of which is at the rate of 15 Kg/hr, what is the rate of other product stream?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 Kg/hr",
            "b)\t15 Kg/hr",
            "c)\t25 Kg/hr",
            "d)\t35 Kg/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Total feed rate = Total product rate, => 10 + 30 = 15 + x, => x = 25 Kg/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 204,
        "Question": "Feed of a reactor has 0.75 mass fraction of O2 and some SO2, if the product rate is 1000 Kg/hr then what is the rate of SO2 in the feed?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t100 Kg/hr",
            "b)\t250 Kg/hr",
            "c)\t750 Kg/hr",
            "d)\t1000 Kg/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Feed rate = Product rate = 1000 Kg/hr, => Rate of SO2 = (1 – 0.75)*1000 = 250 Kg/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 205,
        "Question": "A reactor has two feed streams with the ratio of their rate as 1:9 and has O2 and O3 with the mass fraction of 0.6 and 0.4 in stream 1 and 0.2 and 0.8 in stream 2, what is the mass fraction of O2 in the product side?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.24",
            "b)\t0.48",
            "c)\t0.72",
            "d)\t0.96"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Let the stream rates be 1 Kg/hr and 9 Kg/hr, => mass fraction of O¬2 in product side = (1*0.6 + 9*0.2)/(1 + 9) = 0.24."
    },
    {
        "id": 206,
        "Question": "A reactor with efficiency 50%, has the feed CO2 and SO2 with mass fraction 0.4 and 0.6 with the rate 10 Kg/hr, what is the rate of CO2 in product side?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.5 Kg/hr",
            "b)\t1 Kg/hr",
            "c)\t1.5 Kg/hr",
            "d)\t2 Kg/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Rate at product side = 10*50/100 = 5 Kg/hr, => rate of CO2 = 5*0.4 = 2 Kg/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 207,
        "Question": "A reactor has feed rate of 10 Kg/ hr and 5 Kg/hr and product rate of 9 Kg/hr, what is the efficiency of the reactor?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t30%",
            "c)\t60%",
            "d)\t100%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Efficiency = 9/(10 + 5)*100 = 60%."
    },
    {
        "id": 208,
        "Question": "Waste water flowing with TSS concentration 40 mg/L at the rate of 10 Liter/min is discharged into the river if the river is flowing at the rate of 15 Liter/min, what is the concentration of TSS in the river?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 mg/L",
            "b)\t30 mg/L",
            "c)\t45 mg/L",
            "d)\t60 mg/L"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Concentration of TSS in river = 40*15/10 = 60 mg/L."
    },
    {
        "id": 209,
        "Question": "Water flowing with chlorine concentration 10 mg/L at the rate of 20 Liter/min, is discharged into a river if the concentration of chlorine in a river is 5 mg/L what is the flow rate of river?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 Liter/min",
            "b)\t20 Liter/min",
            "c)\t30 Liter/min",
            "d)\t40 Liter/min"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Rate of flow of river = 20*5/10 = 10 Liter/min."
    },
    {
        "id": 210,
        "Question": "Water flowing with TSS at the rate of 40 Liter/min, is discharged into a river flowing at the rate of 20 Liter/min, if the concentration of TSS in the river is 5 mg/L, what is the concentration of TSS in water?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 mg/L",
            "b)\t10 mg/L",
            "c)\t15 mg/L",
            "d)\t20 mg/L"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Concentration of TSS in water = 5*40/20 = 10 mg/L."
    },
    {
        "id": 211,
        "Question": "The rate of flow in stream with 20% CH4 and 80% H2O is 5 mole/hr, the contained was initially filled with 3 mole of H2O, what will be the percentage of CH4 in product stream?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5",
            "b)\t12.5",
            "c)\t25",
            "d)\t37.5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Percentage of CH4 = 1/(1 + 4 + 3)*100 = 12.5%."
    },
    {
        "id": 212,
        "Question": "The rate of flow in stream with 20% O2 and 80% CO2 is 5 mole/hr, the contained was initially filled with 3 mole of O2, what will be the percentage of O2 in product stream?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12.5",
            "b)\t25",
            "c)\t37.5",
            "d)\t50"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Percentage of O2 = 4/(4 + 4)*100 = 50%."
    },
    {
        "id": 213,
        "Question": "The rate of flow in stream with 40% O2 and 60% CO2 is 10 mole/hr, the contained was initially filled with 6 mole of O2, what will be the percentage of O2 in product stream?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12.5",
            "b)\t25",
            "c)\t50",
            "d)\t62.5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Percentage of O2 = 10/(10 + 6)*100 = 62.5%."
    },
    {
        "id": 214,
        "Question": "The rate of flow in stream with 50% O2 and 50% CO2 is 10 mole/hr, the contained was initially filled with 10 mole of O2, what will be the percentage of O2 in product stream?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25",
            "b)\t50",
            "c)\t75",
            "d)\t100"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Percentage of O2 = 15/(10 + 10)*100 = 75%."
    },
    {
        "id": 215,
        "Question": "The rate of flow in stream with 75% O2 and 25% CO2 is 20 mole/hr, the contained was initially filled with 5 mole of O2, what will be the percentage of O2 in product stream?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20",
            "b)\t40",
            "c)\t60",
            "d)\t80"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Percentage of O2 = 20/(10 + 15)*100 = 8%."
    },
    {
        "id": 216,
        "Question": "The general material balance equation for reactive system is Accumulation = Input + Generation – x, what is x?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tConsumption – Output",
            "b)\tConsumption + Output",
            "c)\tOutput – Consumption",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Accumulation = Input – Output + Generation – Consumption, => x = Consumption + Output."
    },
    {
        "id": 217,
        "Question": "In a system if, Accumulation = Input – Output + Generation – Consumption, where all the four terms are distinct and non-zero, then the system is which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tSteady-state",
            "b)\tClosed",
            "c)\tNon-reactive",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: As the formula involves input and output it is an open system, and also as it involves generation and consumption the system is reactive, and since the input is not equal to output so the system is unsteady-state, and the answer is d."
    },
    {
        "id": 218,
        "Question": "In a system if, Accumulation = Generation – Consumption, where both the terms are distinct and non-zero, then the system is which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tSteady-state",
            "b)\tClosed",
            "c)\tNon-reactive",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: As the formula does not involve input and output it is a closed system."
    },
    {
        "id": 219,
        "Question": "In a system if, Accumulation = Input – Output, where both the terms are distinct and non-zero, then the system is which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tSteady-state",
            "b)\tClosed",
            "c)\tNon-reactive",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: As the formula does not involve generation and consumption it is a non-reactive system."
    },
    {
        "id": 220,
        "Question": "In a steady-state reactive system, NaOH and HCl are supplied to the system both at the rate of 100 mole/min, then what is the rate of NaCl produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t100 mole/min",
            "b)\t200 mole/min",
            "c)\t300 mole/min",
            "d)\t400 mole/min"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: As the system is in steady-state, rate of product = rate of feed, => rate of NaCl = 100 + 100 = 200 mole/min."
    },
    {
        "id": 221,
        "Question": "In a steady-state reactive system, 1 molar each of NaOH and HCl are supplied to the system both at the rate of 100 L/min, then what is the amount of NaCl produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 molar",
            "b)\t2 molar",
            "c)\t3 molar",
            "d)\t4 molar"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The balanced reaction of the system is NaOH + HCl -> NaCl + H2O, => amount of NaCl = amount of HCl = amount of NaOH = 1 molar."
    },
    {
        "id": 222,
        "Question": "In a steady-state reactive system, NaCl and H2CO3 are supplied to the system at the rate of 200 L/min and 100 L/min respectively, what is the rate at which Na2CO3 is produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t100 L/min",
            "b)\t200 L/min",
            "c)\t300 L/min",
            "d)\t400 L/min"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: As the system is in steady state, => rate of product = rate of feed, => rate of Na2CO3 = 200 + 100 = 300 L/min."
    },
    {
        "id": 223,
        "Question": "In a steady-state reactive system, 2 molar NaCl and 1 molar H2CO3 are supplied to the system both at the rate of 100 mole/min, then how much Na2CO3 produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 molar",
            "b)\t2 molar",
            "c)\t3 molar",
            "d)\t4 molar"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The balanced reaction of the system is 2NaCl + H2CO3 -> Na2CO3 + 2HCl, => amount of Na2CO3 = 1 molar."
    },
    {
        "id": 224,
        "Question": "In a steady-state reactive system, 5 molar CH4 and 5 molar O2 are supplied to the system, then what is the amount of CO2 produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2.5 molar",
            "b)\t5 molar",
            "c)\t7.5 molar",
            "d)\t10 molar"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction of the system is CH4 + O2 -> CO2 + 2H2O, => amount of CO2 = 5 molar."
    },
    {
        "id": 225,
        "Question": "In a steady-state reactive system, 5 molar KNO3 and 5 molar H2SO4 are supplied to the system, then what is the amount of K2SO4 produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2.5 molar",
            "b)\t5 molar",
            "c)\t7.5 molar",
            "d)\t10 molar"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction of the system is 2KNO3 + H2SO4 -> K2SO4 + 2HNO3, => amount of K2SO4 = 2.5 molar."
    },
    {
        "id": 226,
        "Question": "The flow in rate of HCl and NaOH in a system are 1 mole/hr each what is the flow out rate of NaCl?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 mole/hr",
            "b)\t2 mole/hr",
            "c)\t3 mole/hr",
            "d)\t4 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The reaction is HCl + NaOH -> NaCl + H2O, => flow out rate of NaCl = 1 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 227,
        "Question": "The flow in rate of H2SO4 and NaCl in a system are 2 mole/hr each what is the flow out rate of HCl?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 mole/hr",
            "b)\t2 mole/hr",
            "c)\t3 mole/hr",
            "d)\t4 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The reaction is H2SO4 + 2NaCl -> 2HCl + Na2SO4, => flow out rate of HCl = 2*1 = 2 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 228,
        "Question": "The flow in rate of CH4 and O2 in a system are 2 mole/hr each what is the flow out rate of CO2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 mole/hr",
            "b)\t2 mole/hr",
            "c)\t3 mole/hr",
            "d)\t4 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The reaction is CH4 + 2O2 -> CO2 + 2H2O, => flow out rate of CO2 = 1*1 = 1 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 229,
        "Question": "The flow in rate of C3H8 and O2 in a system are 2 mole/hr each what is the flow out rate of CO2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 mole/hr",
            "b)\t1.2 mole/hr",
            "c)\t1.5 mole/hr",
            "d)\t2 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The reaction is C3H8 + 5O2 -> 3CO2 + 4H2O, => flow out rate of CO2 = 2*3/5 = 1.2 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 230,
        "Question": "The flow in rate of C6H6 and H2 in a system are 3 mole/hr each what is the flow out rate of C6H12?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 mole/hr",
            "b)\t1.2 mole/hr",
            "c)\t1.5 mole/hr",
            "d)\t2 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The reaction is C6H6 + 3H2 -> C6H12, => flow out rate of C6H12 = 3*1/3 = 1 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 231,
        "Question": "A batch process is that in which material enters the system and _____ which of the following should fill the gap?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tLeaves",
            "b)\tDoes not leaves",
            "c)\tHalf of it leaves",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A batch process is that in which material enters the system and operated and leaves."
    },
    {
        "id": 232,
        "Question": "A semi-batch process is that in which material enters the system and _____ which of the following should fill the gap?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tLeaves",
            "b)\tDoes not leaves",
            "c)\tHalf of it leaves",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A semi-batch process is that in which material enters a system and does not leave."
    },
    {
        "id": 233,
        "Question": "A semi-batch process differs from an open process in which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tInput",
            "b)\tOutput",
            "c)\tGeneration",
            "d)\tConsumption"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A semi-batch process does not have output, while an open system has output."
    },
    {
        "id": 234,
        "Question": "A semi-batch process differs from a closed process in which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tInput",
            "b)\tOutput",
            "c)\tGeneration",
            "d)\tConsumption"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A semi-batch process has some input, while a closed process does not have input."
    },
    {
        "id": 235,
        "Question": "Tap filling a jar with water is an example of which of the following process?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tBatch",
            "b)\tSemi-batch",
            "c)\tNeither of them",
            "d)\tBatch & Semi-batch"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since water is entering the jar and does not leave, it is a semi-batch process."
    },
    {
        "id": 236,
        "Question": "Water flowing in plants from tap through a pipe, the process is an example of which of the following process?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tBatch",
            "b)\tSemi-batch",
            "c)\tNeither of them",
            "d)\tBatch & Semi-batch"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since water enters the pipe from one end and leaves from another end, it is a batch process."
    },
    {
        "id": 237,
        "Question": "Water boiling in a container is an example of which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tBatch",
            "b)\tSemi-batch",
            "c)\tNeither of them",
            "d)\tBatch & Semi-batch"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Since nothing is entering in the container but steam is leaving the container, it is neither a batch process nor a semi-batch process."
    },
    {
        "id": 238,
        "Question": "Two reactants enter a vessel and a reaction is carried out, it is an example of which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tBatch",
            "b)\tSemi-batch",
            "c)\tNeither of them",
            "d)\tBatch & Semi-batch"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since material enters the vessel and operated but does not comes out, so it is a semi-batch process."
    },
    {
        "id": 239,
        "Question": "In a batch process, 70 Kg of H2O and 10 Kg of NaOH and some other reactants enters the vessel, if 100 Kg of the product leaves the vessel, what is the percentage of H2O in the product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t30%",
            "c)\t70%",
            "d)\t100%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Percentage of H2O in the product = (70/100)*100 = 70%."
    },
    {
        "id": 240,
        "Question": "10 Kg of oil is burnt in a container and taken off from the container if 1% of oil remains on the container wall, how much oil is taken off?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t8.9 Kg",
            "b)\t9 Kg",
            "c)\t9.9 Kg",
            "d)\t10 Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Amount of oil taken off = 10*(1 – 1/100) = 9.9 Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 241,
        "Question": "In a batch process, 50 Kg of H2O and 40 Kg of CO2 entered a vessel with some H2O, if 100 Kg of product leaves the vessel, what is the percentage of H2O in the product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t30%",
            "c)\t60%",
            "d)\t80%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Percentage of H2O in the product = (100 – 40)/100*100 = 60%."
    },
    {
        "id": 242,
        "Question": "In a batch process, 40 mole of O2 and 30 mole of CO2 entered a vessel with some CO2, if 100 mole of product leaves the vessel, what is the percentage of O2 in the product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t40%",
            "c)\t60%",
            "d)\t80%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Percentage of H2O in the product = 40/100*100 = 40%."
    },
    {
        "id": 243,
        "Question": "In a batch process, 5 mole of H2 and 3 mole of CO2 entered a vessel with some CO2, if 10 mole of product leaves the vessel, what is the percentage of H2 in the product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t30%",
            "c)\t50%",
            "d)\t80%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Percentage of H2 in the product = 5/10*100 = 50%."
    },
    {
        "id": 244,
        "Question": "In a batch process, 2 mole of SO2 and 3 mole of CO2 entered a vessel with some SO2, if 5 mole of product leaves the vessel, what is the percentage of SO2 in the product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t20%",
            "c)\t40%",
            "d)\t50%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Percentage of H2 in the product = 2/5*100 = 40%."
    },
    {
        "id": 245,
        "Question": "In a batch process, 5 mole of SO2 and 3 mole of CO2 entered a vessel with some SO2, if 10 mole of product leaves the vessel, what is the percentage of SO2 in the product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t30%",
            "c)\t50%",
            "d)\t70%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Percentage of H2 in the product = (10 – 3)/10*100 = 70%."
    },
    {
        "id": 246,
        "Question": "Solution-1 at the rate F combines with solution-2 at the rate D, their combination gives the product at the rate P, what is the equation of material balance?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tF + D = P",
            "b)\tF – P = D",
            "c)\tD – F = P",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The general equation of material balance is F + D = P."
    },
    {
        "id": 247,
        "Question": "Solution-1 containing 30% sulfuric acid flowing at the rate 10 Kg/min combines with Solution-2 containing 20% sulfuric acid flowing at the rate 5 Kg/min, if their product is out at the rate 20 Kg/min what is the percentage of sulfuric acid in the product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t20%",
            "c)\t30%",
            "d)\t40%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Equation of material balance, 0.3(10) + 0.2(5) = x(20), => x = 0.2, => Percentage of sulfuric acid in the product = 20%."
    },
    {
        "id": 248,
        "Question": "Solution-1 containing 10% nitric acid flowing at the rate 10 Kg/min combines with Solution-2 containing 40% nitric acid flowing at the rate 5 Kg/min, if their product contains 30% nitric acid, what is the flow rate of product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 Kg/min",
            "b)\t20 Kg/min",
            "c)\t30 Kg/min",
            "d)\t40 Kg/min"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Equation of material balance, 0.1(10) + 0.4(5) = 0.3(x), => x = 10 Kg/min."
    },
    {
        "id": 249,
        "Question": "Solution-1 containing 10% nitric acid and 20% acetic acid at the rate F combines with Solution-2 containing 20% nitric acid and 10% acetic acid at the rate D, the product formed contains 30% nitric acid and 20% acetic acid at the rate P, how many independent equations containing F, D, and P are possible?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The equations of material balance are: 0.1F + 0.2D = 0.3P, 0.2F + 0.1D = 0.2P, and F + D = P."
    },
    {
        "id": 250,
        "Question": "Solution-1 containing 10% hydrochloric acid and 20% acetic acid at the rate F combines with Solution-2 containing 20% hydrochloric acid and 30% acetic acid at the rate D, the product formed contains 20% hydrochloric acid and 30% acetic acid at the rate P, how many independent equations containing F, D, and P are possible?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The equations of material balance are: 0.1F + 0.2D = 0.2P, 0.2F + 0.3D = 0.3P and F + D = P, but if we subtract first two of them then we get the third, so number of independent equations are 2."
    },
    {
        "id": 251,
        "Question": "Solution-1 containing 40% nitric acid and 20% carbon dioxide at the rate F combines with Solution-2 containing 30% nitric acid and 40% carbon dioxide at the rate D, the product formed contains 30% nitric acid and 20% carbon dioxide at the rate P, If P = xF what is x?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The equations of material balance are: 0.4F + 0.2D = 0.3P, 0.2F + 0.4D = 0.3P, and F + D = P, Solving these we get D = F = P/2, => x = 2."
    },
    {
        "id": 252,
        "Question": "Solution-1 containing 40% acetic acid and 20% carbon dioxide at the rate F combines with Solution-2 containing 20% acetic acid and 40% carbon dioxide at the rate D, the product formed contains 30% acetic acid at the rate P, what is the percentage of carbon dioxide in product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t20%",
            "c)\t30%",
            "d)\t40%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The equations for material balance are: 0.4F + 0.2D = 0.3P, F + D = P, and 0.2F + 0.4D = yP, solving these we get y = 0.3, => percentage of carbon dioxide = 30%."
    },
    {
        "id": 253,
        "Question": "Solution-1 containing 20% w1 and w2 at the rate 10 Kg/min combines with Solution-2 containing 10% w1, 20% w2 and w3 at the rate 20 Kg/min, the product formed contains and 10% w1, 30% w2 and 20% w3, what is the percentage of w2 in solution-1?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5%",
            "b)\t10%",
            "c)\t25%",
            "d)\t50%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Rate of product, P = 10 + 20 = 30 Kg/min, equation of material balance for w2: x(10) + 0.2(20) = 0.3(30), => w2 = 0.5, => percentage of w2 = 50%."
    },
    {
        "id": 254,
        "Question": "CH4 at the rate 10 mole/min is reacted with O2 at the rate 10 mole/min, what is the rate of formation of CO2 in the product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 mole/min",
            "b)\t10 mole/min",
            "c)\t20 mole/min",
            "d)\t40 mole/min"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is: CH4 + 2O2 -> CO2 + 2H2O, this means O2 is the limiting reagent, => rate of formation of CO2 = 10/2 = 5 mole/min."
    },
    {
        "id": 255,
        "Question": "CH4 at the rate 10 mole/min is reacted with O2 at the rate 30 mole/min, what is the rate of formation of CO2 in the product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 mole/min",
            "b)\t10 mole/min",
            "c)\t20 mole/min",
            "d)\t40 mole/min"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is: CH4 + 2O2 -> CO2 + 2H2O, this means CH4 is the limiting reagent, => rate of formation of CO2 = 10 mole/min."
    },
    {
        "id": 256,
        "Question": "Solution-1 containing 30% acetic acid and 20% nitrogen at the rate F combines with Solution-2 containing 20% acetic acid and 10% nitrogen at the rate D and Solution-3 containing 10% acetic acid and 30% nitrogen at the rate N the product formed contains 20% acetic acid at the rate P, what is the percentage of nitrogen in product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t20%",
            "c)\t30%",
            "d)\tCannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The equations for material balance are: 0.3F + 0.2D + 0.1N = 0.2P, F + D + N = P, and 0.2F + 0.1D + 0.3N = yP, since there are 5 variables and 3 equation, the equations cannot be solved."
    },
    {
        "id": 257,
        "Question": "Solution-1 containing 30% acetic acid and 20% nitrogen at the rate F combines with Solution-2 containing 20% acetic acid and 10% nitrogen at the rate D and Solution-3 containing 10% acetic acid and 30% nitrogen at the rate N the product formed contains 20% acetic acid at the rate P, what is the percentage of nitrogen in product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t20%",
            "c)\t30%",
            "d)\tCannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The equations for material balance are: 0.3F + 0.2D + 0.1N = 0.2P, F + D + N = P, and 0.2F + 0.1D + 0.3N = yP, since there are 5 variables and 3 equation, the equations cannot be solved."
    },
    {
        "id": 258,
        "Question": "Solution-1 containing 30% acetic acid and 20% nitrogen at the rate F combines with Solution-2 containing 20% acetic acid and 10% nitrogen at the rate D and Solution-3 containing 10% acetic acid and 30% nitrogen at the rate N the product formed contains 20% acetic acid at the rate 10 Kg/min, what is the percentage of nitrogen in product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t20%",
            "c)\t30%",
            "d)\tCannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The equations for material balance are: 0.3F + 0.2D + 0.1N = 0.2(10), F + D + N = 10, and 0.2F + 0.1D + 0.3N = y(10), since there are 4 variables and 3 equation, the equations cannot be solved."
    },
    {
        "id": 259,
        "Question": "Solution-1 containing 30% acetic acid and 100% nitrogen at the rate 10 Kg/min combines with Solution-2 containing 20% acetic acid and 10% nitrogen at the rate 20 Kg/min and Solution-3 containing 10% acetic acid and 30% nitrogen at the rate 30 Kg/min the product formed contains 20% acetic acid, what is the percentage of nitrogen in product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t20%",
            "c)\t30%",
            "d)\tCannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The equations for material balance are: P = 10 + 20 + 30 = 60 Kg/min, and 0.1(10) + 0.1(20) + 0.3(30) = y(60), => y = 0.1, => Percentage of nitrogen in the product = 10%."
    },
    {
        "id": 260,
        "Question": "Solution-1 containing 30% acetic acid and 20% nitrogen at the rate 10 Kg/min combines with Solution-2 containing 20% acetic acid and 10% nitrogen at the rate 20 Kg/min and Solution-3 containing 10% acetic acid and 30% nitrogen at the rate N the product formed contains 20% acetic acid at the rate P, what is the percentage of nitrogen in product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t17.5%",
            "c)\t25.5%",
            "d)\t32.5%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The equations for material balance, P = F + D + N = 30 + N, and 0.3(10) + 0.2(20) + 0.1N = 0.2P = 0.2(30 + N), => N = 10 Kg/min, => P = 40 Kg/min, equation of material balance for nitrogen: 0.2(10) + 0.1(20) + (0.3)10 = y(40), => y = 7/40 = 0.175, => Percentage of nitrogen in the product is 17.5%."
    },
    {
        "id": 261,
        "Question": "An aqueous solution with sulfur 10 g/L at the rate is 100 L/min and an organic compound with no sulfur at the rate 50 L/min were put into an extraction machine and produced an aqueous solution with sulfur 1 g/L, what is the amount of sulfur in the organic compound after extraction?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 g/L",
            "b)\t5 g/L",
            "c)\t9 g/L",
            "d)\t15 g/L"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Let the amount of sulfur in the organic compound be x. Sulfur balance equation, 100(10) + 50(0) = 100(1) + 50(x), => x = 9 g/L."
    },
    {
        "id": 262,
        "Question": "An aqueous solution with chlorine 30 g/L and an organic compound with no chlorine at the rate 50 L/min were put into an extraction machine and produced aqueous solution with chlorine 5 g/L and organic compound with chlorine 10 g/L, what is the rate of aqueous solution?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 L/min",
            "b)\t20 L/min",
            "c)\t30 L/min",
            "d)\t40 L/min"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Let the rate of an aqueous solution be x. Chlorine balance equation, x(30) + 50(0) = x(5) + 50(10), => x = 20 L/min."
    },
    {
        "id": 263,
        "Question": "A gas mixture input is given to a membrane with 40% O2 and 60% N2, the waste contains 80% of the input and the product contains 25% O2 and 75% N2, what is the percentage of O2 in the waste?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.22",
            "b)\t0.44",
            "c)\t0.66",
            "d)\t0.88"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Let the input is 100 Kg mol, => waste = 0.8(100) = 80 Kg mol, => Product = 20 Kg mol. Equation of material balance, O2: 0.4(100) = 0.25(20) + y(80), => y = 0.4375 ≈ 0.44."
    },
    {
        "id": 264,
        "Question": "A gas mixture input is given to a membrane with 20% O2 and 80% N2, the waste contains 60% of the input and the product contains 30% O2 and 70% N2, what are the number of moles of O2 in the waste?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\tCan’t be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Since the amount of input is not given, number of moles of O2 cannot be determined."
    },
    {
        "id": 265,
        "Question": "100 Kg mol of a gas mixture input is given to a membrane with 30% O2 and 70% N2, the waste contains 60% of the input and the product contains 10% O2 and 90% N2, what are the number of moles of O2 in the waste?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12",
            "b)\t16",
            "c)\t34",
            "d)\t42"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Let the moles of O2 in the waste be x, Amount of waste = 100(0.6) = 60 Kg mol, => amount of product = 40 Kg mol. Material balance equation for O2: 0.3(100) + 0.1(40) = x, => x = 34 moles."
    },
    {
        "id": 266,
        "Question": "A liquid solid mixture with 10% solid and 90% liquid is input to a dryer, some of the liquid evaporated and the product contains 60% solid and 40% liquid, what is the ratio of an amount of water evaporated and amount of input?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2:1",
            "b)\t3:2",
            "c)\t5:4",
            "d)\t6:5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Let the amount of input be F and the amount of evaporated water be W. Solid balance: 0.1*F = 0*W + 0.6*(F – W), => F/W = 6/5."
    },
    {
        "id": 267,
        "Question": "A liquid solid mixture with 20% solid and 80% liquid is input to a dryer, if the amount of evaporated water is 60% of the amount of input, what is the percentage of solid in the product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t40%",
            "b)\t50%",
            "c)\t80%",
            "d)\t90%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Let the amount of input be F, => the amount of evaporated water be 0.6F, => amount of product = 0.4F. Solid Balance: 0.2(F) = 0(0.6F) + x(0.4F), => x = 0.5, => percentage of solid in the product = 50%."
    },
    {
        "id": 268,
        "Question": "A 100 Kg liquid solid mixture with 10% solid and 90% liquid is input to a dryer, if the amount of evaporated water is 60% of the amount of input, what is the amount of liquid in the product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 Kg",
            "b)\t20 Kg",
            "c)\t30 Kg",
            "d)\t40 Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Let the amount of liquid in the product be x. Liquid balance: 0.9(100) = 1(60) + x, => x = 30 Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 269,
        "Question": "50 Kg of a solid liquid mixture containing 10% solid and 90% water is left open in an atmosphere, after some time the water is 80%, what is the weight of the mixture now?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 Kg",
            "b)\t25 Kg",
            "c)\t35 Kg",
            "d)\t50 Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Let the new weight of mixture be P. Solid balance: 0.1(50) = 0.2P, => P = 25 Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 270,
        "Question": "50 Kg of a solid liquid mixture containing 20% solid and 80% water is left open in the atmosphere, after some time the water is 60%, how much water is evaporated?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t15 Kg",
            "b)\t25 Kg",
            "c)\t35 Kg",
            "d)\t45 Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Let the weight of the water evaporated be W. Water Balance: 0.8(50) = 1(W) + 0.6(50 – W), => W = 25 Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 271,
        "Question": "A gas mixture of 40% He and 60% Ne is passed through a diffusion tube and the product has 10% He and 90% Ne, what is the percentage of He recovered?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25%",
            "b)\t33.3%",
            "c)\t50%",
            "d)\t66.6%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Let the amount of input gas mixture be F, amount of He recovered be D. He balance: 0.4F = 1D + 0.1(F – D), => D/F = 0.333, => percentage of He recovered = 33.3%."
    },
    {
        "id": 272,
        "Question": "100 Kg of a gas mixture of 40% He and 60% Ne is passed through a diffusion tube and the product has 20% He and 80% Ne, what is the amount of He recovered?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25 Kg",
            "b)\t45 Kg",
            "c)\t50 Kg",
            "d)\t75 Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Let the amount of He recovered be D, He Balance: 0.4(100) = 1(D) + 0.2(100 – D), => D = 25 Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 273,
        "Question": "A gas mixture of 40% He and 60% Ne is passed through a diffusion tube, if the amount of He is recovered is 20% of the input, what is the percentage of He in the product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25 %",
            "b)\t33.3 %",
            "c)\t50 %",
            "d)\t66.6 %"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Let the amount of input be F, He balance: 0.4(F) = 1(0.2F) + x(F – 0.2F), => x = 0.25, => Percentage of He in the product = 25%."
    },
    {
        "id": 274,
        "Question": "400 g of CaSO4 is dissolved with 500 g of H2O, if 226 g of CaSO4.5H2O crystallizes out, then what is the percentage of CaSO4 in the remaining solution?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t39.16%",
            "b)\t51.54%",
            "c)\t62.28%",
            "d)\t75.67%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Moles of crystal = 226/226 = 1, => the crystal has 136 g of CaSO4 and 90 g of water, => Remaining solution has 264 g of CaSO4 and 410 g of H2O, => Percentage of CaSO4 in remaining solution = 264/(264 + 410) *100 = 39.16%."
    },
    {
        "id": 275,
        "Question": "How much nitrogen must be added to a 20% nitrogen solution to obtain 100 Kg of 40% nitrogen solution?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 Kg",
            "b)\t25 Kg",
            "c)\t50 Kg",
            "d)\t75 Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Let the amount of nitrogen added be x, and amount of 20% nitrogen solution be P. Nitrogen balance: x + 0.2(P) = 0.4(100), Water balance: 0.8(P) = 0.6(100), => P = 75 Kg, => x = 0.4(100) – 0.2(75), => x = 25 Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 276,
        "Question": "Which of the following does stoichiometry of a reaction is all about?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tExtent of reaction",
            "b)\tHeat of reaction",
            "c)\tAmount of reactants and products",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: By definition, Stoichiometry relates the amount of reactants and products in a reaction."
    },
    {
        "id": 277,
        "Question": "C2H4 + xO2 -> 2CO2 + yH2O, what is the value of x + y?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2",
            "b)\t3",
            "c)\t5",
            "d)\t8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The balance combustion equation is C2H4 + 3O2 -> 2CO2 + 2H2O, => x = 3, y = 2, => x + y = 5."
    },
    {
        "id": 278,
        "Question": "C5H12 + xO2 -> yCO2 + zH2O, what is the value of x + y*z?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t24",
            "b)\t38",
            "c)\t46",
            "d)\t54"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is: C5H12 + 8O2 -> 5CO2 + 6H2O, => x + y*z = 8 + 5*6 = 38."
    },
    {
        "id": 279,
        "Question": "wC3H6O3 + xO2 –> yCO2 + zH2O, what is the value of w + x + y + z?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3",
            "b)\t6",
            "c)\t10",
            "d)\t14"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is: C3H6O3 + 3O2 –> 3CO2 + 3H2O, => w + x + y + z = 14."
    },
    {
        "id": 280,
        "Question": "wC3H7O4 + xO2 -> yCO2 + zH2O, what is the value of w + x + y + z?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t21",
            "b)\t35",
            "c)\t41",
            "d)\t47"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is: 4C3H7O4 + 11O2 -> 12CO2 + 14H2O, => w + x + y + z = 41."
    },
    {
        "id": 281,
        "Question": "20 grams of CaCO3 is heated, how much calcium oxide will produce?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5.6 grams",
            "b)\t11.2 grams",
            "c)\t22.4 grams",
            "d)\t44.8 grams"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The balance chemical reaction is CaCO3 -> CaO + CO2, moles of CaO = moles of CaCO3 = 20/100 = 0.2, => amount of CaO = 0.2*56 = 11.6 grams."
    },
    {
        "id": 282,
        "Question": "56 grams of carbon monoxide is oxidized with excess oxygen, how much carbon dioxide will it produce?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t22 grams",
            "b)\t44 grams",
            "c)\t66 grams",
            "d)\t88 grams"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is 2CO + O2 -> 2CO2, => moles of CO2 = moles of CO = 56/28 = 2, => amount of CO2 = 2*44 = 88 grams."
    },
    {
        "id": 283,
        "Question": "Pentane is burnt to produce carbon dioxide 40% of which can be converted into carbon monoxide, how much Butane must be burnt to produce 176 grams of carbon monoxide?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t18 grams",
            "b)\t36 grams",
            "c)\t72 grams",
            "d)\t96 grams"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is C5H12 + 8O2 -> 5CO2 + 6H2O, Let the mass of pentane be x, => (x/72)*5*44*(40/100) = 176, => x = 36 grams."
    },
    {
        "id": 284,
        "Question": "1 mole of glucose is burnt, how much carbon dioxide will it produce?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t44 grams",
            "b)\t176 grams",
            "c)\t264 grams",
            "d)\t352 grams"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is C6H12O6 + 6O2 -> 6CO2 + 6H2O, => moles of CO2 produced = 6, => amount of CO2 produced = 6*44 = 264 grams."
    },
    {
        "id": 285,
        "Question": "78 grams of benzene is burnt in air, how much water will it produce?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t18 grams",
            "b)\t36 grams",
            "c)\t54 grams",
            "d)\t72 grams"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is C6H6 + 7.5O2 -> 6CO2 + 3H2O, => moles of water = 3*78/78 = 3, => weight of water produced = 3*18 = 54 grams."
    },
    {
        "id": 286,
        "Question": "xKMnO4 + yFeS + zH2SO4 -> xMnSO4 + wFe2(SO4)3 + uK2SO4 + zH2O, what is the value of x + y + z + w + u?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t60",
            "b)\t74",
            "c)\t85",
            "d)\t98"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is 18KMnO4 + 10FeS + 32H2SO4 -> 18MnSO4 + 5Fe2(SO4)3 + 9K2SO4 + 32H2O, => x + y + z + w + u = 74."
    },
    {
        "id": 287,
        "Question": "158 grams of potassium permanganate is reacted with ferrous sulfide in the presence of hydrochloric acid, approximately how much ferric sulfate will it produce?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t111 grams",
            "b)\t169 grams",
            "c)\t254 grams",
            "d)\t399 grams"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is 18KMnO4 + 10FeS + 32H2SO4 -> 18MnSO4 + 5Fe2(SO4)3 + 9K2SO4 + 32H2O, => weight of ferric sulfate = (158/158)*(5/18)*400 = 111.1 grams ≈ 111 grams."
    },
    {
        "id": 288,
        "Question": "20 grams of NaOH is reacted with excess HCl, how much NaCl will it produce?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t29.25 grams",
            "b)\t58.5 grams",
            "c)\t117 grams",
            "d)\t234 grams"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is NaOH + HCl -> NaCl + H2O, => amount of NaCl = (20/40)*58.5 = 29.25 grams."
    },
    {
        "id": 289,
        "Question": "xFeS2 + yO2 -> zFe2O3 + wSO2, what is the value of x + y + z + w?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t16",
            "b)\t21",
            "c)\t25",
            "d)\t32"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is 4FeS2 + 11O2 -> 2Fe2O3 + 8SO2, => x + y + z + w = 25."
    },
    {
        "id": 290,
        "Question": "60 grams of FeS2, is burnt in air, how much sulfur dioxide will produce?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t16 grams",
            "b)\t32 grams",
            "c)\t64 grams",
            "d)\t128 grams"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is 4FeS2 + 11O2 -> 2Fe2O3 + 8SO2, => amount of SO2 produced = (60/120)*(8/4)*64 = 64 grams."
    },
    {
        "id": 291,
        "Question": "What is extent of reaction of a in the reaction 2CO + O2 -> 2CO2, if 20 moles CO2 is produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5",
            "b)\t10",
            "c)\t20",
            "d)\t40"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Extent of reaction = (20 – 0)/2 = 10."
    },
    {
        "id": 292,
        "Question": "N2 + 2O2 -> 2NO2, what is the extent of reaction if 6 moles of NO2 is produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3",
            "b)\t6",
            "c)\t12",
            "d)\t18"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Extent of reaction = (6 – 0)/2 = 3."
    },
    {
        "id": 293,
        "Question": "CH4 + 2O2 -> CO2 + 2H2O, what is the extent of reaction if only 50% of 96 grams of CH4 is consumed?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Moles of CH4 = 96/16 = 6, => Extent of reaction = (6*0.5 – 6)/(-1) = 3."
    },
    {
        "id": 294,
        "Question": "H2O2 + H2 -> 2H2O, if the extent of reaction is 10, how much water is produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 moles",
            "b)\t20 moles",
            "c)\t30 moles",
            "d)\t40 moles"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 10 = (x – 0)/2, => x = 20 moles."
    },
    {
        "id": 295,
        "Question": "4FeS2 + 11O2 -> 2Fe2O3 + 8SO2, what is the extent of reaction if 512 grams of SO2 is produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Moles of SO2 = 512/64 = 8, => Extent of reaction = (8 – 0)/8 = 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 296,
        "Question": "Which of the following is true about limiting reagents?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tConsumes completely",
            "b)\tConsumes partially",
            "c)\tDoes not react",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Limiting reagent is the reactant which reacts completely in a reaction."
    },
    {
        "id": 297,
        "Question": "Which of the following is true about excess reagents?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tConsumes completely",
            "b)\tConsumes partially",
            "c)\tDoes not react",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Excess reagents are reactants which are excess in amount and reacts partially in a reaction."
    },
    {
        "id": 298,
        "Question": "4 moles of CH4 and 4 moles of O2 are reacted, then what type of reactant CH4 is?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tLimiting reagent",
            "b)\tExcess reagent",
            "c)\tCan’t say",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is CH4 + 2O2 -> CO2 + 2H2O, => If 4 moles of O2 are reacting only 2 moles of CH4 will react, this means CH4 is an excess reagent."
    },
    {
        "id": 299,
        "Question": "2 moles of N2 and 8 moles of H2 are reacted, then what type of reactant N2 is?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tLimiting reagent",
            "b)\tExcess reagent",
            "c)\tCan’t say",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is N2 + 3H2 -> 2NH3, => If 2 moles of N2 are reacting only 6 moles of H2 will react, this means H2 is an excess reagent and N2 is a limiting reagent."
    },
    {
        "id": 300,
        "Question": "4 moles of CO and 2 moles of O2 are reacted, then what type of reactant O2 is?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tLimiting reagent",
            "b)\tExcess reagent",
            "c)\tCan’t say",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is 2CO + O2 -> 2CO2, => If 4 moles of CO are reacting, 2 moles of O2 will react, this means none of the two is limiting reagent or excess reagent."
    },
    {
        "id": 301,
        "Question": "If 28 grams of N2 and 10 grams of H2 are reacted, how much NH3 will produce?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t17 grams",
            "b)\t34 grams",
            "c)\t51 grams",
            "d)\t54 grams"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Moles of N2 = 28/28 = 1, moles of H2 = 10/2 = 5, Reaction is N2 + 3H2 -> 2NH3, => N2 is limiting reagent, => moles of NH3 = 2*1 = 2, => weight of NH3 = 2*17 = 34 grams."
    },
    {
        "id": 302,
        "Question": "10 moles of C6H12 reacted with 18 moles of O2, how many moles of CO2 will produce?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3",
            "b)\t6",
            "c)\t9",
            "d)\t12"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is C6H12 + 9O2 -> 6CO2 + 3H2O, => O2 is the limiting reagent, => moles of CO2 = (18/9)*6 = 12."
    },
    {
        "id": 303,
        "Question": "5 moles of Al2O3 are reacted with 10 moles H2SO4, how many moles of Al2(SO4)3 will produce?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3.33",
            "b)\t10",
            "c)\t30",
            "d)\t33.3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is Al2O3 + 3H2SO4 -> Al2(SO4)3 + 3H2O, =>  moles of Al2(SO4)3 = 10/3 = 3.33. "
    },
    {
        "id": 304,
        "Question": "10 grams of NaCl and 1.8 grams of H2O are reacted, how much sodium hydroxide will produce?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4 grams",
            "b)\t10 grams",
            "c)\t40 grams",
            "d)\t80 grams"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is NaCl + H2O -> NaOH + HCl, in this case H2O is a limiting reagent, => moles of NaOH = moles of H2O = 1.8/18 = 0.1, => weight of NaOH = 0.1*40 = 4 grams."
    },
    {
        "id": 305,
        "Question": "1 mole of potassium permanganate and 1 mole of ferrous sulfide are reacted in presence of excess hydrochloric acid, how many moles of Ferric sulfate will produce?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10/18",
            "b)\t5/18",
            "c)\t1/18",
            "d)\t1/36"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is 18KMnO4 + 10FeS + 32H2SO4 -> 18MnSO4 + 5Fe2(SO4)3 + 9K2SO4 + 32H2O, => KMnO4 is limiting reagent, => moles of Fe2(SO4)3 = (5/18)*1 = 5/18."
    },
    {
        "id": 306,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 6 moles of CO and 3 moles of O2 and produced 4 moles of CO2, what is the extent of reaction?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The reaction is 2CO + O2 -> 2CO2, => Extent of reaction = (4 – 0)/2 = 2."
    },
    {
        "id": 307,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 6 moles of N2 and 9 moles of H2, if 3 moles of NH3 is produced, how many moles of H2 are left at the end?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1.5",
            "b)\t3",
            "c)\t4.5",
            "d)\t6"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The reaction is N2 + 3H2 -> 2NH3, => extent of reaction = (3 – 0)/2 = 1.5, => moles of H2 left = 9 – 1.5*3 = 4.5."
    },
    {
        "id": 308,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 10 moles of CH4 and 10 moles of O2, if the extent of reaction is 3, what are the moles of CO2 produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3",
            "b)\t6",
            "c)\t8",
            "d)\t12"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The chemical reaction is CH4 + 2O2 -> CO2 + 2H2O, => moles of CO2 produced = 3*1 = 3."
    },
    {
        "id": 309,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 10 moles of O2 and 10 moles of H2, if the extent of reaction is 5, how many moles of water is produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5",
            "b)\t10",
            "c)\t15",
            "d)\t20"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The chemical reaction is 2H2 + O2 -> 2H2O, => moles of H2O produced = 5*2 = 10."
    },
    {
        "id": 310,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 5 moles of KNO3 and some H2SO4, if the extent of reaction is 2, how many moles of H2SO4 were supplied?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t5",
            "d)\tCannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Since the final moles of H2SO4 are not given, initial moles cannot be determined."
    },
    {
        "id": 311,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with a 100 mole feed of composition 46% C3H7O4, 44% O2 and 10% N2, if 50% of the limiting reagent is converted into product, what is the extent of reaction?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The reaction is 4C3H7O4 + 11O2 -> 12CO2 + 14H2O, => limiting reagent is O2, => Extent of reaction = (44*0.5 – 44)/(-11) = 2."
    },
    {
        "id": 312,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with a feed of composition 46% C3H7O4, 44% O2 and 10% N2, if 50% of the limiting reagent is converted into product, what is the percentage of O2 in the product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10",
            "b)\t18",
            "c)\t38",
            "d)\t54"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The reaction is 4C3H7O4 + 11O2 -> 12CO2 + 14H2O, => Limiting reagent is O2. Let 100 moles of feed was supplied, => after the reaction, moles of CO2 = 24, moles of H2O = 28, moles of O2 = 22, moles of C3H7O4 = 38, moles of N2 = 10, => percentage of O2 = 18%."
    },
    {
        "id": 313,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with a feed of composition 46% C3H7O4, 44% O2 and 10% N2, if 50% of the limiting reagent is converted into product, what is the percentage of N2 in the product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t8",
            "b)\t18",
            "c)\t34",
            "d)\t46"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The reaction is 4C3H7O4 + 11O2 -> 12CO2 + 14H2O, => Limiting reagent is O2. Let 100 moles of feed was supplied, => after the reaction, moles of CO2 = 24, moles of H2O = 28, moles of O2 = 22, moles of C3H7O4 = 38, moles of N2 = 10, => percentage of N2 = 8%."
    },
    {
        "id": 314,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with a feed of composition 46% C3H7O4, 44% O2 and 10% N2, if 50% of the limiting reagent is converted into product, what is the percentage of C3H7O4 in the product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10",
            "b)\t16",
            "c)\t31",
            "d)\t43"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The reaction is 4C3H7O4 + 11O2 -> 12CO2 + 14H2O, => Limiting reagent is O2. Let 100 moles of feed was supplied, => after the reaction, moles of CO2 = 24, moles of H2O = 28, moles of O2 = 22, moles of C3H7O4 = 38, moles of N2 = 10, => percentage of C3H7O4 = 31%."
    },
    {
        "id": 315,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with a feed of composition 46% C3H7O4, 44% O2 and 10% N2, if 50% of the limiting reagent is converted into product, what is the percentage of H2O in the product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t15",
            "b)\t23",
            "c)\t39",
            "d)\t51"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The reaction is 4C3H7O4 + 11O2 -> 12CO2 + 14H2O, => Limiting reagent is O2. Let 100 moles of feed was supplied, => after the reaction, moles of CO2 = 24, moles of H2O = 28, moles of O2 = 22, moles of C3H7O4 = 38, moles of N2 = 10, => percentage of H2O = 23%."
    },
    {
        "id": 316,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with two steams with equal flow rates, stream-1 containing 75% SO2, 25% N2 and stream-2 containing pure H2S, if the product has 1200 grams of S, and the ratio of H2S to H2O is 5 and the ratio of SO2 to H2S is 2, what is the rate of streams?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 mole",
            "b)\t20 moles",
            "c)\t30 moles",
            "d)\t40 moles"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The reaction is 2H2S + SO2 -> 3S + H2O, => extent of reaction, E = (1200/32)/3 = 12.5, Let the rate be F. nSO2p = 2nH2Sp, => 0.75F – E = 2(F – 2E), => 1.25F = 3(12.5), => F = 30 moles."
    },
    {
        "id": 317,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with two steams with equal flow rates, stream-1 containing 75% SO2, 25% N2 and stream-2 containing pure H2S, if the product has 1200 grams of S, and the ratio of H2S to H2O is 5 and the ratio of SO2 to H2S is 2, what fraction of limiting reagent is converted into product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.21",
            "b)\t0.46",
            "c)\t0.73",
            "d)\t0.83"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The reaction is 2H2S + SO2 -> 3S + H2O, => extent of reaction, E = (1200/32)/3 = 12.5, Let the rate be F. nSO2p = 2nH2Sp, => 0.75F – E = 2(F – 2E), => 1.25F = 3(12.5), => F = 30 moles, => limiting reagent is H2S, => fraction of H2S converted into product = 2E/F = 2(1.25)/3 = 0.83."
    },
    {
        "id": 318,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with two steams with equal flow rates, stream-1 containing 75% SO2, 25% N2 and stream-2 containing pure H2S, if the product has 1200 grams of S, and the ratio of H2S to H2O is 5 and the ratio of SO2 to H2S is 2, how many moles of water are produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The reaction is 2H2S + SO2 -> 3S + H2O, => extent of reaction, E = (1200/32)/3 = 12.5, Let the rate be F. nSO2p = 2nH2Sp, => 0.75F – E = 2(F – 2E), => 1.25F = 3(12.5), => F = 30 moles. 5nH2Op = nH2Sp, => 5 nH2Op = 30 – 2(12.5) = 5, => nH2Op = 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 319,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with two steams with equal flow rates, stream-1 containing 75% SO2, 25% N2 and stream-2 containing pure H2S, if the product has 1200 grams of S, and the ratio of H2S to H2O is 5 and the ratio of SO2 to H2S is 2, what fraction of excess reagent is converted into product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.23",
            "b)\t0.55",
            "c)\t0.74",
            "d)\t0.87"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The reaction is 2H2S + SO2 -> 3S + H2O, => extent of reaction, E = (1200/32)/3 = 12.5, Let the rate be F. nSO2p = 2nH2Sp, => 0.75F – E = 2(F – 2E), => 1.25F = 3(12.5), => F = 30 moles. => The excess reagent is SO2, => fraction of SO2 converted into product = E/0.75F = 12.5/(0.75*30) = 0.55."
    },
    {
        "id": 320,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with two steams with equal flow rates, stream-1 containing 75% SO2, 25% N2 and stream-2 containing pure H2S, if the product has 1200 grams of S, and the ratio of H2S to H2O is 5 and the ratio of SO2 to H2S is 2, what is percentage of Sulfur in the product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t23%",
            "b)\t47%",
            "c)\t61%",
            "d)\t84%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The reaction is 2H2S + SO2 -> 3S + H2O, => extent of reaction, E = (1200/32)/3 = 12.5, Let the rate be F. nSO2p = 2nH2Sp, => 0.75F – E = 2(F – 2E), => 1.25F = 3(12.5), => F = 30 moles. => Moles of SO2 = 0.75F – E = 10, moles of H2S = F – 2E = 5, moles of N2 = 7.5, moles of S = 37.5, moles of H2O = 1, => percentage of sulfur = 61%."
    },
    {
        "id": 321,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 5 moles each of CH3OH and O2, and the following reactions occur, CH3OH + 1/2O2 -> CH2O + H2O and then CH2O + 1/2O2 -> CO + H2O, the conversion of methanol is 80% in first reaction, and conversion of CH2O is 50% in second reaction. How many moles of CO are produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Extent of reaction E1 = (-0.8)/(-1) = 0.8, E2 = (-0.5)/(-1) = 0.5, => moles of CO = (0.8*5)*0.5 = 2."
    },
    {
        "id": 322,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 5 moles each of CH3OH and O2, and the following reactions occur, CH3OH + 1/2O2 -> CH2O + H2O and then CH2O + 1/2O2 -> CO + H2O, the conversion of methanol is 80% in first reaction, and conversion of CH2O is 50% in second reaction. How many moles of H2O are produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2",
            "b)\t3",
            "c)\t5",
            "d)\t6"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Extent of reaction E1 = (-0.8)/(-1) = 0.8, E2 = (-0.5)/(-1) = 0.5, => moles of H2O = (0.8*5) + (0.8*5)*0.5 = 6."
    },
    {
        "id": 323,
        "Question": " A reactor is supplied with 5 moles each of CH3OH and O2, and the following reactions occur, CH3OH + 1/2O2 -> CH2O + H2O and then CH2O + 1/2O2 -> CO + H2O, the conversion of methanol is 80% in first reaction, and conversion of CH2O is 50% in second reaction. How many moles of CH2O came out of the reactor?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Extent of reaction E1 = (-0.8)/(-1) = 0.8, E2 = (-0.5)/(-1) = 0.5, => moles of CH2O unreacted = 0.8*5 – (0.8*5)*0.5 = 2."
    },
    {
        "id": 324,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 5 moles each of CH3OH and O2, and the following reactions occur, CH3OH + 1/2O2 -> CH2O + H2O and then CH2O + 1/2O2 -> CO + H2O, the conversion of methanol is 80% in first reaction, and conversion of CH2O is 50% in second reaction. How many moles of O2 are there in the products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1.75",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3.25",
            "d)\t5.5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Extent of reaction E1 = (-0.8)/(-1) = 0.8, E2 = (-0.5)/(-1) = 0.5, => moles of O2 = (2.5 – 2.5*0.8) + (2.5 – 2.5*0.5) = 1.75."
    },
    {
        "id": 325,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 5 moles each of CH3OH and O2, and the following reactions occur, CH3OH + 1/2O2 -> CH2O + H2O and then CH2O + 1/2O2 -> CO + H2O, the conversion of methanol is 80% in first reaction, and conversion of CH2O is 50% in second reaction. How many moles of CH3OH are there in the products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Extent of reaction E1 = (-0.8)/(-1) = 0.8, E2 = (-0.5)/(-1) = 0.5, => moles of CH3OH = 5 – 5*0.8 = 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 326,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with C6H12O6 and the following reactions occur C6H12O6 -> 2C2H5OH + 2CO2 and C6H12O6 –> 2C2H3CO2H + 2H2O, 360 grams of pure glucose is supplied and 44 grams of CO2 was produced, what 90 grams of glucose left unreacted, how many grams of propenoic acid was produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t18",
            "b)\t36",
            "c)\t72",
            "d)\t144"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Weight of glucose reacted in first reaction = (44/44)*(1/2)*180 = 90 grams, => (360 – 90 – 90) = 180 grams of glucose reacted in second reaction, => weight of propenoic acid produced = 2*(180/180)*72 = 144 grams."
    },
    {
        "id": 327,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with C6H12O6 and the following reactions occur C6H12O6 -> 2C2H5OH + 2CO2 and C6H12O6 –> 2C2H3CO2H + 2H2O, 360 grams of pure glucose is supplied and 44 grams of CO2 was produced, what 90 grams of glucose left unreacted, how many grams of ethanol was produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t23",
            "b)\t46",
            "c)\t92",
            "d)\t186"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Moles of glucose reacted in first reaction = 90/180 = 0.5, => weight of ethanol produced = 2*0.5*46 = 46 grams."
    },
    {
        "id": 328,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with C6H12O6 and the following reactions occur C6H12O6 -> 2C2H5OH + 2CO2 and C6H12O6 –> 2C2H3CO2H + 2H2O, 360 grams of pure glucose is supplied and 44 grams of CO2 was produced, what 90 grams of glucose left unreacted, how many grams of water was produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t9",
            "b)\t18",
            "c)\t36",
            "d)\t54"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Weight of glucose reacted in first reaction = ½*(66/44)*180 = 135 grams => Weight of glucose reacted in second reaction = 360 – 180 – 135 = 45 grams, => moles of water produced = 2*(45/180)*18 = 9 grams."
    },
    {
        "id": 329,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 5 moles of C4H10, and it undergoes following reactions C4H10 + 4H2O -> 4CO + 9H2 and C4H10 + 6.5O2 -> 4CO2 + 5H2O, if 8 moles of CO2 was produced and 2 moles of C4H10 remains unreacted, what are the number of moles of water produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2",
            "b)\t5",
            "c)\t7.5",
            "d)\t10"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Extent of second reaction = (8 – 0)/4 = 2, => moles of water produced = 5*2 = 10."
    },
    {
        "id": 330,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 5 moles of C4H10, and it undergoes following reactions C4H10 + 4H2O -> 4CO + 9H2 and C4H10 + 6.5O2 -> 4CO2 + 5H2O, if 8 moles of CO2 was produced and 2 moles of C4H10 remains unreacted, what are the number of moles of CO produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Extent of second reaction = (8 – 0)/4 = 2, => moles of C4H10 reacted in second reaction = 2*1 = 2, => moles of C4H10 reacted in first reaction = 5 – 2 – 2 = 1, => extent of first reaction = (0 – 1)/(-1) = 1, => moles of CO produced = 4*1 = 4."
    },
    {
        "id": 331,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 12 moles of C, and it undergoes following reactions C + 0.5O2 -> CO and C + O2 -> CO2, if 4 moles of CO2 was produced and 4 moles of C remains unreacted, what are the number of moles of CO produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Extent of second reaction = (4 – 0)/1 = 4, => moles of C reacted in second reaction = 4*1 = 4, => moles of C reacted in first reaction = 12 – 4 – 4 = 4, => extent of first reaction = (0 – 4)/(-1) = 4, => moles of CO produced = 4*1 = 4."
    },
    {
        "id": 332,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 15 moles of C, and it undergoes following reactions C + 0.5O2 -> CO and C + O2 -> CO2, if 8 moles of CO2 was produced and 3 moles of C remains unreacted, what are the number of moles of CO produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Extent of second reaction = (8 – 0)/1 = 8, => moles of C reacted in second reaction = 8*1 = 8, => moles of C reacted in first reaction = 15 – 8 – 3 = 4, => extent of first reaction = (0 – 4)/(-1) = 4, => moles of CO produced = 4*1 = 4."
    },
    {
        "id": 333,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 25 moles of C, and it undergoes following reactions C + 0.5O2 -> CO and C + O2 -> CO2, if 13 moles of CO2 was produced and 5 moles of C remains unreacted, what are the number of moles of CO produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t3",
            "c)\t5",
            "d)\t7"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Extent of second reaction = (13 – 0)/1 = 13, => moles of C reacted in second reaction = 13*1 = 13, => moles of C reacted in first reaction = 25 – 13 – 5 = 7, => extent of first reaction = (0 – 7)/(-1) = 7, => moles of CO produced = 7*1 = 7."
    },
    {
        "id": 334,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 20 moles of C, and it undergoes following reactions C + 0.5O2 -> CO and C + O2 -> CO2, if 10 moles of CO2 was produced and 5 moles of C remains unreacted, what are the number of moles of CO produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t3",
            "c)\t5",
            "d)\t7"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Extent of second reaction = (10 – 0)/1 = 10, => moles of C reacted in second reaction = 10*1 = 10, => moles of C reacted in first reaction = 20 – 10 – 5 = 5, => extent of first reaction = (0 – 5)/(-1) = 5, => moles of CO produced = 5*1 = 5."
    },
    {
        "id": 335,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 45 moles of C, and it undergoes following reactions C + 0.5O2 -> CO and C + O2 -> CO2, if 25 moles of CO2 was produced and 6 moles of C remains unreacted, what are the number of moles of CO produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t6",
            "b)\t9",
            "c)\t14",
            "d)\t17"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Extent of second reaction = (25 – 0)/1 = 25, => moles of C reacted in second reaction = 25*1 = 25, => moles of C reacted in first reaction = 45 – 25 – 6 = 14, => extent of first reaction = (0 – 14)/(-1) = 14, => moles of CO produced = 14*1 = 14."
    },
    {
        "id": 336,
        "Question": "A reactor supplied with CO2 and H2O, the product contains 10% H2CO3 and 90% H2O, what is the feed rate of CO2, if the rate of product is 50 mole?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 mole",
            "b)\t10 mole",
            "c)\t25 mole",
            "d)\t50 mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The reaction is CO2 + H2O -> H2CO3. Let the rates of CO2 and H2O be F and W respectively. Element balances, C: F(1) = 0.1P(1), => 10F = P, => F = 5 mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 337,
        "Question": "A reactor supplied with CO2 and H2O, the product contains H2O and H2CO3, if the rate of CO2 is 10 mole, what is the percentage of H2CO3 in products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10",
            "b)\t50",
            "c)\t75",
            "d)\t100"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The reaction is CO2 + H2O -> H2CO3. Let the rate of CO2 and H2O and product be F and W respectively, and the fraction of H2CO3 in products be x. Element balances, C: F(1) = x*10(1), => F = 10x, => x = 1, => percentage of H2CO3 = 100%."
    },
    {
        "id": 338,
        "Question": "A reactor supplied with CO2 and H2O, the product contains H2O and H2CO3, if the rate of H2O is 10 mole, what is the rate of products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 mole",
            "b)\t10 mole",
            "c)\t15 mole",
            "d)\t20 mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The reaction is CO2 + H2O -> H2CO3. Let the rate of products be P, and the fraction of H2CO3 in products be x, material balances, H: 10(2) = x*P(2) + (1 – x)*P(2), => P = 10 mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 339,
        "Question": "A reactor supplied with CO2 and H2O, the product contains CO2, H2O and H2CO3, if the rate of products is 10 mole and percentage of CO2 in products is 20%, what is the feed rate of H2O?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 mole",
            "b)\t4 mole",
            "c)\t8 mole",
            "d)\t10 mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The reaction is CO2 + H2O -> H2CO3. Let the rate of H2O be W, and percentage of H2O in products be x. Material balances, H: W(2) = x*10(2) + (1 – x – 0.2)*10(2), => W = 8 mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 340,
        "Question": "A reactor supplied with CO2 and H2O, the product contains 40% CO2, 30% H2O and 30% H2CO3, what is the ratio of feed rate of CO2 and rate of products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.3",
            "b)\t0.4",
            "c)\t0.7",
            "d)\t0.9"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The reaction is CO2 + H2O -> H2CO3. Let the rate of CO2, H2O and H2CO3 be F, W and P respectively. Element balances, C: F(1) = 0.4P(1) + 0.3P(1), => F/P = 0.7."
    },
    {
        "id": 341,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with Hexane and hydrogen to produce 20% methane, 30% propane and 50% butane, what is the ratio of hydrogen consumed and the hexane reacted?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.21",
            "b)\t0.45",
            "c)\t0.59",
            "d)\t0.73"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The reaction is 2C6H14 + 2H2 -> CH4 + 2C3H8 + C5H12, Let the rate of Hexane, hydrogen and products be F, W and P respectively. Element balances, C: 2F(6) = 0.2P(1) + 2*0.3P(3) + 0.5P(5), => 8F = 3P, H: 2F(14) + 2W(2) = 0.2P(4) + 2*0.3P(8) + 0.5P(12), => 7F + W = 2.9P, => W/F= 2.2/3 = 0.73."
    },
    {
        "id": 342,
        "Question": " A reactor is supplied with 10 mole of Hexane and some hydrogen to produce 20% methane, 30% propane and 50% butane, what is the rate of products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 mole",
            "b)\t16.6 mole",
            "c)\t26.6 mole",
            "d)\t40 mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The reaction is 2C6H14 + 2H2 -> CH4 + 2C3H8 + C5H12, Let the rate of products be P. Element balance, C: 2*10(6) = 0.2P(1) + 2*0.3P(3) + 0.5P(5), => 120 = 4.5P, => P = 26.6 mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 343,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with glucose and oxygen to produce 40% CO2, 60% H2O, what is the ratio of glucose reacted and products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.2",
            "b)\t0.4",
            "c)\t0.6",
            "d)\t0.8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The reaction is C6H12O6 + 6O2 -> 6CO2 + 6H2O, Let the rate of glucose and products be F and P, Element balances, C: F(6) = 6*0.4P(1), => F/P = 0.4."
    },
    {
        "id": 344,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 10 moles glucose and excess oxygen to produce 40% CO2, 60% H2O, what is the rate of products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25 mole",
            "b)\t50 mole",
            "c)\t75 mole",
            "d)\t100 mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The reaction is C6H12O6 + 6O2 -> 6CO2 + 6H2O, Let the rate of products be P. Element balances, C: 10(6) = 6*0.4P(1), => P = 25 mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 345,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 10 moles glucose and excess oxygen to produce CO2 and H2O, if the rate of products is 25 moles, what is the percentage of CO2 in the products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.1",
            "b)\t0.2",
            "c)\t0.3",
            "d)\t0.4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The reaction is C6H12O6 + 6O2 -> 6CO2 + 6H2O. Let the fraction of CO2 be x, Element balances, C: 10(6) = 6*x*5(1), => x = 0.4."
    },
    {
        "id": 346,
        "Question": "Ethane is supplied at the rate F with oxygen at the rate W and leaves the following products CO2, H2O, O2, C2H6 and H2 at the rate P. How many independent element balances are possible?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The reaction is C2H6 + 3.5O2 -> 2CO2 + 3H2O, since there are three elements C, H and O, we can write 3 independent material balances."
    },
    {
        "id": 347,
        "Question": "Ethane is supplied with chlorine in a reactor, how many independent element balances can you write?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The reaction is C2H6 + Cl2 -> C2H5Cl + HCl, Element balance C: 2F = 2xP, H: 6F = 5xP + (1 – x)P, Cl: 2W = xP + (1 – x)P, => The equations are F = xP, 6F = 4xP + P, and 2W = P, which are independent."
    },
    {
        "id": 348,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 2 streams both at same rates, one has pure Cl2, and another has pure C2H6, if the product has 20% C2H5Cl and 80% HCl, what is the ratio of rate of feed and rate of product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.2",
            "b)\t0.5",
            "c)\t2",
            "d)\t5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The reaction is C2H6 + Cl2 -> C2H5Cl + HCl, Let the rate of feed and products be F and P respectively. Element balances, C: F(2) = 0.2P(2), => F/P = 0.2."
    },
    {
        "id": 349,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 2 streams both at same rates, one has pure Cl2, and another has pure C2H6, if the product has 20% C2H5Cl and 50% HCl and 30% C2H6, what is the ratio of rate of feed and rate of product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.2",
            "b)\t0.5",
            "c)\t2",
            "d)\t5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The reaction is C2H6 + Cl2 -> C2H5Cl + HCl, Let the rate of feed and products be F and P respectively. Element balances, C: F(2) – 0.3P(2) = 0.2P(2), => F/P = 0.5."
    },
    {
        "id": 350,
        "Question": "A reactor is supplied with 2 streams both at the rate 5 mole, one has 40% Cl2 and 60% N2, and another has pure C2H6, if the product has C2H5Cl, HCl and N2 at the rate 20 mole, what is the percentage of HCl in products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t15%",
            "c)\t25%",
            "d)\t30%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The reaction is C2H6 + Cl2 -> C2H5Cl + HCl, Let the fraction of C2H5Cl, HCl and N2 be x, y and (1 – x – y) respectively. Element balances, Cl: 0.4*5(2) = x*10(1) + y*10(1), => x + y = 0.4, C: 5(2) = x*20(2), => x = 0.25, => y = 0.4 – 0.25 = 0.15, => percentage of HCl = 15%."
    },
    {
        "id": 351,
        "Question": "What is the percentage of excess air, if 10 moles of air entered the process and only 5 moles of that are required?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t50%",
            "c)\t75%",
            "d)\t100%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Percentage of excess air = 100*(10 – 5)/5 = 100%."
    },
    {
        "id": 352,
        "Question": "What is the percentage of excess air if 50 grams of air is in excess and 150 grams of air enters the process?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t25%",
            "c)\t50%",
            "d)\t100%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Percentage of excess air = 100*50/(150 – 50) = 50%."
    },
    {
        "id": 353,
        "Question": "10 moles of ethane is supplied with 49 moles of oxygen, what is the percentage of excess oxygen?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20%",
            "b)\t40%",
            "c)\t50%",
            "d)\t70%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The balanced reaction is C2H6 + 3.5O2 -> 2CO2 + 3H2O, => O2 required = 3.5*10 = 35 moles, => percentage of excess oxygen = 100*(49 – 35)/35 = 40%."
    },
    {
        "id": 354,
        "Question": "The extent of a reaction is 10, and the stoichiometric coefficient of O2 is 2.5, if the moles of O2 entering the process is 45, what is the percentage of excess air?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20%",
            "b)\t40%",
            "c)\t60%",
            "d)\t80%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Moles of O2 required = 10*2.5 = 25, => Percentage of excess air = 100*(45 – 25)/25 = 80%."
    },
    {
        "id": 355,
        "Question": "144 grams of C5H12 is burnt with 64 grams O2, and 44 grams of CO2 is formed, what is the percentage of excess O2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25%",
            "b)\t50%",
            "c)\t75%",
            "d)\t100%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The balanced chemical reaction is C5H12 + 8O2 -> 5CO2 + 6H2O, => Extent of reaction = (44/44 – 0)/5 = 0.2. Moles of O2 entered the process = 64/32 = 2, Moles of O2 required = 0.2*8 = 1.6, => Percentage of excess oxygen = 100*(2 – 1.6)/1.6 = 25%."
    },
    {
        "id": 356,
        "Question": "Ethene is burnt with 50% of excess air, what is the percentage of CO2 in the products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t11.11%",
            "b)\t36.36%",
            "c)\t66.66%",
            "d)\t72.72%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The reaction is C2H4 + 3O2 -> 2CO2 + 2H2O. Basis: 10 moles of C2H4, => moles of O2 reacted = 30, => moles of O2 entered the process = 45, => moles of CO2, H2O and O2 in products are 20, 20 and 15 respectively, => percentage of CO2 = 20/55*100 = 36.36%."
    },
    {
        "id": 357,
        "Question": "Ethene is burnt with 150% of excess air, what is the percentage of O2 in the products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12.5%",
            "b)\t33.3%",
            "c)\t45.4%",
            "d)\t52.9%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The reaction is C2H4 + 3O2 -> 2CO2 + 2H2O. Basis: 10 moles of C2H4, => moles of O2 reacted = 30, => moles of O2 entered the process = 75, => moles of CO2, H2O and O2 in products are 20, 20 and 45 respectively, => percentage of O2 = 45/85*100 = 52.9%."
    },
    {
        "id": 358,
        "Question": "Pentane is burnt with 100% of excess air, what is the percentage of H2O in the products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12.4%",
            "b)\t34.6%",
            "c)\t42.1%",
            "d)\t56.9%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The reaction is C5H12 + 8O2 -> 5CO2 + 6H2O. Basis: 10 moles of C5H12, => moles of O2 reacted = 80, => moles of O2 entered the process = 160, => moles of CO2, H2O and O2 in products are 50, 60 and 80, => percentage of H2O = 80/190*100 = 42.1%."
    },
    {
        "id": 359,
        "Question": "Propane is burnt with 20% excess O2, what is the percentage of CO2 in products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12.5%",
            "b)\t25%",
            "c)\t45%",
            "d)\t75.5%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The reaction is C3H8 + 5O2 -> 3CO2 + 4H2O. Basis: 10 moles of C3H8, => moles of O2 reacted = 50, => moles of O2 entered the process = 60, => moles of CO2, H2O and O2 in products are 30, 40 and 10, => percentage of CO2 = 10/80*100 = 12.5%."
    },
    {
        "id": 360,
        "Question": "Octane is burnt with 40% excess O2, what is the percentage of CO2 in products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t18.18%",
            "b)\t36.36%",
            "c)\t54.54%",
            "d)\t72.72%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The reaction is C8H18 + 12.5O2 -> 8CO2 + 9H2O. Basis: 10 moles of C8H18, => moles of O2 reacted = 125, => moles of O2 entered the process = 175, => moles of CO2, H2O and O2 in products are 80, 90 and 50, => percentage of CO2 = 80/220*100 = 36.36%."
    },
    {
        "id": 361,
        "Question": "Methane is at the rate 50 moles is supplied to a reactor with air at the rate 1000 moles, the reactor leaves O2, N2, CO2 and H2O, what is the rate of products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t900 moles",
            "b)\t950 moles",
            "c)\t1000 moles",
            "d)\t1050 moles"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The reaction is CH4 + 2O2 -> CO2 + 2H2O. O2 supplied = 1000*21/100 = 210 moles, N2 supplied = 1000*79/100 = 790 moles, => O2 unreacted = 210 – 100 = 110 moles, CO2 formed = 50 moles, H2O formed = 100 moles. => Rate of products = 790 + 110 + 50 + 100 = 1050 moles."
    },
    {
        "id": 362,
        "Question": "Methane is at the rate 50 moles is supplied to a reactor with air at the rate 1000 moles, the reactor leaves O2, N2, CO2 and H2O, what is the percentage of O2 in products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10.4%",
            "b)\t25.8%",
            "c)\t45.6%",
            "d)\t78.2%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The reaction is CH4 + 2O2 -> CO2 + 2H2O. O2 supplied = 1000*21/100 = 210 moles, N2 supplied = 1000*79/100 = 790 moles, => O2 unreacted = 210 – 100 = 110 moles, CO2 formed = 50 moles, H2O formed = 100 moles. => Percentage of O2 = 110/1050*100 = 10.4%."
    },
    {
        "id": 363,
        "Question": "Methane is at the rate 50 moles is supplied to a reactor with air at the rate 1000 moles, the reactor leaves O2, N2, CO2 and H2O, what is the percentage of CO2 in products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4.7%",
            "b)\t10.4%",
            "c)\t16.5%",
            "d)\t24.3%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The reaction is CH4 + 2O2 -> CO2 + 2H2O. O2 supplied = 1000*21/100 = 210 moles, N2 supplied = 1000*79/100 = 790 moles, => O2 unreacted = 210 – 100 = 110 moles, CO2 formed = 50 moles, H2O formed = 100 moles. => Percentage of CO2 = 50/1050*100 = 4.7%."
    },
    {
        "id": 364,
        "Question": "Methane is at the rate 50 moles is supplied to a reactor with air at the rate 1000 moles, the reactor leaves O2, N2, CO2 and H2O, what is the percentage of N2 in products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25.4%",
            "b)\t45.2%",
            "c)\t75.2%",
            "d)\t95.6%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The reaction is CH4 + 2O2 -> CO2 + 2H2O. O2 supplied = 1000*21/100 = 210 moles, N2 supplied = 1000*79/100 = 790 moles, => O2 unreacted = 210 – 100 = 110 moles, CO2 formed = 50 moles, H2O formed = 100 moles. => Percentage of N2 = 790/1050*100 = 75.2%."
    },
    {
        "id": 365,
        "Question": "Methane is at the rate 50 moles is supplied to a reactor with air at the rate 1000 moles, the reactor leaves O2, N2, CO2 and H2O, what is the percentage of H2O in products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5.8%",
            "b)\t9.5%",
            "c)\t15.4%",
            "d)\t20.7%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The reaction is CH4 + 2O2 -> CO2 + 2H2O. O2 supplied = 1000*21/100 = 210 moles, N2 supplied = 1000*79/100 = 790 moles, => Osub>2 unreacted = 210 – 100 = 110 moles, COsub>2 formed = 50 moles, Hsub>2O formed = 100 moles. => Percentage of H2O = 100/1050*100 = 9.5%."
    },
    {
        "id": 366,
        "Question": "What is the value of C?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t400 Kg/hr",
            "b)\t689.5 Kg/hr",
            "c)\t819.6 Kg/hr",
            "d)\t959.2 Kg/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: 10 + 20 = P + 10 + 5, => P = 15 mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 367,
        "Question": "What is the value of W?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t159.2 Kg/hr",
            "b)\t281.3 Kg/hr",
            "c)\t465.7 Kg/hr",
            "d)\t633.8 Kg/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: 10 + 20 = 5 + P, => P = 25 mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 368,
        "Question": "What is the value of F?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t98.5 Kg/hr",
            "b)\t131.1 Kg/hr",
            "c)\t167.7 Kg/hr",
            "d)\t256.4 Kg/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: 10 = P + 5, => P = 5 mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 369,
        "Question": "What is the value of D?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t32.3 Kg/hr",
            "b)\t49.1 Kg/hr",
            "c)\t85.6 Kg/hr",
            "d)\t105.3 Kg/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: F = 15 + 10 = 25 mole, P + 20 = F = 25, => P = 5 mole, => F*P = 125."
    },
    {
        "id": 370,
        "Question": "What is the value of W?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t227.5 mole/hr",
            "b)\t479.1 mole/hr",
            "c)\t568.2 mole/hr",
            "d)\t721.4 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 2 recycle streams are there which goes from second reactor to first."
    },
    {
        "id": 371,
        "Question": "What is the value of C?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t104.1 mole/hr",
            "b)\t213.5 mole/hr",
            "c)\t342.2 mole/hr",
            "d)\t416.4 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: There are three recycle streams, from second to first, from third to first, from second to first."
    },
    {
        "id": 372,
        "Question": "What is the value of C?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t945.5 mole/hr",
            "b)\t1874.6 mole/hr",
            "c)\t2474.5 mole/hr",
            "d)\t3951.2 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: There are two recycle streams, one from top reactor to left most reactor and other from right most to left most."
    },
    {
        "id": 373,
        "Question": "What is the value of F for the B solution to remain 80% KOH if the recycle stream is removed?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t123.1 mole/hr",
            "b)\t666.5 mole/hr",
            "c)\t988.4 mole/hr",
            "d)\t1499.8 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Material balance for whole process, A = P + D, => P = 2 mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 374,
        "Question": "What is the value of B?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t18.9 mole/hr",
            "b)\t38.6 mole/hr",
            "c)\t45.2 mole/hr",
            "d)\t72.1 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Any reactor in which recycled matter goes in is a mixer."
    },
    {
        "id": 375,
        "Question": "What is the value of H?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t250 mole/hr",
            "b)\t400 mole/hr",
            "c)\t525 mole/hr",
            "d)\t750 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Overall NaOH balance, 1000*0.5 = P [0.9*1 + 0.1*0.6], => P = 520.8 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 376,
        "Question": "What is the value of G?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t50 mole/hr",
            "b)\t100 mole/hr",
            "c)\t150 mole/hr",
            "d)\t200 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Overall water balance, 1000*0.5 = 520.8*0.1*0.6 + W*1, => W = 479.1 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 377,
        "Question": "What is the value of C?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t126.1 mole/hr",
            "b)\t150.8 mole/hr",
            "c)\t178.4 mole/hr",
            "d)\t196.3 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: First reactor balance, KOH: 1000*0.5 + C*0.6 = B*0.8, => 4B = 3C + 2500, H2O: 1000*0.5 + C*0.4 = 479.1*1 + B*0.2, => 209 + 4C = 2B, solving both equations we get C = 416.4 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 378,
        "Question": "What is the value of W?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 mole/hr",
            "b)\t40 mole/hr",
            "c)\t50 mole/hr",
            "d)\t90 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: W = 10 + 40 = 50 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 379,
        "Question": "What is the value of P?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 mole/hr",
            "b)\t10 mole/hr",
            "c)\t25 mole/hr",
            "d)\t40 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: P = 20% of W, => P = 50*20/100 = 10 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 380,
        "Question": "What is the overall extent of reaction?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5",
            "b)\t10",
            "c)\t20",
            "d)\t25"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Extent of reaction = (P – 0)/2 = (10 – 0)/2."
    },
    {
        "id": 381,
        "Question": "What is the overall fraction conversion?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t20%",
            "c)\t80%",
            "d)\t100%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Overall fraction conversion = (10 – 0)/10*100 = 100%."
    },
    {
        "id": 382,
        "Question": "What is the single pass fraction conversion?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t20%",
            "c)\t25%",
            "d)\t50%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Single pass fraction conversion = (50 – 40)/50*100 = 20%."
    },
    {
        "id": 383,
        "Question": "What is the extent of reaction?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3.6",
            "b)\t4.8",
            "c)\t6.4",
            "d)\t7.2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Extent of reaction = 4*0.9/1 = 3.6."
    },
    {
        "id": 384,
        "Question": "What are the moles of ethane in products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2.4",
            "b)\t3.6",
            "c)\t6.4",
            "d)\t7.2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Moles of C2H6 = 3.6*1 = 3.6."
    },
    {
        "id": 385,
        "Question": "What is the value of P?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3.6 mole/hr",
            "b)\t5.4 mole/hr",
            "c)\t6.4 mole/hr",
            "d)\t7.8 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The extent of reaction = (4*0.9)/1 = 3.6, => moles of C2H6 = 3.6, moles of H2 = 6 – 3.6 = 2.4, moles of C2H4 = 4 – 3.6 = 0.4, => P = 3.6 + 2.4 + 0.4 = 6.4 moles/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 386,
        "Question": "What is the value of R?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t18.4 mole/hr",
            "b)\t44 mole/hr",
            "c)\t70 mole/hr",
            "d)\t98.5 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: 0.2 = – (-3.6)/(4 + 0.2*R), => R = 70 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 387,
        "Question": "What is the value of G?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 mole/hr",
            "b)\t30 mole/hr",
            "c)\t70 mole/hr",
            "d)\t80 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: G = 10 + 70 = 80 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 388,
        "Question": "What is the extent of reaction?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4",
            "b)\t8",
            "c)\t12",
            "d)\t16"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Moles of C6H12 in feed = 80, => extent of reaction = (80*0.2 – 80)/(-1) = 64."
    },
    {
        "id": 389,
        "Question": "How many moles of benzene are formed?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t8",
            "b)\t16",
            "c)\t32",
            "d)\t64"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Moles of benzene formed = 64*1 = 64."
    },
    {
        "id": 390,
        "Question": "What is the value of P?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t64 mole/hr",
            "b)\t192 mole/hr",
            "c)\t272 mole/hr",
            "d)\t512 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Moles of benzene = 64, moles of hexane = 80 – 80*0.8 = 16, moles of H2 = 64*3 = 192, => P = 64 + 16 + 192 = 272 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 391,
        "Question": "What is the value of R?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t600 mole/hr",
            "b)\t720 mole/hr",
            "c)\t880 mole/hr",
            "d)\t960 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: 0.2 = – (-64)/(80 + 0.4*R), => R = 600 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 392,
        "Question": "What is the value of G?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t600 mole/hr",
            "b)\t700 mole/hr",
            "c)\t800 mole/hr",
            "d)\t900 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: G = 100 + 600 = 700 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 393,
        "Question": "A bypass stream does not go through which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tMixer",
            "b)\tProcess",
            "c)\tSeparator",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A bypass stream directly goes from divider to separator skipping the process."
    },
    {
        "id": 394,
        "Question": "Which of the following does the purge stream comes from?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tFeed stream",
            "b)\tProduct stream",
            "c)\tRecycle stream",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Purge stream is the removal of unwanted material from the recycle stream."
    },
    {
        "id": 395,
        "Question": "Which of the following composition can be controlled by a bypass stream?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tExit stream",
            "b)\tFeed",
            "c)\tProcess",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Bypass stream can be used to control the composition of a final stream."
    },
    {
        "id": 396,
        "Question": "Which of the following composition is controlled by purge stream?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tFeed",
            "b)\tProduct stream",
            "c)\tRecycle stream",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Composition of recycle stream can be controlled by purge stream."
    },
    {
        "id": 397,
        "Question": "Which of the following is decreased by the bypass stream?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tFeed",
            "b)\tProduct",
            "c)\tFeed & Product",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Bypass stream decreases the feed and increases the product."
    },
    {
        "id": 398,
        "Question": "What is the value of P?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 mole/hr",
            "b)\t10 mole/hr",
            "c)\t15 mole/hr",
            "d)\t20 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Overall CH4 balance: 0.6*20 = 0.8*P, => P = 15 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 399,
        "Question": "What is the value of W?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 mole/hr",
            "b)\t10 mole/hr",
            "c)\t20 mole/hr",
            "d)\t25 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Overall C2H6 balance: 0.4*20 = 0.2*15 + 1*W, => W = 5 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 400,
        "Question": "What is the value of G?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12.5 mole/hr",
            "b)\t25 mole/hr",
            "c)\t37.5 mole/hr",
            "d)\t50 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Material balance: G = 5 + H, CH4 balance: G(0.6) = H, solving both equations G = 12.5 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 401,
        "Question": "What is the value of H?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 mole/hr",
            "b)\t7.5 mole/hr",
            "c)\t10 mole/hr",
            "d)\t12.5 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: H = 0.6G = 7.5 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 402,
        "Question": "What is the value of B?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t7.5 mole/hr",
            "b)\t15 mole/hr",
            "c)\t20 mole/hr",
            "d)\t22.5 mole/hr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: B = F – G = 20 – 12.5 = 7.5 mole/hr."
    },
    {
        "id": 403,
        "Question": "What is the value of P?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2.5 mole",
            "b)\t5 mole",
            "c)\t7.5 mole",
            "d)\t10 mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: 0.2*10 = 0.8*1*W, => W = 2.5 mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 404,
        "Question": "What is the fraction of N2 in purge stream?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.04",
            "b)\t0.05",
            "c)\t0.16",
            "d)\t0.4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: F = W + P, => 10 = 2.5 + P, => P = 7.5 mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 405,
        "Question": "How many moles of H2 are recycled?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1.5",
            "b)\t2.2",
            "c)\t2.8",
            "d)\t3.9"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: N2 balance: 10*0.2 – 10*0.2*0.8 = 7.5*x, => x = 0.05."
    },
    {
        "id": 406,
        "Question": "What is the value of R?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1.4",
            "b)\t2.8",
            "c)\t4.2",
            "d)\t6.8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Moles of H2 in G stream = 10*0.8 – 3*10*0.2*0.8 = 3.2 = moles of H2 in H stream. Moles of H2 in P stream = 0.95*7.5 = 7.125, => moles of H2 in R stream = 7.125 – 3.2 = 3.925."
    },
    {
        "id": 407,
        "Question": "Which of the following term does not involve in ideal gas law?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tPressure",
            "b)\tVolume",
            "c)\tTemperature",
            "d)\tTime"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Ideal gas law is PV = nRT, which does not involve time."
    },
    {
        "id": 408,
        "Question": "What is the shape of a P-T curve for ideal gas?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tStraight line",
            "b)\tParabolic",
            "c)\tHyperbolic",
            "d)\tEllipse"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: P-T curve is a straight line for ideal gas."
    },
    {
        "id": 409,
        "Question": "What is the shape of a V-T curve for ideal gas?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tStraight line",
            "b)\tParabolic",
            "c)\tHyperbolic",
            "d)\tEllipse"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: V-T curve is straight line for ideal gas."
    },
    {
        "id": 410,
        "Question": "What is the shape of a P-V curve for an ideal gas?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tStraight line",
            "b)\tParabolic",
            "c)\tHyperbolic",
            "d)\tEllipse"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: P-V curve is hyperbolic for an ideal gas."
    },
    {
        "id": 411,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not true about ideal gas molecules?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tThey have negligible size",
            "b)\tThey do not have attractive forces",
            "c)\tThey do not apply pressure",
            "d)\tThey move in random motion"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Ideal gas molecules apply pressure to the walls of a container."
    },
    {
        "id": 412,
        "Question": "What is the pressure of a 5 liter/mole ideal gas at temperature 27oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2.5 atm",
            "b)\t3.8 atm",
            "c)\t4.4 atm",
            "d)\t5.3 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: PV = nRT, => P*5 = 0.0821*300, => P = 5.3 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 413,
        "Question": "What is the Temperature of a 2 liter/mole ideal gas with pressure 10 atm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t243.6 K",
            "b)\t268.4 K",
            "c)\t289.1 K",
            "d)\t313.5 K"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: PV = nRT, => 10*2 = 0.0821*T, => T = 243.6 K."
    },
    {
        "id": 414,
        "Question": "First of the two ideal gases has twice molar volume as much as the second at same temperature, what is the ratio of their pressures?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4:1",
            "b)\t1:4",
            "c)\t2:1",
            "d)\t1:2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: P1V1 = n1RT1, P2V2 = n2RT2 dividing both the equations, => P1:P2 = 1:2."
    },
    {
        "id": 415,
        "Question": "88 grams of CO2 at 27oC is applying 5 atm pressure, what is the volume occupied by it?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5.6 liter",
            "b)\t7.9 liter",
            "c)\t9.8 liter",
            "d)\t12.2 liter"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: n = 88/44 = 2, PV = nRT, => 5*V = 2*0.0821*300, => V = 9.8 liter."
    },
    {
        "id": 416,
        "Question": "What is the density of O2 at 27oC with pressure 1 atm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1.1 g/L",
            "b)\t1.3 g/L",
            "c)\t1.5 g/L",
            "d)\t1.7 g/L"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Molecular wt. of O2= 44 g, PV = nRT, => PV = (m/M)RT, => d = PM/RT = (1*32)/(0.0821*300) = 1.3 g/L."
    },
    {
        "id": 417,
        "Question": "What is the molecular mass of an ideal gas with pressure 1 atm, and density 10 g/L at temperature 27oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t84.5 g",
            "b)\t135.1 g",
            "c)\t186.8 g",
            "d)\t246.3 g"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: M = dRT/P = 10*0.0821*300/1 = 246.3 g."
    },
    {
        "id": 418,
        "Question": "What is the specific gravity of CO2 at 27oC and pressure 1 atm with respect to air of with density 1 g/L?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1.23",
            "b)\t1.55",
            "c)\t1.78",
            "d)\t1.96"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Density of CO2 = PM/RT = 1*44/(0.0821*300) = 1.78 g/L, => Specific gravity = 1.78/1 = 1.78."
    },
    {
        "id": 419,
        "Question": "What is the specific gravity of CO at 27oC and pressure 5 atm with respect to air (molecular wt. = 29 g) at 27oC and pressure 10 atm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.48",
            "b)\t0.56",
            "c)\t0.64",
            "d)\t0.72"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Density of CO = 5*28/(0.0821*300) = 5.68 g/L, density of air = 10*29/(0.0821*300) = 11.77 g/L, => specific gravity = 5.68/11.77 = 0.48."
    },
    {
        "id": 420,
        "Question": "What is the compressibility factor for an ideal gas?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\tDepends on the gas"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Compressibility of an ideal gas is always 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 421,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not the unit of R?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tAtm.liter/K.mole",
            "b)\tPa.m3/K",
            "c)\tN.Kg.m3/K.mole",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: N.Kg.m/K.mole is the unit of R."
    },
    {
        "id": 422,
        "Question": "A container has two gases at 27oC, one with molar volume 6 L/mole, another with molar volume 3 L/mole, what is the total pressure of the container?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t6.9 atm",
            "b)\t8.5 atm",
            "c)\t12.3 atm",
            "d)\t15.8 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: p1V1 = n1RT1, => p1 = 0.0821*300/6 = 4.1 atm, p2 = 0.0821*300/3 = 8.2 atm, => P = 4.1 + 8.2 = 12.3 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 423,
        "Question": "The fraction of gas in a container is 0.1, if the total pressure of the container is 10 atm, what is the partial pressure of the gas?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 atm",
            "b)\t5 atm",
            "c)\t10 atm",
            "d)\t20 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Partial pressure of gas = 0.1*10 = 1 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 424,
        "Question": "The fraction of gas in a container is 0.5, if the total volume of the container is 6 liter, what is the volume of the gas?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 liter",
            "b)\t3 liter",
            "c)\t5 liter",
            "d)\t6 liter"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Volume of gas = Volume of container = 6 liter."
    },
    {
        "id": 425,
        "Question": "A gas mixture contains 30% CO2, 40% O2, 30% N2, if the partial pressure of CO2 is 6 Pa, what is the total pressure of gas mixture?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t6 Pa",
            "b)\t10 Pa",
            "c)\t20 Pa",
            "d)\t60 Pa"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: 0.3*P = 6, => P = 20 Pa."
    },
    {
        "id": 426,
        "Question": "The highest pressure gas of a mixture has partial pressure p, the partial pressure of other gases decreases by factor of 2n-1, the partial pressure of second gases decreases by a factor of 2, partial pressure of third gas increases by 4, and so on, if the total pressure of gas mixture is 31p/16, how many gases are present in the mixture?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3",
            "b)\t5",
            "c)\t10",
            "d)\t15"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Let n gases are present in the mixture, => p + p/2 + p/4 + – – – + p/2n-1 = 7p/8, => p(1 – 1/2n)/(1 – ½) = 31p/16, => n = 5."
    },
    {
        "id": 427,
        "Question": "A gas mixture comprises of 20% CO2, 50% O2, and 30% N2 has the total pressure 100 Pa at temperature -73oC, if the temperature is increased to 27oC, what is the new partial pressure of N2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t15 Pa",
            "b)\t30 Pa",
            "c)\t45 Pa",
            "d)\t60 Pa"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: P1/P2 = T1/T2, => 100/P2 = 200/300, => P2 = 150 Pa, => new partial pressure of N2 = 0.3*150 = 45 Pa."
    },
    {
        "id": 428,
        "Question": "A container has gas mixture of 20% H2 and 80% N2 with total pressure P, now same amount of O2 is added to the mixture, what is the new partial pressure of N2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.2P",
            "b)\t0.8P",
            "c)\tP",
            "d)\t1.6P"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: New partial pressure of N2 = Old partial pressure of N2 = 0.8P."
    },
    {
        "id": 429,
        "Question": "A container has gas mixture of 40% CO2 and 60% H2 with total pressure 10 Pa, if now O2 is added to it isothermally so that the final composition of the mixture becomes 20% CO2, 30% H2, and 50% O2, what is the partial pressure of O2 in the new composition?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 Pa",
            "b)\t10 Pa",
            "c)\t20 Pa",
            "d)\t35 Pa"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Partial pressure of H2 = 0.6*10 = 6 Pa, => Partial pressure of O2 = 0.5*6/0.3 = 10 Pa."
    },
    {
        "id": 430,
        "Question": "A gas mixture has 30% O2, 40% H2, and 30% N2 with molar volume of N2 10 L/mole at temperature 27oC, what is the partial pressure of H2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2.4 atm",
            "b)\t3.6 atm",
            "c)\t4.8 atm",
            "d)\t6.4 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Molar volume of H2 = molar volume of N2 = 10 L/mole, PV = nRT, => P*10 = 0.0821*300, => P = 2.4 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 431,
        "Question": "A gas mixture contains 20% CO, 30% SO2, and 50% N2, if the partial pressure of N2 is 5 atm at 27oC, what is the molar volume of N2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2.4 liter",
            "b)\t3.7 liter",
            "c)\t4.9 liter",
            "d)\t5.6 liter"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Total pressure of mixture = 5/0.5 = 10 atm, => Molar Volume of N2 = Total molar volume of mixture = 0.0821*300/10 = 2.4 liter."
    },
    {
        "id": 432,
        "Question": "What is the total pressure of contained if it contains 0.5 fraction of O2 with partial pressure 3 Pa, 0.3 fraction of H2 with partial pressure 5 Pa, 0.2 fraction of CO2 with partial pressure 15 Pa?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t6 Pa",
            "b)\t7 Pa",
            "c)\t8 Pa",
            "d)\t9 Pa"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Total pressure = 0.5*3 + 0.3*5 + 0.2*15 = 6 Pa."
    },
    {
        "id": 433,
        "Question": "What is the total pressure of contained if it contains 0.3 fraction of N2 with partial pressure 8 Pa, 0.3 fraction of H2 with partial pressure 2 Pa, 0.4 fraction of CO2 with partial pressure 15 Pa?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t6.4 Pa",
            "b)\t7 Pa",
            "c)\t8.5 Pa",
            "d)\t9 Pa"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Total pressure = 0.3*8 + 0.3*2 + 0.4*15 = 9 Pa."
    },
    {
        "id": 434,
        "Question": "What is the partial pressure of O2 with fraction 0.1, if the total pressure is 10 Pa?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 Pa",
            "b)\t3 Pa",
            "c)\t5 Pa",
            "d)\t7 Pa"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Partial pressure = 0.1*10 = 1 Pa."
    },
    {
        "id": 435,
        "Question": "A container with total volume 10 liter is filled with 20% of O2, 40% of N2, and 40% of CO, what is the volume of O2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 liter",
            "b)\t4 liter",
            "c)\t8 liter",
            "d)\t10 liter"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Volume of each gas in the container is equal to the total volume of the container."
    },
    {
        "id": 436,
        "Question": "A vessel contains 10 moles of O2 and some other gases, total pressure is 10 atm, what is the partial pressure of O2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 atm",
            "b)\t10 atm",
            "c)\t100 atm",
            "d)\tCannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Since the total moles are not given, fraction of O2 cannot be determined, so partial pressure of O2 cannot be determined."
    },
    {
        "id": 437,
        "Question": "H2 at 27oC with pressure 10 atm and volume 10 liter is passed through a reactor with 6 moles of oxygen, if the limiting reagent reacts completely, how many moles of oxygen is left unreacted?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t4",
            "d)\t6"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The reaction is 2H2 + O2 -> 2H2O, moles of H2 passed = 10*10/(0.0821*300) = 4, => moles of H2 reacted = 4, => moles of O2 reacted = 4, => moles of O2 left unreacted = 6 – 2 = 4."
    },
    {
        "id": 438,
        "Question": "N2 with pressure 10 atm and H2 with pressure 30 atm, both with volume 10 liter at 27oC are passed into a reactor, how many moles NH3 is produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4",
            "b)\t8",
            "c)\t12",
            "d)\t16"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The reaction is N2 + 3H2 -> 2NH3, moles of N2 = 10*10/(0.0821*300) = 4, moles of H2 = 30*10/(0.0821*300) = 12, => extent of reaction = (0 – 4)/(-1) = 4, => moles of NH3 = 4*2 = 8."
    },
    {
        "id": 439,
        "Question": "CH4 with pressure 10 atm and volume 5 liter at 27oC is passed into a reactor with 50% excess oxygen, how many moles of oxygen is left in the products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2",
            "b)\t4",
            "c)\t6",
            "d)\t8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The reaction is CH4 + 2O2 -> CO2 + 2H2O, moles of CH4 = 10*5/(0.0821*300) = 2, => moles of O2 left = 2*2(50/100) = 2."
    },
    {
        "id": 440,
        "Question": " CO with pressure 10 atm at 27oC is passed through a reactor with O2, what is the pressure of CO2 produced if 60% CO reacted?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 atm",
            "b)\t6 atm",
            "c)\t10 atm",
            "d)\t14 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The reaction is 2CO + O2 -> 2CO2, pressure of CO2 = 10*0.6 = 6 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 441,
        "Question": "Glucose with pressure 10 atm at 27oC is passed through a reactor with O2, what is the temperature of CO2 produced if pressure becomes thrice?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t150 K",
            "b)\t240 K",
            "c)\t300 K",
            "d)\t330 K"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The reaction is C6H12O6+ 9O2 -> 6CO2 + 6H2O, => 30/T = 6(10/300), => T = 150 K."
    },
    {
        "id": 442,
        "Question": "A gas mixture with 6% O2 with pressure 1 atm at 27oC is entered a reactor with rate F, and another stream with pure O2 with 2 atm pressure at 27oC entered the reactor with rate 1 liter/s, product has 10% O2 with same conditions with rate P, what is the value of F?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t575.5 liter/s",
            "b)\t725 liter/s",
            "c)\t895 liter/s",
            "d)\t997.5 liter/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Overall material balance: F + 1 = P, O2 balance: 0.06*F + 2*1*1 = 0.1*P, => 6F + 400 = 10P, => F = 399*2.5= 997.5 liter/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 443,
        "Question": "A mixture with 60% O2 and 40% H2 with pressure 5 Pa at 27oC at the rate 15 liter/s is passed through a reactor with another stream containing pure H2 with pressure 10 Pa at 27oC at the rate 5 liter/s, what is the fraction of H2 with pressure 5 Pa at 27oC in product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.2",
            "b)\t0.4",
            "c)\t0.6",
            "d)\t0.8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Overall material balance: 15 + 5 = P, => P = 20 mole/s, Overall O2 balance: 0.4*5*15 + 1*10*5 = 20*x*5, => x = 0.8."
    },
    {
        "id": 444,
        "Question": "A gas mixture has 10% CH4 with pressure 5 Pa at 27oC at the rate F, is passed through a reactor with another stream containing 60% CH4 with pressure 5 Pa at -73oC at the rate 10 liter/s, if the percentage of CH4 with pressure 5 Pa at 27oC in product is 80%, what is the value of F?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 liter/s",
            "b)\t1.4 liter/s",
            "c)\t2 liter/s",
            "d)\t2.6 liter/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Overall material balance: F + 10 = P, Overall CH4 Balance: 0.1*F*5/300 + 0.6*10*5/200 = 0.8*P*5/300, => F + 90 = 8P, => F = 10/7 = 1.4 liter/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 445,
        "Question": "A gas mixture with 50% H2 at the rate F is passed through a reactor and it produced a gas mixture with 80% H2 at the rate 15 liter/s, what is the value of F?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 liter/s",
            "b)\t8 liter/s",
            "c)\t15 liter/s",
            "d)\t24 liter/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Overall H2 balance: 0.5F = 0.8*15, => F = 24 liter/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 446,
        "Question": "A gas mixture with 20% O2 with pressure 100 Pa at 27oC at the rate 50 liter/s is passed through a reactor and products a gas mixture with 40% O2 with pressure 25 Pa at 27oC, what is the rate of product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t50 liter/s",
            "b)\t100 liter/s",
            "c)\t200 liter/s",
            "d)\t400 liter/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: O2 balance: 0.2*100*50 = 0.4*25*P, => P = 100 liter/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 447,
        "Question": "A gas mixture with 10% H2 with pressure 15 Pa at 27oC at the rate 20 liter/s is passed through a reactor and products a gas mixture with 30% H2 with pressure 25 Pa at 27oC, what is the rate of product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4 liter/s",
            "b)\t10 liter/s",
            "c)\t24 liter/s",
            "d)\t30 liter/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: H2 balance: 0.1*15*20 = 0.3*25*P, => P = 4 liter/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 448,
        "Question": "A gas mixture with 50% Ar with pressure 80 Pa at 0oC at the rate 5 liter/s is passed through a reactor and products a gas mixture with 80% Ar with pressure 50 Pa at 27oC, what is the rate of product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 liter/s",
            "b)\t10 liter/s",
            "c)\t20 liter/s",
            "d)\t40 liter/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Ar balance: 0.5*80*5 = 0.8*50*P, => P = 5 liter/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 449,
        "Question": "A gas mixture with 5% Neon with pressure 10 atm at 27oC is entered a reactor with rate F, and another stream with pure Neon with 8 atm pressure at 27oC entered the reactor with rate 3 liter/s, product has 10% Neon with same conditions with rate P, what is the value of F?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3 liter/s",
            "b)\t15 liter/s",
            "c)\t48 liter/s",
            "d)\t72 liter/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Neon balance- 0.05*F*10 + 3*1*8 = 0.1*P*8, => 0.5F + 24 = 0.8P, Overall balance- F + 3 = P, => 0.3F = 21.6, => F = 72 liter/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 450,
        "Question": "CH4 with pressure 10 atm and volume 10 liter at 27oC is passed into a reactor with 20% excess oxygen, how many moles of oxygen is left in the products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2",
            "b)\t4",
            "c)\t6",
            "d)\t8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The reaction is CH4 + 2O2 -> CO2 + 2H2O, moles of CH4 = 10*10/(0.0821*300) = 4, => moles of O2 left = 2*4(50/100) = 4."
    },
    {
        "id": 451,
        "Question": "A gas mixture with 20% Neon with pressure 3 atm at 27oC is entered a reactor with rate F, and another stream with pure Neon with 2 atm pressure at 27oC entered the reactor with rate 5 liter/s, product has 40% Neon with same conditions with rate P, what is the value of F?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3 liter/s",
            "b)\t15 liter/s",
            "c)\t30 liter/s",
            "d)\t45 liter/s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Neon balance- 0.2*F*3 + 5*2*1 = 0.4*P*2, => 0.6F + 10 = 0.8P, Overall balance- F + 5 = P, => F = 30 liter/s."
    },
    {
        "id": 452,
        "Question": "What is the compressibility of ideal gases?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Compressibility = PV/nRT, but for ideal gases PV = nRT, => Compressibility = 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 453,
        "Question": "Which of the following is true about compressibility of real gases?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tZ = 1",
            "b)\tZ < 1",
            "c)\tZ > 1",
            "d)\tBoth Z < 1 and Z > 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: For any value of compressibility except 1, the gas is real."
    },
    {
        "id": 454,
        "Question": "What is the pressure of CO2 gas with compressibility z = 0.8, if the ideal gas pressure of CO2 is 10 Pa, all other variables are same?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5",
            "b)\t8",
            "c)\t10",
            "d)\t14"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Pressure of CO2 = 0.8*10 = 8 Pa."
    },
    {
        "id": 455,
        "Question": "What is the pressure of H2 with compressibility 0.6, molar volume 5 liter/mole at 27oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2.9 atm",
            "b)\t5.4 atm",
            "c)\t9.6 atm",
            "d)\t14.5 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: P = znRT/V, => P = 0.6*0.0821*300/5 = 2.9 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 456,
        "Question": "At what temperature, does SO2 with compressibility 2 has pressure 5 atm and molar volume 10 mole/s?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t300.5 K",
            "b)\t304.5 K",
            "c)\t310 K",
            "d)\t312.5 K"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: T = PV/zR = 5*10/(2*0.0821) = 304.5 K."
    },
    {
        "id": 457,
        "Question": "What is the compressibility factor of water with density 1 g/liter at 27oC and 1 atm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.25",
            "b)\t0.59",
            "c)\t0.73",
            "d)\t0.91"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: z = PM/dRT = 1*18/(1*0.0821*300) = 0.73."
    },
    {
        "id": 458,
        "Question": "What is the compressibility factor of a liquid of molar mass 90 g and density 10 g/liter at 27oC and 2 atm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.14",
            "b)\t0.39",
            "c)\t0.51",
            "d)\t0.73"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: z = PM/dRT = 2*90/(10*0.0821*300) = 0.73."
    },
    {
        "id": 459,
        "Question": "What is the pressure of 80 grams of CH4 with compressibility 5, with 10 liter volume at 27oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10.5 atm",
            "b)\t28.9 atm",
            "c)\t44.2 atm",
            "d)\t61.5 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: P = 5*5*0.0821*300/10 = 61.5 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 460,
        "Question": "What is the compressibility of methane with density 10 g/liter at 27oC and 500 atm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t32.5",
            "b)\t34.8",
            "c)\t39.6",
            "d)\t44.1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: z = PM/dRT = 500*16/(10*0.0821*300) = 32.5."
    },
    {
        "id": 461,
        "Question": "What is the compressibility of neon (molar mass = 20) with density 20 g/liter at 27oC and 100 atm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2.1",
            "b)\t3.5",
            "c)\t4",
            "d)\t6.8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: z = PM/dRT = 100*20/(20*0.0821*300) = 4."
    },
    {
        "id": 462,
        "Question": "90 g glucose is filled in a container at 10 atm, if the volume of container is 2 liter, what is the temperature of glucose (z = 1.5)?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25.4oC",
            "b)\t51.7oC",
            "c)\t76.9oC",
            "d)\t103.5oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: T = PV/znR = 10*2/(1.5*0.5*0.0821) = 324.8 K = 51.7oC."
    },
    {
        "id": 463,
        "Question": "How many grams of C2H6 (z = 1.4) is present in the container at 27oC and 5 atm and with volume 10 liter?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20 g",
            "b)\t30.4 g",
            "c)\t40.6 g",
            "d)\t50.8 g"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: n = 5*10/(1.4*0.0821*300) = 1.45, mass of C2H6 = 1.45*28 = 40.6 g."
    },
    {
        "id": 464,
        "Question": "What is the volume of 21 g of propane (z = 1.9) at 1 atm and 27oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t23.4 liter",
            "b)\t37.5 liter",
            "c)\t42.1 liter",
            "d)\t59.6 liter"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: V = 1.9*0.5*0.0821*300/1 = 23.4 liter."
    },
    {
        "id": 465,
        "Question": "1 mole of cyclohexane (z = 1.2) is filled in a container at 27oC and 4 atm, what is the volume of container?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3.8 liter",
            "b)\t4.4 liter",
            "c)\t5.6 liter",
            "d)\t7.4 liter"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: V = 1.2*1*0.0821*300/4 = 7.4 liter."
    },
    {
        "id": 466,
        "Question": "39 grams of benzene (z = 1.4) is filled in a container of volume 10 liter at 27oC, what is the pressure of container?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1.7 atm",
            "b)\t1.9 atm",
            "c)\t2.2 atm",
            "d)\t2.5 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: P = 1.4*0.5*0.0821*300/10 = 1.7 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 467,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not the equation of state?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tVan der Waals Equation",
            "b)\tCharles Equation",
            "c)\tHolborn Equation",
            "d)\tPeng Robinson Equation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Charles equation is simply P α 1/V which is not the equation of state."
    },
    {
        "id": 468,
        "Question": "Virial Equation is a ______",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tArithmetic Progression",
            "b)\tGeometric Progression",
            "c)\tHarmonic Progression",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Virial equation is PV = RT (1 + 1/V + 1/V2 + 1/V3 + – – – – -), which is a geometric progression."
    },
    {
        "id": 469,
        "Question": "If the vander waal equation has only one root, what is the relation between a and b?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t729a = pb2",
            "b)\t243a = pb2",
            "c)\t81a = pb2",
            "d)\t9a = pb2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Vander waal equation, V3 – (nb + nRT/p)V2 + (n2a/p)V – n3ab/p = 0, comparing with (V – Vc)3 = 0, => 3n(a/p)1/2 = n(ab/p)1/3, => 729a = pb2."
    },
    {
        "id": 470,
        "Question": "A container has O2 at 5 atm and molar volume 2 liter/mole, if a = 9.24 atm(liter/mole), b = 0.0907 liter/mole, what is the temperature of O2? (Use vander waal equation)",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t140 K",
            "b)\t150 K",
            "c)\t170 K",
            "d)\t190 K"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: (p + a/V2)(V – b) = RT, => T = (5 + 9.24/22)(2 – 0.0907)/0.0821 = 170 K."
    },
    {
        "id": 471,
        "Question": "A container has H2 at 27oC and molar volume 1 liter/mole, if a = 9.24 atm(liter/mole), b = 0.0907 liter/mole, what is the temperature of H2? (Use vander waal equation)",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t7.5 atm",
            "b)\t12.4 atm",
            "c)\t15.6 atm",
            "d)\t17.8 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: (p + a/V2)(V – b) = RT, => p = 0.0821*300/(1 – 0.0907) – 9.24/12 = 17.8 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 472,
        "Question": "What is the pressure of CO2 at 0oC, molar volume = 4 liter/mole, if B = – 0.053 liter/mole, C = 0.0026 liter2/mole2? (Use virial equation, neglect higher terms)",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2.4 atm",
            "b)\t4.1 atm",
            "c)\t5.5 atm",
            "d)\t6.9 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: pV = RT(1 + B/V + C/V2), => p = (0.0821*273/4)(1 – 0.053/4 + 0.0026/16) = 5.5 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 473,
        "Question": "A container is filled with a gas at 10 atm with molar volume 1 liter/mole, if B = – 0.053 liter/mole, C = 0.0026 liter2/mole2, what is the temperature of gas? (Use virial equation, neglect higher terms)",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t128.2 K",
            "b)\t156.9 K",
            "c)\t198.5 K",
            "d)\t243.6 K"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: PV = RT(1 + B/V + C/V2), => T = 10*1/[0.0821*(1 – 0.053/1 + 0.0026/12)] = 128.2 K."
    },
    {
        "id": 474,
        "Question": "What is the unit of ‘b’ in Peng Robinson equation?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tLiter/mole",
            "b)\tLiter2/mole2",
            "c)\tMole/Liter",
            "d)\tMole2/Liter2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Peng Robinson equation is p = RT/(V – b) – aα/[V(V + b) + b(V – b)], => unit of b = unit of molar volume = liter/mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 475,
        "Question": "What is the unit of λ in the SRK equation?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tLiter/mole",
            "b)\tMole/Liter",
            "c)\tAtm(liter/mole)",
            "d)\tIt is dimensionless"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In the SRK equation, λ is a dimensionless function of reduced temperature."
    },
    {
        "id": 476,
        "Question": "What is the unit of ‘a’ in RK equation?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tLiter/mole",
            "b)\tAtm(liter/mole)",
            "c)\tAtm(liter/mole)K0.5",
            "d)\tAtm(liter/mole)K"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: RK equation is p = RT/(V – b) – a/[T0.5V(V + b)], => unit of a = atm(liter/mole)K0.5."
    },
    {
        "id": 477,
        "Question": "What is the pressure of a gas at T = 227oC, it is given that A = 5, B = 4 X 104 and C = 0 if T is in kelvin and p in mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.024 mm Hg",
            "b)\t0.049 mm Hg",
            "c)\t0.075 mm Hg",
            "d)\t0.096 mm Hg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ln p* = A – B/(C + T), => ln p = 5 – 4 X 103/(273 +227) = -3, => p = 0.049 mm Hg."
    },
    {
        "id": 478,
        "Question": "A material’s mass is given by the equation, m = 32P0.02/T0.5, where T is in Kelvin, m is in Kg and P is in mm Hg, what is the mass of material at 127oC, use A = 10, B = 6 X 103 and C = 0?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1.44 Kg",
            "b)\t1.69 Kg",
            "c)\t1.96 Kg",
            "d)\t2.25 Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ln p* = A – B/(C + T) = 10 – 6 X 103/(400) = -5, => p = 0.0067 mm Hg, => m = 32*(0.0067)0.02/4000.5 = 1.44 Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 479,
        "Question": "If the pressure of a gas at 27oC is 15 mm Hg, what will be its pressure at 127oC, use B = 5 X 103, C = 0, T is in kelvin and P is in mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t579 mm Hg",
            "b)\t775 mm Hg",
            "c)\t961 mm Hg",
            "d)\t999 mm Hg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ln P1/P2 = B (1/T2 – 1/T1), => ln 15/P2 = 5 X 103 (1/400 – 1/300), P2 = 961 mm Hg."
    },
    {
        "id": 480,
        "Question": "Pressure of a gas at 127oC is 10 mm Hg and the pressure at 527oC is 20 Pa, what is the value of B?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t225.1",
            "b)\t365.5",
            "c)\t499.2",
            "d)\t554.5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ln 10/20 = B (1/800 – 1/400), => B = 554.5."
    },
    {
        "id": 481,
        "Question": "Pressure of a gas at temperature T is P, What is the pressure of the gas at 2T, use B = 1?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tPe1/T",
            "b)\tPe1/2T",
            "c)\tPe1/3T",
            "d)\tPe1/4T"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ln P/P2 = 1*(1/2T – 1/T), => P2 = Pe1/2T."
    },
    {
        "id": 482,
        "Question": "What is the pressure of CO2 at 325 K, if it is given that pressure at 330 K is 6 Pa, and pressure at 320 K is 4 Pa?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4.5 Pa",
            "b)\t5 Pa",
            "c)\t5.5 Pa",
            "d)\t6 Pa"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Using linear interpolation, P325K = 4 + (325 – 320)*(6 – 4)/(330 – 320) = 4 + 5*2/10 = 5 Pa."
    },
    {
        "id": 483,
        "Question": "Temperature of SO2 at 5 Pa is 395 K and at 10 Pa temperature is 420 K, what is the temperature at 6 Pa?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t400 K",
            "b)\t405 K",
            "c)\t410 K",
            "d)\t415 K"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Using linear interpolation, T6Pa = 395 + (6 – 5)*(420 – 395)/(10 – 5) = 395 + 5 = 400 K."
    },
    {
        "id": 484,
        "Question": "At which of the following values of pressure a solid melts first?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 atm",
            "b)\t720 mm Hg",
            "c)\t500 KPa",
            "d)\t40 Torr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A solid melts first at the highest pressure which is 5 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 485,
        "Question": "A liquid evaporates first at which of the following conditions?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tHigh attraction forces",
            "b)\tLow attraction forces",
            "c)\tLow vapor pressure",
            "d)\tHigh boiling point"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A liquid evaporates first at low attraction forces."
    },
    {
        "id": 486,
        "Question": "At triple point, vapor pressure of ice is given by ln p* = 18 – 2560/T, and vapor pressure of water is given by ln p* = 28 – 5120/T, what is the temperature at triple point?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t225 K",
            "b)\t256 K",
            "c)\t320 K",
            "d)\t400 K"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: At triple point pressure and temperature of all the phases becomes same, => 18 – 2560/T = 28 – 5120/T, => 10 = 2560/T, => T = 256 K."
    },
    {
        "id": 487,
        "Question": "The vapor pressure of liquid benzene is given by ln p* = 15 – 1280/T, and that of vapor benzene is given by ln p* = 23 – 2560/T, what is the boiling point of benzene?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t160 K",
            "b)\t200 K",
            "c)\t240 K",
            "d)\t300 K"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: At boiling point pressure and temperature of both the phases will be same, => 23 – 2560/T = 15 – 1280/T, => 8 = 1280/T, => T = 160K."
    },
    {
        "id": 488,
        "Question": "The vapor pressure of a compound in a liquid phase is given by ln p* = 21 – 2800/T, and in solid phase it is given by ln p* = 28 – 3500/T, what is the sublimation temperature of the compound?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t100 K",
            "b)\t120 K",
            "c)\t150 K",
            "d)\t200 K"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: At sublimation point pressure and temperature of both the phases will be same, => 21 – 2800/T = 28 – 3500/T, => T = 100 K."
    },
    {
        "id": 489,
        "Question": "For CaOCl2, the rate of evaporation is given by W = 325p0.5M/T1.5 g/liter, where T is in K, p in mm Hg, and M is molecular weight, if its pressure is given by ln p* = 25 – 2700/T, what is the evaporation rate at T = 150 K?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t256 g/liter",
            "b)\t499 g/liter",
            "c)\t571 g/liter",
            "d)\t744 g/liter"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ln p* = 25 – 2700/150 = 7, => p = 1096.6 mm Hg, => W = 325(1096.6)0.5*127/1501.5 = 744 g/liter."
    },
    {
        "id": 490,
        "Question": "What is the vapor pressure of ammonia at 305 K, if it is given that the vapor pressure of ammonia at 315 K is 5 mm Hg and at 325 K it is 6 mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 mm Hg",
            "b)\t2 mm Hg",
            "c)\t3 mm Hg",
            "d)\t4 mm Hg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: p305K = 5 – (315 – 305)*(6 – 5)/(325 – 315) = 5 – 1 = 4 mm Hg."
    },
    {
        "id": 491,
        "Question": "The pressure of a compound at 200 K is 10 mm Hg and at 400 K it is 50 mm Hg, what is the pressure at T = 250 K?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t18.1 mm Hg",
            "b)\t24.2 mm Hg",
            "c)\t36.3 mm Hg",
            "d)\t48.4 mm Hg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Let the pressure of the compound is given by ln p* = a + b/T, => ln 10 = a + b/200, ln 50 = a + b/400, => ln 5 = -b/400, => b = -643.7, => a = 5.5, => At T = 250 K, ln p* = 5.5 – 643.7/250 = 2.9, p = 18.1 mm Hg."
    },
    {
        "id": 492,
        "Question": "A vessel contains air and vapor H2O, if the partial pressure of vapor H2O is 4 atm and pressure of air is 1 atm, what is the fraction of vapor H2O in vessel?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.25",
            "b)\t0.5",
            "c)\t0.75",
            "d)\t0.8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: yH2O = 15/(15 + 5) = 0.75."
    },
    {
        "id": 493,
        "Question": "A container has vapor H2O with partial pressure 9 atm, what is fraction of air in the vessel?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.1",
            "b)\t0.4",
            "c)\t0.7",
            "d)\t0.9"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Pressure of air = 1 atm, => fraction of air = 1/(1 + 9) = 0.1."
    },
    {
        "id": 494,
        "Question": "A system has partial pressure 500 mm Hg and the saturated water vapor has partial pressure 25 mm Hg, what is the fraction of water vapor in the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.01",
            "b)\t0.05",
            "c)\t0.1",
            "d)\t0.5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Fraction of water vapor = 25/500 = 0.05."
    },
    {
        "id": 495,
        "Question": "The partial pressure of a system at 49oC is 125 mm Hg and saturated ammonia vapor has partial pressure 20 mm Hg at 49oC, what is the fraction of ammonia vapor in the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.04",
            "b)\t0.08",
            "c)\t0.16",
            "d)\t0.24"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Fraction of ammonia vapor = 20/125 = 0.16."
    },
    {
        "id": 496,
        "Question": "What is the dew point of water at standard conditions?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t32oF",
            "b)\t212oF",
            "c)\t372oF",
            "d)\t584oF"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Dew point of water at standard conditions is 100oC = 212oF."
    },
    {
        "id": 497,
        "Question": "CH4 is burnt with 100% excess O2 at atmospheric pressure, if CH4 conversion is 100%, what is the pressure at dew point?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.2 atm",
            "b)\t0.4 atm",
            "c)\t0.6 atm",
            "d)\t0.8 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: CH4 + 2O2 -> CO2 + 2H2O, Basis: 100 moles of CH4, => moles of O2 reacted = 200, => Product contains, moles of CO2 = 100, moles of H2O = 200, moles of O2 = 200. => Fraction of H2O = 0.4, => Pressure at due point = 1*0.4 = 0.4 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 498,
        "Question": "Ethane is burnt with 20% excess O2 at 2 atm, conversion rate of ethane is 50%, what is the pressure at due point?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.45 atm",
            "b)\t0.75 atm",
            "c)\t0.9 atm",
            "d)\t1 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: C2H6 + 3.5O2 -> 2CO2 + 3H2O, Basis: 100 moles of ethane => moles of O2 reacted = 175, => Product contains, moles of CO2 = 100, moles of C2H6 = 50, moles of O2 = 35, moles of H2O = 150, => fraction of H2O = 0.45, => Pressure at due point = 2*0.45 = 0.9 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 499,
        "Question": "Ethanol is burnt with required amount of O2 at atmospheric pressure, the conversion of ethanol is 100%, what is the pressure at due point?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.2 atm",
            "b)\t0.4 atm",
            "c)\t0.6 atm",
            "d)\t0.8 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: C2H5OH + 3O2 -> 2CO2 + 3H2O, Basis: 100 moles of ethanol, => moles of O2 reacted = 300, => Product contains, moles of CO2 = 200, H2O = 300, fraction of H2O = 0.6, => Pressure at due point = 0.6*1 = 0.6 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 500,
        "Question": "100 KPa of water vapor at 27oC is saturated with air in a system, what is the mole fraction of air?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.230",
            "b)\t0.306",
            "c)\t0.425",
            "d)\t0.503"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Fraction of air = 101.3/(100 + 101.3) = 0.503."
    },
    {
        "id": 501,
        "Question": "10 KPa of water vapor at 27oC is saturated with air in a system, what is the mole fraction of air?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.21",
            "b)\t0.46",
            "c)\t0.79",
            "d)\t0.91"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Fraction of air = 101.3/(10 + 101.3) = 0.91."
    },
    {
        "id": 502,
        "Question": "Which of the following defines condensation?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tChange of solid to vapor",
            "b)\tChange of vapor to liquid",
            "c)\tChange of liquid to vapor",
            "d)\tChange of vapor to solid"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Condensation is phase change from vapor to liquid."
    },
    {
        "id": 503,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a way of condensation of vapor?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tCooling at constant volume",
            "b)\tCooling at constant pressure",
            "c)\tCompress it isothermally",
            "d)\tCompress it"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Compressing a gas and its temperature is increasing does not condense the vapor, compressing vapor at constant temperature is a way of condensation."
    },
    {
        "id": 504,
        "Question": "Condensation starts at which point?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tDew point",
            "b)\tBubble point",
            "c)\tTriple point",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A dew point is a temperature at which condensation starts."
    },
    {
        "id": 505,
        "Question": "If the fraction of water vapor at 27oC and 5 atm is 0.5, then what is the fraction of water vapor at 27oC and 1 atm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.1",
            "b)\t0.2",
            "c)\t0.5",
            "d)\t0.8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Fraction of water vapor at 27oC and 1 atm = 0.5/5 = 0.1."
    },
    {
        "id": 506,
        "Question": "What is the fraction of water vapor at 27oC and 1 atm, if the fraction of water vapor at 127oC and 1 atm is 0.8?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.2",
            "b)\t0.4",
            "c)\t0.6",
            "d)\t0.8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Fraction of water vapor at 127oC and 1 atm = 0.8*300/400 = 0.6."
    },
    {
        "id": 507,
        "Question": "A process is carried out for the feed mixture of 90% air and 10% water vapor, the compressor recovered 90% of water, what is the exit pressure of the compressor if the partial pressure of water vapor is 50 mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t286.1 mm Hg",
            "b)\t396.4 mm Hg",
            "c)\t458.7 mm Hg",
            "d)\t529.5 mm Hg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Exit components, water: 0.1*0.1 = 0.01, air: 0.9, => water = 0.0109 => Total exit pressure = 50/0.109 = 458.7 mm Hg."
    },
    {
        "id": 508,
        "Question": "A process is carried out for the feed mixture of 95% air and 5% ammonia vapor, the compressor recovered 40% of ammonia, what is the exit pressure of the compressor, if the partial pressure of ammonia vapor is 10 mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t225.4 mm Hg",
            "b)\t326.8 mm Hg",
            "c)\t451.2 mm Hg",
            "d)\t593.5 mm Hg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Exit components, ammonia: 0.05*0.6 = 0.03, air: 0.95, => yammonia = 0.03/0.98 = 0.0306, => Total exit pressure = 10/0.0306 = 326.8 mm Hg."
    },
    {
        "id": 509,
        "Question": "A process is carried out for the feed mixture of 80% air and 20% CO2, the compressor recovered 50% of CO2, what is the exit pressure of the compressor, if the partial pressure of CO2 is 15 mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t135 mm Hg",
            "b)\t145 mm Hg",
            "c)\t175 mm Hg",
            "d)\t200 mm Hg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Exit components, CO2: 0.2*0.5 = 0.1, air: 0.8, => yCO2 = 0.1/0.9 = 0.111, => Total exit pressure = 15/0.111 = 135 mm Hg."
    },
    {
        "id": 510,
        "Question": "A process is carried out for the feed mixture of 50% air and 50% methane vapor, the compressor recovered 20% of methane, what is the exit pressure of the compressor, if the partial pressure of methane vapor is 25 mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t56.3 mm Hg",
            "b)\t78.9 mm Hg",
            "c)\t92.1 mm Hg",
            "d)\t98.7 mm Hg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Exit components, methane: 0.5*0.8 = 0.4, air: 0.5, => ymethane= 0.4/0.9 = 0.444, => Total exit pressure = 25/0.444 = 56.3 mm Hg."
    },
    {
        "id": 511,
        "Question": "A process is carried out for the feed mixture of 40% air and 60% oxygen, the compressor recovered 2% of oxygen, what is the exit pressure of the compressor, if the partial pressure of oxygen vapor is 5 mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2.4 mm Hg",
            "b)\t4.8 mm Hg",
            "c)\t6.5 mm Hg",
            "d)\t8.4 mm Hg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Exit components, oxygen: 0.6*0.98 = 0.588, air: 0.4, => yoxygen= 0.588/0.988 = 0.595, => Total exit pressure = 5/0.595 = 8.4 mm Hg."
    },
    {
        "id": 512,
        "Question": "Which of the following is defined as the ratio of partial pressure and vapor pressure?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tRelative Humidity",
            "b)\tMolal Humidity",
            "c)\tHumidity",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Partial pressure divided by vapor pressure is called relative humidity."
    },
    {
        "id": 513,
        "Question": "What is the relative saturation of a gas with partial pressure 10 mm Hg and vapor pressure 5 mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.5",
            "b)\t1",
            "c)\t2",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Relative saturation = 10/5 = 2."
    },
    {
        "id": 514,
        "Question": "What is the relative humidity of a gas with a partial pressure of water vapor is 5 mm Hg and vapor pressure 8 mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25%",
            "b)\t32.5%",
            "c)\t45%",
            "d)\t62.5%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Relative humidity = 5/8*100 = 62.5%."
    },
    {
        "id": 515,
        "Question": "What is the relative saturation of a gas with partial pressure 38 mm Hg and vapor pressure 1 torr?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.05",
            "b)\t0.5",
            "c)\t2",
            "d)\t38"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: 1 torr = 1 mm Hg, => relative saturation = 38/1 = 38."
    },
    {
        "id": 516,
        "Question": "What is the relative humidity of a gas with a partial pressure of water vapor 360 Pa and vapor pressure 1 atm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t100%",
            "b)\t225.1%",
            "c)\t355.4%",
            "d)\t405.9%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Relative humidity = 360/101.3*100 = 355.4%."
    },
    {
        "id": 517,
        "Question": "What is called the ratio of partial pressure of vapor and partial pressure of the dry gas?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tHumidity",
            "b)\tRelative humidity",
            "c)\tMolal humidity",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Partial pressure of vapor divided by the partial pressure of vapor free gas is called molal humidity."
    },
    {
        "id": 518,
        "Question": "What is the molal humidity of a gas with pressure of gas vapor 10 mm Hg and pressure of vapor free gas 20 mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25%",
            "b)\t50%",
            "c)\t100%",
            "d)\t200%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Molal humidity = 10/20*100 = 50%."
    },
    {
        "id": 519,
        "Question": "What is the molal saturation of a gas with 10 moles of gas vapor and 25 moles of dry gas?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.2",
            "b)\t0.4",
            "c)\t0.8",
            "d)\t1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Molal saturation = 10/25 = 0.4."
    },
    {
        "id": 520,
        "Question": "What is the molal saturation of a gas with 10 Pa partial pressure without vapor and 0.5 atm partial pressure with vapor?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.5",
            "b)\t1",
            "c)\t5",
            "d)\t101.3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Molal saturation = 0.5*101.3/10 = 5."
    },
    {
        "id": 521,
        "Question": "What is the molal humidity of a gas with partial pressure with vapor 1 mm Hg and partial pressure without vapor 1 atm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t90%",
            "b)\t131%",
            "c)\t214%",
            "d)\t288%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Molal humidity = 133.3/101.3*100 = 131%."
    },
    {
        "id": 522,
        "Question": "Which of the following is equal to the product of humidity and mass of dry gas?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tMoles of water vapor",
            "b)\tMass of water vapor",
            "c)\tMass of gas vapor",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Humidity = (mass of water vapor)/(mass of dry gas)."
    },
    {
        "id": 523,
        "Question": "What is the humidity, if the mass of dry gas is 10 Kg and mass of water vapor is 5 Kg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25%",
            "b)\t50%",
            "c)\t100%",
            "d)\t200%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Humidity = 5/10*100 = 50%."
    },
    {
        "id": 524,
        "Question": "What is the mass of water vapor, if the mass of dry gas is 10 lb and humidity 10%?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t254 g",
            "b)\t453 g",
            "c)\t746 g",
            "d)\t1 Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Mass of water vapor = 10*0.1 = 1 lb = 453 g."
    },
    {
        "id": 525,
        "Question": "What is the humidity if the moles of dry gas is 25 and mole of water vapor are 15?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t60%",
            "b)\t90%",
            "c)\t150%",
            "d)\t200%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Humidity = 15/25*100 = 60%."
    },
    {
        "id": 526,
        "Question": "What are moles of dry gas if the moles of water vapor is 14 at 25% humidity?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3.5",
            "b)\t7",
            "c)\t14",
            "d)\t56"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Moles of dry gas = 14/0.25 = 56."
    },
    {
        "id": 527,
        "Question": "A reaction has produced 5 moles of water vapor and 10 liter bone dry air at 27oC and 15 atm, what is the humidity?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t24%",
            "b)\t49%",
            "c)\t83%",
            "d)\t106%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Moles of bone dry air = 6, => humidity = 5/6*100 = 83%."
    },
    {
        "id": 528,
        "Question": "A reaction has produced 1 mole of water vapor and 5 liter of bone dry air at 27oC and 5 atm, what is the humidity?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t100%",
            "b)\t104%",
            "c)\t115%",
            "d)\t169%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Moles of bone dry air = 1, => Humidity = 1/1*100 = 100%."
    },
    {
        "id": 529,
        "Question": "A reaction has produced 0.4 mole of water vapor and 1 liter of bone dry air at 27oC and 5 atm, what is the humidity?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t85%",
            "b)\t143%",
            "c)\t178%",
            "d)\t200%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Moles of bone dry air = 0.2, => Humidity = 0.4/0.2*100 = 200%."
    },
    {
        "id": 530,
        "Question": "A reaction has produced 1.5 moles of water and 2 liter of bone dry air at 27oC and 25 atm, what is the humidity?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5%",
            "b)\t25%",
            "c)\t50%",
            "d)\t75%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Moles of bone dry air = 2, => Humidity = 1.5/2*100 = 75%."
    },
    {
        "id": 531,
        "Question": "A reaction has produced 45 moles of water and 25 liter of bone dry air at 27oC and 25 atm, what is the humidity?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25%",
            "b)\t104%",
            "c)\t180%",
            "d)\t209%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Moles of bone dry air = 25, => Humidity = 45/25*100 = 180%."
    },
    {
        "id": 532,
        "Question": "1 mole of CH4 reacts completely with excess air, if 5 liter of bone dry air is produced at 27oC and 5 atm, what is the humidity?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25%",
            "b)\t50%",
            "c)\t100%",
            "d)\t200%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Moles of bone dry air = 1, moles of H2O produced = 2, => humidity = 2/1*100 = 200%."
    },
    {
        "id": 533,
        "Question": "2 mole of CH4 reacts completely with excess air, if 25 liter of bone dry air is produced at 27oC and 5 atm, what is the humidity?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t45%",
            "b)\t80%",
            "c)\t95%",
            "d)\t143%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Moles of bone dry air = 5, moles of H2O produced = 4, => humidity = 4/5*100 = 80%."
    },
    {
        "id": 534,
        "Question": "0.1 mole of CH4 reacts completely with excess air, if 1 liter of bone dry air is produced at 27oC and 25 atm, what is the humidity?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4%",
            "b)\t15%",
            "c)\t20%",
            "d)\t52%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Moles of bone dry air = 1, moles of H2O produced = 0.2, => humidity = 0.2/1*100 = 20%."
    },
    {
        "id": 535,
        "Question": "50 mole of CH4 reacts completely with excess air, if 25 liter of bone dry air is produced at 27oC and 25 atm, what is the humidity?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20%",
            "b)\t80%",
            "c)\t200%",
            "d)\t400%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Moles of bone dry air = 25, moles of H2O produced = 100, => humidity = 100/25*100 = 400%."
    },
    {
        "id": 536,
        "Question": "25 mole of CH4 reacts completely with excess air, if 25 liter of bone dry air is produced at 27oC and 5 atm, what is the humidity?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t100%",
            "c)\t500%",
            "d)\t1000%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Moles of bone dry air = 5, moles of H2O produced = 50, => humidity = 50/5*100 = 1000%."
    },
    {
        "id": 537,
        "Question": "0.2 mole glucose reacts completely with excess air, if 5 liter of bone dry air is produced at 27oC and 5 atm, what is the humidity?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t40%",
            "b)\t80%",
            "c)\t120%",
            "d)\t160%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Moles of bone dry air = 1, moles of H2O produced = 1.2, => humidity = 1.2/1*100 = 120%."
    },
    {
        "id": 538,
        "Question": "1 mole glucose reacts completely with excess air, if 25 liter of bone dry air is produced at 27oC and 5 atm, what is the humidity?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t40%",
            "b)\t80%",
            "c)\t120%",
            "d)\t160%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Moles of bone dry air = 5, moles of H2O produced = 6, => humidity = 6/5*100 = 120%."
    },
    {
        "id": 539,
        "Question": "6 mole glucose reacts completely with excess air, if 25 liter of bone dry air is produced at 27oC and 20 atm, what is the humidity?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20%",
            "b)\t80%",
            "c)\t145%",
            "d)\t180%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Moles of bone dry air = 20, moles of H2O produced = 36, => humidity = 36/20*100 = 180%."
    },
    {
        "id": 540,
        "Question": "10 mole glucose reacts completely with excess air, if 25 liter of bone dry air is produced at 27oC and 30 atm, what is the humidity?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t100%",
            "b)\t200%",
            "c)\t300%",
            "d)\t400%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Moles of bone dry air = 30, moles of H2O produced = 60, => humidity = 60/30*100 = 200%."
    },
    {
        "id": 541,
        "Question": "1.5 mole glucose reacts completely with excess air, if 5 liter of bone dry air is produced at 27oC and 30 atm, what is the humidity?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t50%",
            "b)\t150%",
            "c)\t200%",
            "d)\t300%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Moles of bone dry air = 6, moles of H2O produced = 9, => humidity = 9/6*100 = 150%."
    },
    {
        "id": 542,
        "Question": "What is the degree of freedom of a system with 2 phases and 1 component?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: F = 2 – 2 + 1 = 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 543,
        "Question": "What is the number of phases in a system with 2 degrees of freedom and 2 components?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: P = 2 – 2 + 2 = 2."
    },
    {
        "id": 544,
        "Question": "What is the number of components in a system with 3 degrees of freedom and 2 phases?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: C = 2 – 2 + 3 = 3."
    },
    {
        "id": 545,
        "Question": "What is the degree of freedom of a system with 3 phases and 5 components?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: F = 2 – 3 + 5 = 6."
    },
    {
        "id": 546,
        "Question": "What is the degrees of freedom of a system with 5 phases and 5 components?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: F = 2 – 5 + 5 = 2."
    },
    {
        "id": 547,
        "Question": "What is the degrees of freedom of a system with pure water?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2",
            "b)\t4",
            "c)\t5",
            "d)\t7"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: F = 2 – 1 + 1 = 2."
    },
    {
        "id": 548,
        "Question": "What is the degrees of freedom of a system with a mixture of water and ice?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: F = 2 – 2 + 1 = 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 549,
        "Question": "What is the degrees of freedom of a system with a mixture of water, liquid benzene and oxygen?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: F = 2 – 2 + 3 = 3."
    },
    {
        "id": 550,
        "Question": "What is the degrees of freedom of a system with a mixture of ice, water and neon?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: F = 2 – 3 + 2 = 3."
    },
    {
        "id": 551,
        "Question": "What is the degrees of freedom of a system with a mixture of copper pyrites, liquid benzene and helium?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: F = 2 – 3 + 3 = 2."
    },
    {
        "id": 552,
        "Question": "What is the degree of freedom of a gas mixture composed of CO2, SO2, SO3, CH4, H2CO3?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2",
            "b)\t3",
            "c)\t5",
            "d)\t7"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: F = 2 – 1 + 4 = 5."
    },
    {
        "id": 553,
        "Question": "What is the degree of freedom of a gas mixture composed of O2, H2O and H2O2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: F = 2 – 1 + 2 = 3."
    },
    {
        "id": 554,
        "Question": "What is the degree of freedom of a mixture composed Liquid H2O, solid Br2 and gaseous CO2, NO2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: F = 2 – 3 + 4 = 3."
    },
    {
        "id": 555,
        "Question": "What is the degree of freedom of a mixture composed of liquid O2, gaseous H2 and ice?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: F = 2 – 3 + 2 = 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 556,
        "Question": "What is the degree of freedom of a gaseous mixture composed of CH4, CO2, H2CO3, H2O and H2O2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: F = 2 – 1 + 3 = 4."
    },
    {
        "id": 557,
        "Question": "What is the partial pressure of a 40% gas in a system with vapor pressure 1 mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.2 mm Hg",
            "b)\t0.4 mm Hg",
            "c)\t0.6 mm Hg",
            "d)\t0.8 mm Hg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: p = 0.4*1 = 0.4 mm Hg."
    },
    {
        "id": 558,
        "Question": "What is the vapor pressure of 50% gas in a system with partial pressure 2 mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 mm Hg",
            "b)\t2 mm Hg",
            "c)\t4 mm Hg",
            "d)\t8 mm Hg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: P = 2/0.5 = 4 mm Hg."
    },
    {
        "id": 559,
        "Question": "What is the fraction of gas in a system with partial pressure 2 mm Hg and vapor pressure 5 mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.4",
            "b)\t0.5",
            "c)\t0.6",
            "d)\t0.8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Fraction of gas = 2/5 = 0.4."
    },
    {
        "id": 560,
        "Question": "What is the partial pressure of 20% gas in a system with vapor pressure 10 mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 mm Hg",
            "b)\t10 mm Hg",
            "c)\t50 mm Hg",
            "d)\t100 mm Hg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Partial pressure = 0.2*10 = 2 mm Hg."
    },
    {
        "id": 561,
        "Question": "What is the vapor pressure of 40% gas in a system with partial pressure 20 mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 mm Hg",
            "b)\t10 mm Hg",
            "c)\t20 mm Hg",
            "d)\t50 mm Hg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Vapor pressure = 20/0.4 = 50 mm Hg."
    },
    {
        "id": 562,
        "Question": "According to Henry’s Law, what is the fraction of a gas with partial pressure p and Henry’s constant H?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tp*H",
            "b)\tp/H",
            "c)\tp + H",
            "d)\tp – H"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: According to Henry’s Law, p = H*x, => x = p/H."
    },
    {
        "id": 563,
        "Question": "What is the partial pressure of a 10% gas in a system, if H = 2 mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.1 mm Hg",
            "b)\t0.2 mm Hg",
            "c)\t0.3 mm Hg",
            "d)\t0.4 mm Hg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: p = 0.1*2 = 0.2 mm Hg."
    },
    {
        "id": 564,
        "Question": "What is the fraction of a gas in a system with partial pressure 10 mm Hg, H = 25 mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.1",
            "b)\t0.2",
            "c)\t0.3",
            "d)\t0.4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Fraction of a gas = 10/25 = 0.4."
    },
    {
        "id": 565,
        "Question": "A 40% gas in a system has partial pressure 4 atm, what is Henry’s constant?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1.6 atm",
            "b)\t4 atm",
            "c)\t10 atm",
            "d)\t16 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: H = 4/0.4 = 10 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 566,
        "Question": "What is the partial pressure of a 70% gas in a system, if H = 5 mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3.5 mm Hg",
            "b)\t7 mm Hg",
            "c)\t14 mm Hg",
            "d)\t35 mm Hg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Partial pressure = 0.7*5 = 3.5 mm Hg."
    },
    {
        "id": 567,
        "Question": "What is the K value of a gas with partial pressure 10 atm and the total pressure of the system is 50 atm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.1",
            "b)\t0.2",
            "c)\t100",
            "d)\t500"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: K = 10/50 = 0.2."
    },
    {
        "id": 568,
        "Question": "What is the K value of a gas with partial pressure 50 Pa and the total pressure of the system is 1 mm Hg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.37",
            "b)\t0.45",
            "c)\t0.79",
            "d)\t0.91"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: K = 50/133.3 = 0.37."
    },
    {
        "id": 569,
        "Question": "What is the total pressure of a system having 40% O2 with 5 atm partial pressure and 60% N2 with 10 atm partial pressure?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 atm",
            "b)\t6 atm",
            "c)\t8 atm",
            "d)\t10 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: P = 0.4*5 + 0.6*10 = 8 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 570,
        "Question": "What is the total pressure of a system having 25% CO2 with 4 atm partial pressure and 30% O2 with 10 atm partial pressure, and 45% SO2 with partial pressure 20 atm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t9 atm",
            "b)\t13 atm",
            "c)\t17 atm",
            "d)\t19 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: P = 0.25*4 + 0.3*10 + 0.45*20 = 1 + 3 + 9 = 13 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 571,
        "Question": "What is the total pressure of a system having 50% H2CO3 with 6 atm partial pressure and 50% O2 with 12 atm partial pressure?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3 atm",
            "b)\t6 atm",
            "c)\t9 atm",
            "d)\t12 atm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: P = 0.5*6 + 0.5*12 = 9 atm."
    },
    {
        "id": 572,
        "Question": "What is the fraction of a gas in a system at partial pressure 1 mm Hg, if the 0.2 fraction of the same gas is at partial pressure 2 mm Hg and 0.3 fraction at partial pressure 3 mm Hg (Use Freundlich Isotherm)?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.1",
            "b)\t0.2",
            "c)\t0.3",
            "d)\t0.4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: y1/y2 = (p1/p2)n, => 0.2/0.3 = (2/3)n => n = 1, => 0.2 = k*21 = k = 0.1, => y = 0.1*11 = 0.1."
    },
    {
        "id": 573,
        "Question": "What is the fraction of a gas in a system at partial pressure 2 mm Hg, if the 0.2 fraction of the same gas is at partial pressure 8 mm Hg and 0.3 fraction at partial pressure 18 mm Hg (Use Freundlich Isotherm)?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.0125",
            "b)\t0.0250",
            "c)\t0.0375",
            "d)\t0.0450"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: y1/y2 = (p1/p2)n, => 0.2/0.3 = (8/18)n => n = 2, => 0.2 = k*82 = k = 0.2/64, => y = 0.2/64*22 = 0.0125."
    },
    {
        "id": 574,
        "Question": "What is the fraction of a gas in a system at partial pressure 1 atm, if the 0.1 fraction of the same gas is at partial pressure 2 atm and 0.2 fraction at partial pressure 4 atm (Use Freundlich Isotherm)?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.01",
            "b)\t0.03",
            "c)\t0.05",
            "d)\t0.08"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: y1/y2 = (p1/p2)n, => 0.1/0.2 = (2/4)n => n = 1, => 0.1 = k*21 = k = 0.1/2, => y = 0.1/2 = 0.05."
    },
    {
        "id": 575,
        "Question": "What is the fraction of a gas in a system at partial pressure 1 atm, if the 0.2 fraction of the same gas is at partial pressure 4 atm and 0.4 fraction at partial pressure 8 atm (Use Freundlich Isotherm)?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.1",
            "b)\t0.2",
            "c)\t0.4",
            "d)\t0.5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: y1/y2 = (p1/p2)n, => 0.2/0.4 = (4/8)n => n = 1, => 0.2 = k*41 = k = 0.2/4, => y = 0.2/4*1 = 0.05."
    },
    {
        "id": 576,
        "Question": "What is the fraction of a gas in a system at partial pressure 3 atm, if the 0.2 fraction of the same gas is at partial pressure 4 atm and 0.3 fraction at partial pressure 6 atm (Use Freundlich Isotherm)?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.1",
            "b)\t0.15",
            "c)\t0.2",
            "d)\t0.25"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: y1/y2 = (p1/p2)n, => 0.2/0.3 = (4/6)n => n = 1, => 0.2 = k*41 = k = 0.2/4, => y = 0.2/4*31 = 0.15."
    },
    {
        "id": 577,
        "Question": "Which of the following is called for the adsorbing the molecules?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tAdsorbate",
            "b)\tAdsorbent",
            "c)\tAbsobate",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The one which adsorbs the molecules is called the adsorbent."
    },
    {
        "id": 578,
        "Question": "Which of the following adsorbs on the adsorbing surface?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tAdsorbate",
            "b)\tAdsorbent",
            "c)\tAbsobate",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Adsorbate adsorbs on the adsorbent."
    },
    {
        "id": 579,
        "Question": "Which of the following is called for the curves following isothermal adsorbtion?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tAdsorbtion isotherm",
            "b)\tAdsorbate isotherm",
            "c)\tAdsorbent isotherm",
            "d)\tAbsorbent isotherm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The curves for isothermal adsorbtion are called adsorbtion isotherms."
    },
    {
        "id": 580,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the property of adsorbtion isotherm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tLinear",
            "b)\tDecreasing",
            "c)\tMonotonous",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Since the adsorbtion isotherms are always increasing they are monotonous."
    },
    {
        "id": 581,
        "Question": "Which of the following satisfies the first derivative of adsorbtion isotherms?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tGreater than 1",
            "b)\tLess than 1",
            "c)\tEqual to 1",
            "d)\tCannot say"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since adsorbtion isotherms are always increasing, so their first derivative are always increasing."
    },
    {
        "id": 582,
        "Question": "What separates the system and surroundings?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tBoundary",
            "b)\tTemperature",
            "c)\tPressure",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Boundary separates system and surroundings."
    },
    {
        "id": 583,
        "Question": "Which of the following is true for an open system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tFlow system",
            "b)\tNon flow system",
            "c)\tCannot say",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since matter can come in or out in an open system, it is a flow system."
    },
    {
        "id": 584,
        "Question": "Which of the following is true about the closed system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tFlow system",
            "b)\tNon flow system",
            "c)\tCannot say",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since matter cannot come in or out in a closed system, it is a non-flow system."
    },
    {
        "id": 585,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not change in the steady state system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tFlow in rate",
            "b)\tFlow out rate",
            "c)\tAccumulation",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In a steady state system accumulation is zero."
    },
    {
        "id": 586,
        "Question": "Which of the following is correct about an isothermal process?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t∆T = 0",
            "b)\tdT = 0",
            "c)\t∆T /= 0",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In an isothermal process, temperature does not changes throughout the process, => dT = 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 587,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a state function?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tWork",
            "b)\tEntropy",
            "c)\tHeat",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Entropy is a state function as it does not depend on the path of the process."
    },
    {
        "id": 588,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a path function?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tWork",
            "b)\tInternal Energy",
            "c)\tEntropy",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since work depends on the path of a process, it is a path function."
    },
    {
        "id": 589,
        "Question": "Internal energy is which of the following function?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tPath function",
            "b)\tState function",
            "c)\tCannot say",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since internal energy does not depend on path, it is a state function."
    },
    {
        "id": 590,
        "Question": "Which of the following has a steepest P-V curve?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tAdiabatic",
            "b)\tIsothermal",
            "c)\tIsobaric",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Slope of an adiabatic curve is greater than that of isothermal and isobaric, so it has the steepest P-V curve."
    },
    {
        "id": 591,
        "Question": "What do we call a process having constant volume throughout?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tIsobaric",
            "b)\tIsochoric",
            "c)\tIsothermal",
            "d)\tAdiabatic"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Isochoric process has constant volume throughout."
    },
    {
        "id": 592,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an extensive variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tPressure",
            "b)\tTemperature",
            "c)\tVolume",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Volume is dependent on mass, it is an extensive variable."
    },
    {
        "id": 593,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an extensive variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tEnergy",
            "b)\tVolume",
            "c)\tMoles",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Energy, Volume and Moles all are dependent on mass, all are extensive variable."
    },
    {
        "id": 594,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an intensive variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tMoles",
            "b)\tEnthalpy per mole",
            "c)\tEnthalpy",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Enthalpy and mole both are extensive properties since the ratio of two extensive properties is an intensive property, Enthalpy per mole is an extensive property."
    },
    {
        "id": 595,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an intensive property?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tMole",
            "b)\tGibbs Free energy",
            "c)\tEnthalpy",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Since all depends on mass, all are extensive properties."
    },
    {
        "id": 596,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an intensive property?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tRefractive index",
            "b)\tHardness",
            "c)\tDensity",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Since none of the properties depends on mass, all are intensive properties."
    },
    {
        "id": 597,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not the type of energy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tEnthalpy",
            "b)\tHeat",
            "c)\tEntropy",
            "d)\tWork"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Entropy is not a type of energy."
    },
    {
        "id": 598,
        "Question": "Which of the following process P-V work in highest?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tSecond derivative is negative",
            "b)\tSecond derivative is positive",
            "c)\tSecond derivative is zero",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Work in highest when the area under the P-V curve is highest, which is when the second derivative of the curve is negative."
    },
    {
        "id": 599,
        "Question": "An object is moved from one position to another with a specific force, what type of work is it?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tShaft Work",
            "b)\tFlow Work",
            "c)\tMechanical Work",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Since work is caused by mechanical force it is a mechanical work."
    },
    {
        "id": 600,
        "Question": "An object is moved at a distance of 10 m with the force of 5 N, what is the work done by the force?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 Joule",
            "b)\t50 Joule",
            "c)\t500 Joule",
            "d)\t5000 Joule"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Work = 10*5 = 50 N-m = 50 Joule."
    },
    {
        "id": 601,
        "Question": "An object moved forward 10 meters and then comes back 5 meter all with a constant force of 5 N, what is the work done by the force?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 Joule",
            "b)\t25 Joule",
            "c)\t50 Joule",
            "d)\t75 Joule"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Work = (10 – 5)* 5 = 25 Joule."
    },
    {
        "id": 602,
        "Question": "A piston cylinder is compressed with some pressure, what is the work done on the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tPositive",
            "b)\tNegative",
            "c)\tZero",
            "d)\tCannot say"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since pressure and displacement are positive their products are also positive, => work done on the system is positive."
    },
    {
        "id": 603,
        "Question": "A piston cylinder expands with some pressure, what is the work done by the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tPositive",
            "b)\tNegative",
            "c)\tZero",
            "d)\tCannot Say"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since direction of displacement and force are same, work done will be positive."
    },
    {
        "id": 604,
        "Question": "A piston cylinder contracts from 10 Liter to 5 Liter with an external pressure of 10 Pa, what is the work done on the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.5 mJ",
            "b)\t5 mJ",
            "c)\t10 mJ",
            "d)\t50 mJ"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Work = 10*(10 – 5) = 50 mJ."
    },
    {
        "id": 605,
        "Question": "A piston cylinder expands from 7 liter to 15 liter with the external pressure of 500 Pa, what is the work done by the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t– 1.5 Joule",
            "b)\t– 4 Joule",
            "c)\t1.5 Joule",
            "d)\t4 Joule"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Work = 500*(15 – 7) = 4000 mJ = 4 Joule."
    },
    {
        "id": 606,
        "Question": "A piston cylinder expands from 8 liter to 12 liter with the external pressure of 900 Pa, what is the work done on the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3.6 Joule",
            "b)\t– 3.6 Joule",
            "c)\t7.2 Joule",
            "d)\t– 7.2 Joule"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Work done on the system = 900(8 – 12) = – 3600 mJ = – 3.6 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 607,
        "Question": "You shake a thermos so that the temperature of tea inside increases by 2oC, if you transferred Q amount of heat to the thermos, which of the following satisfies Q?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tQ > 0",
            "b)\tQ < 0",
            "c)\tQ = 0",
            "d)\tCannot say"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If you are shaking a thermos, you are doing work on it not transferring any heat."
    },
    {
        "id": 608,
        "Question": "Q amount of heat is transferred in an adiabatic process, which of the following is correct?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tQ > 0",
            "b)\tQ = 0",
            "c)\tQ < 0",
            "d)\tCannot say"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In an adiabatic process Q = 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 609,
        "Question": "Q amount of heat is transferred to a system, which of the following is correct?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tQ > 0",
            "b)\tQ < 0",
            "c)\tQ = 0",
            "d)\tCannot say"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since heat is transferred to a system, => Q > 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 610,
        "Question": "Temperature of a system is increased with no change in internal energy, if the work done by the system is 10 Joule, what amount of heat is taken out from the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t– 10 J",
            "c)\t0",
            "d)\t5 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: W = – 10, => 0 = Q + W, => Q = 10 J, => amount of heat taken out = – 10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 611,
        "Question": "Ratio heat transferred from 37oC to a colder body and from that body to – 11oC is 2, what is the temperature of colder body if surface areas are same for all bodies?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t– 5oC",
            "b)\t– 3oC",
            "c)\t5oC",
            "d)\t9oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: 2 = (37 – T)/(T + 11), => T = 5oC."
    },
    {
        "id": 612,
        "Question": "What is the change potential energy of a stone of mass 5 Kg that falls from a cliff 10 m high?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J",
            "b)\t50 J",
            "c)\t500 J",
            "d)\t5000 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: PE = 5*10*10 = 500 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 613,
        "Question": "What is the change in potential energy of a stone of mass 1 Kg thrown up with a velocity 10 m/s and comes down?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t100 J",
            "d)\t500 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since the stone comes down to its initial position, its potential energy does not change."
    },
    {
        "id": 614,
        "Question": "A fluid in supplied to a cliff 10 m high, what is the change in specific potential energy of fluid?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J/Kg",
            "b)\t100 J/Kg",
            "c)\t200 J/Kg",
            "d)\t500 J/Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Change in specific potential energy = 10*10 = 100 J/Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 615,
        "Question": "A fluid is supplied to a cliff 20 m high and comes down by 5 m, what is the change in specific potential energy of fluid?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t100 J/Kg",
            "b)\t150 J/Kg",
            "c)\t200 J/Kg",
            "d)\t250 J/Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Change in specific potential energy = 10*(20 – 5) = 150 J/Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 616,
        "Question": "A ball is thrown up and someone catches it on the cliff, what is the change in potential energy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tPositive",
            "b)\tNegative",
            "c)\tZero",
            "d)\tCannot say"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Change in potential energy will be positive as the change in kinetic energy will be negative."
    },
    {
        "id": 617,
        "Question": "What is the kinetic energy of an object of mass 10 Kg moving with velocity 2 m/s?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t20 J",
            "c)\t40 J",
            "d)\t50 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: KE = ½*10*22 = 20 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 618,
        "Question": "What is the kinetic energy of an object of mass 2 Kg and velocity 5 m/s?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20 J",
            "b)\t25 J",
            "c)\t35 J",
            "d)\t50 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: KE = ½*2*52 = 25 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 619,
        "Question": "What is the specific kinetic energy of a fluid flowing at rate 0.1 m3/s and 1 m diameter pipe?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.008 J/Kg",
            "b)\t0.016 J/Kg",
            "c)\t0.028 J/Kg",
            "d)\t0.064 J/Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: v = 0.1/∏(0.5)2, => specific KE = v2/2 = 0.008 J/Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 620,
        "Question": "A stone is thrown up with a velocity and comes down, what is the change in kinetic energy of stone?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tPositive",
            "b)\tNegative",
            "c)\tZero",
            "d)\tCannot say"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: According to the conservation of energy, during a process change in total energy will always be zero, if the stone comes to the same level the change in potential energy becomes zero so the change in kinetic energy also becomes zero."
    },
    {
        "id": 621,
        "Question": "A stone is released from a cliff and comes down, what is the change in kinetic energy of stone?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tPositive",
            "b)\tNegative",
            "c)\tZero",
            "d)\tCannot say"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since its velocity increases as it comes down, so a change in kinetic energy is positive."
    },
    {
        "id": 622,
        "Question": "What is the change in internal energy for a process which has final and initial states are exactly similar?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tPositive",
            "b)\tNegative",
            "c)\tZero",
            "d)\tCannot say"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Since internal energy is a state function, change in internal energy for the process will be zero."
    },
    {
        "id": 623,
        "Question": "What is the change in internal energy of 2 mole of air (Cv = 2.1 X 104 J/moleoC), if its temperature changes from 10oC to 20oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t420 kJ",
            "b)\t540 kJ",
            "c)\t840 kJ",
            "d)\t1050 kJ"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Change in internal energy = 2*(2.1 X 104)*(20 – 10) = 420 kJ."
    },
    {
        "id": 624,
        "Question": "What is the change in internal energy of 1 mole of air ((Cv = 2.1 X 104  J/moleoC), if its temperature changes from 10oC to 5oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t84 kJ",
            "b)\t105 kJ",
            "c)\t– 84 kJ",
            "d)\t– 105 kJ"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Change in internal energy = 1*(2.1 X 104)*(5 – 10) = – 105 kJ."
    },
    {
        "id": 625,
        "Question": "Ratio of change in internal energy of a substance from 4oC to T and from T to 10oC is 2, what is T?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5oC",
            "b)\t6oC",
            "c)\t7oC",
            "d)\t8oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: 2 = (T – 4)/(10 – T), =>  T = 8oC."
    },
    {
        "id": 626,
        "Question": "Ratio of change in internal energy of a substance from 15oC to T and from T to 10oC is – 2, what is T?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5oC",
            "b)\t15oC",
            "c)\t20oC",
            "d)\t30oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: – 2 = (T – 15)/(10 – T), => T = 5oC."
    },
    {
        "id": 627,
        "Question": "Total energy of the universe is always ______",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tIncreasing",
            "b)\tDecreasing",
            "c)\tConstant",
            "d)\tCannot say"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: According to the law of conservation of energy, the total energy of the universe is always constant."
    },
    {
        "id": 628,
        "Question": "A stone has initial potential and kinetic energy as 10 J and 5 J respectively if the final potential energy of the stone is 15 J what is its final kinetic energy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t10 J",
            "d)\t15 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Law of conservation of energy, 10 + 5 = 15 + KE, => KE = 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 629,
        "Question": "A stone has initial potential and kinetic energy as 5 J and 20 J respectively if the final kinetic energy of the stone is 15 J what is its final potential energy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t15 J",
            "d)\t25 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 5 + 20 = 15 + PE, => PE = 10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 630,
        "Question": "A stone has initial potential, kinetic and internal energy 4 J, 15 J and 20 J respectively, if the final kinetic energy and potential energy of the stone is 5 J and 10 J respectively, what is the final internal energy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t15 J",
            "b)\t20 J",
            "c)\t24 J",
            "d)\t32 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Final internal energy = 4 + 15 + 20 – 5 – 10 = 24 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 631,
        "Question": "A stone has initial potential, kinetic and internal energy 7 J, 10 J and 2x J respectively, if the final kinetic energy, potential energy and internal energy are 5 J, 21 J and x respectively, what is the final internal energy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 J",
            "b)\t4 J",
            "c)\t5 J",
            "d)\t9 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: 7 + 10 + 2x = 5 + 21 + x, => x = 9 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 632,
        "Question": "10 J of heat and 5 J of work are supplied to the system, what is the change in internal energy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t15 J",
            "d)\t20 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ∆U = 5 + 10 = 15 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 633,
        "Question": "15 J of heat is supplied to a system and system does 5 J of work, what is the change in internal energy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t15 J",
            "d)\t20 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ∆U = 15 – 5 = 10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 634,
        "Question": "5 J of heat is taken out of the system and 20 J of work is done on the system, what is the change in internal energy of the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t15 J",
            "d)\t20 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ∆U = 20 – 5 = 15 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 635,
        "Question": "10 J of heat is supplied and 3 J is taken out, if the change in internal energy of the system is 5 J, what is the work done on the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 J",
            "b)\t– 2 J",
            "c)\t5 J",
            "d)\t– 5 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 5 = 10 – 3 + W, => W = – 2 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 636,
        "Question": "5 J of work is done by the system, if the change in internal energy of the system is 10 J, what is the heat supplied to the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t– 5 J",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t– 15 J",
            "d)\t15 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: 10 = – 5 + Q, => Q = 15 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 637,
        "Question": "2 Kg of steam is enclosed in a container with internal energy = 5 J/Kg, then 5 J of heat is supplied to the system, what is the final internal energy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t7.5 J/ Kg",
            "b)\t15 J/Kg",
            "c)\t22.5 J/Kg",
            "d)\t30 J/Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: 5 = 2(U – 5), => U = 7.5 J/Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 638,
        "Question": "5 Kg of steam is enclosed in a container with internal energy = 10 J/Kg, then 25 J of heat is supplied to the system, what is the final internal energy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J/Kg",
            "b)\t10 J/Kg",
            "c)\t15 J/Kg",
            "d)\t20 J/Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 25 = 5(U – 10), => U = 15 J/Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 639,
        "Question": "In a 2 stage process Q1 = 5 J, Q2 = 10 J, if the change in internal energy in first stage is 10 J and the total change in internal energy is 20 J, what is the work do done in second stage?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t10 J",
            "d)\t– 5 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Change in internal energy in second stage = 20 – 10 =10 J, Work done in second stage = 10 – 10 = 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 640,
        "Question": "In a 3 stage process Q1 = 10 J, Q2= – 15 J, Q3 = 25 J, if ∆E1 = 15J and ∆E3 = 10 J, what is the work done in second stage, if the total ∆E is 30 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t15 J",
            "d)\t20 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ∆E2 = 5 J, => W2 = 5 + 15 = 20 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 641,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred to 2 Kg and 5 m3 of a rigid system, with change in enthalpy 5 J/Kg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t15 J",
            "d)\t20 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since the system is rigid, ∆V = 0, => Q = ∆H = 5*2 = 10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 642,
        "Question": "What is ∆E for a steady-state system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tPositive",
            "b)\tNegative",
            "c)\tZero",
            "d)\tCannot say"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Change in internal energy for a steady-state system is always zero."
    },
    {
        "id": 643,
        "Question": "5 J of heat is supplied to a steady state system, what is the work done by the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t– 5 J",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t0",
            "d)\t10 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 0 = 5 – W, => W = 5 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 644,
        "Question": "10 J of heat is taken off from a steady state system, what is the work done on the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t– 10 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t– 5 J",
            "d)\t5 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 0 = – 10 + W, => W = 10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 645,
        "Question": "10 J of work is done on a steady state system, what is the heat supplied to the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t– 10 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t5 J",
            "d)\t0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: 0 = 10 + Q, => Q = – 10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 646,
        "Question": "15 J of work is done by a steady state system, what is the heat supplied to the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t– 15 J",
            "b)\t15 J",
            "c)\t10 J",
            "d)\t– 10 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 0 = – 15 + Q, => Q = 15 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 647,
        "Question": "10 J of heat and 5 J of work is supplied to a system and 20 J of heat is taken out, then the system is which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tSteady state",
            "b)\tUnsteady state",
            "c)\tClosed",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ∆E = 10 + 5 – 20 = – 5 J which is not equal to zero, so the system is unsteady state system."
    },
    {
        "id": 648,
        "Question": "15 J of heat and 10 J of work is supplied to a system and 25 J of heat is taken out, then the system is which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tSteady state",
            "b)\tUnsteady state",
            "c)\tClosed",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ∆E = 15 + 10 – 25 = 0, so the system is steady state system."
    },
    {
        "id": 649,
        "Question": "15 J of heat is supplied to a system and 15 J of work is done on the system, then the system is which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tSteady state",
            "b)\tUnsteady state",
            "c)\tClosed",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ∆E = – 15 – 15 = – 30 J, which is not equal to zero, so the system is unsteady state system."
    },
    {
        "id": 650,
        "Question": "1 J of heat is supplied to the system and 1 kJ of work is done by the system, then the system is which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tSteady state",
            "b)\tUnsteady state",
            "c)\tClosed",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ∆E = 1 – 1000 = – 999 J, which is not equal to zero, so the system is unsteady state system."
    },
    {
        "id": 651,
        "Question": "10 J of work and 5 J of heat is supplied to the system, then the system is which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tSteady state",
            "b)\tUnsteady state",
            "c)\tClosed",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ∆E = 10 + 5 = 15 J, which is not equal to zero, so the system is unsteady state system."
    },
    {
        "id": 652,
        "Question": "For an open unsteady state system, 5 J of heat was supplied and 10 J of work was done on the system, what is the value of a change in enthalpy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t15 J",
            "d)\t20 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ∆H = 5 + 10 = 15 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 653,
        "Question": "For an open unsteady state system, 10 J of heat was supplied and 10 J of work was done by the system, what is the value of a change in enthalpy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t20 J",
            "d)\t– 20 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ∆H = 10 – 10 = 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 654,
        "Question": "For an open unsteady state system, 5 J of heat was supplied and 10 J of work was done by the system, what is the value of a change in enthalpy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t– 5 J",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t10 J",
            "d)\t15 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ∆H = 5 – 10 = – 5 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 655,
        "Question": "For an open unsteady state system, 15 J of heat was taken off and 10 J of work was done by the system, what is the value of a change in enthalpy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t– 5 J",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t25 J",
            "d)\t– 25 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ∆H = 10 – 15 = – 5 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 656,
        "Question": "For an open unsteady state system, 15 J of heat was supplied and -5 J of work was done on the system, what is the value of a change in enthalpy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t– 15 J",
            "c)\t20 J",
            "d)\t– 25 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ∆H = 15 – 5 = 10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 657,
        "Question": "Which of the following represents vaporization?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tChange of vapor to liquid",
            "b)\tChange of vapor to solid",
            "c)\tChange of solid to vapor",
            "d)\tChange of liquid to vapor"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Vaporization is the reverse of condensation which is a change of liquid to vapor."
    },
    {
        "id": 658,
        "Question": "Which of the following can definitely cause vaporization?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tHeating a liquid",
            "b)\tHeating a liquid at constant pressure",
            "c)\tCooling a liquid",
            "d)\tCooling a liquid at constant volume"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Vaporization is caused by heating a liquid at constant pressure."
    },
    {
        "id": 659,
        "Question": "Vaporization starts at which point?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tDew point",
            "b)\tBubble point",
            "c)\tTriple point",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Bubble point is the point at which liquid starts evaporating which is the point at which vaporization starts."
    },
    {
        "id": 660,
        "Question": "What is the vaporization temperature of water at standard conditions?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t100oF",
            "b)\t212oF",
            "c)\t345oF",
            "d)\t432oF"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Vaporization temperature of water at standard conditions is 100oC = 212oF."
    },
    {
        "id": 661,
        "Question": "What is the point of saturation of a condensable vapor?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tBubble point",
            "b)\tBoiling point",
            "c)\tTriple point",
            "d)\tDew point"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Condensation of gas starts at its dew point."
    },
    {
        "id": 662,
        "Question": "Which of the following is heat required in phase transitions?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tLatent Heat",
            "b)\tSensible Heat",
            "c)\tDepends on type of phase transition",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Heat required for phase transitions is latent heat."
    },
    {
        "id": 663,
        "Question": "What is the latent heat for melting?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tHeat of vaporization",
            "b)\tHeat of fusion",
            "c)\tHeat of Solidification",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Latent heat for melting is called heat of vaporization."
    },
    {
        "id": 664,
        "Question": "15 J is the latent heat for melting of ice, what is the heat of transition from 0oC ice to 15oC water if heat of transition from 0oC water to 15oC water is 10 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t15 J",
            "c)\t25 J",
            "d)\t40 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: H = 15 + 10 = 25 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 665,
        "Question": "5 J is the latent heat for melting of ice, what is the heat of transition from 0oC ice to 15oC water if heat of transition from 0oC water to 15oC water is 12 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J",
            "b)\t12 J",
            "c)\t15 J",
            "d)\t17 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: H = 5 + 12 = 17 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 666,
        "Question": "150 J is the latent heat for vaporization of water, what is the heat of transition from 50oC water to 100oC steam if heat of transition from 50oC water to 100oC water is 12 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12 J",
            "b)\t152 J",
            "c)\t162 J",
            "d)\t200 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: H = 150 + 12 = 162 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 667,
        "Question": "Heat of fusion of benzene is 10 J at 0oC, if Cp of solid benzene is 10 J/oC, and that of liquid benzene is 5 J/oC what is the enthalpy change of benzene from – 10oC to 10oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t160 J",
            "b)\t200 J",
            "c)\t240 J",
            "d)\t300 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ∆H = -10∫010.dT + 10 + 0∫105.dT = 10*10 + 10 + 5*10 = 160 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 668,
        "Question": "If Cp of liquid water is 10 J/oC, what is the enthalpy change of water at standard conditions from – 10oC to 0oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t50 J",
            "c)\t100 J",
            "d)\tCannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Since the phase of water from – 10oC to 0oC is solid ice, but Cp of liquid water is given, so it cannot be determined."
    },
    {
        "id": 669,
        "Question": "If Cp of liquid benzene is 15 J/oC, what is the enthalpy change of water from 5oC to 10oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t15 J",
            "b)\t50 J",
            "c)\t75 J",
            "d)\t90 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ∆H = 5∫1015.dT = 75 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 670,
        "Question": "If Cp of solid benzene is 10 J/oC, what is the enthalpy change of water from 5oC to 75oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t75 J",
            "d)\t700 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ∆H = 5∫7510.dT = 700 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 671,
        "Question": "If Cp of steam is 105 J/oC, what is the enthalpy change of steam from 106oC to 118oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t420 J",
            "b)\t640 J",
            "c)\t890 J",
            "d)\t1260 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ∆H = 106∫118105.dT = 1260 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 672,
        "Question": "If Cp of water is (23 + T) J/oC, what is the enthalpy change of water from 3oC to 5oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t54 J",
            "b)\t96 J",
            "c)\t140 J",
            "d)\t196 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ∆H = 3∫5(23 + T).dT = 23(5 – 3) + (52 – 32)/2 = 54 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 673,
        "Question": "If Cp of water is 45T J/oC, what is the enthalpy change of water from 6oC to 8oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t7 J",
            "b)\t14 J",
            "c)\t28 J",
            "d)\t56 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ∆H = 6∫8T.dT = (82 – 62)/2 = 14 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 674,
        "Question": "Cp of ice is 25 J/oC and that of water is 30 J/oC, what is the enthalpy change of water from – 10oC to 35oC at standard conditions, if the later heat of fusion of water is 110 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t250 J",
            "b)\t595 J",
            "c)\t960 J",
            "d)\t1410 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ∆H = -10∫025.dT + 110 + 0∫3530.dT = 25*10 + 110 + 35*30 = 1410 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 675,
        "Question": "Cp of ice is 10 J/oC and that of water is 15 J/oC, what is the enthalpy change of water from – 15oC to 0oC at standard conditions, if the later heat of fusion of water is 110 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t150 J",
            "b)\t315 J",
            "c)\t485 J",
            "d)\t560 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ∆H = -15∫025.dT + 110 = 25*15 + 110 = 485 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 676,
        "Question": "Cp of water is 10 J/oC and that of steam is 15 J/oC, what is the enthalpy change of water from 75oC to 110oC at standard conditions, if the later heat of vaporization of water is 245 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t395 J",
            "b)\t645 J",
            "c)\t840 J",
            "d)\t999 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ∆H = 75∫10010.dT + 245 + 100∫11015.dT = 25*10 + 245 + 15*10 = 645 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 677,
        "Question": "Water having CP = 10 J/oC, is heated from 10oC to 50oC, what is the enthalpy change?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t100 J",
            "b)\t250 J",
            "c)\t400 J",
            "d)\t500 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ∆H = 10∫5010.dT = 10*40 = 400 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 678,
        "Question": "Liquid benzene having CP = 29 J/oC, is heated from 5oC to 10oC, what is the enthalpy change?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t29 J",
            "b)\t145 J",
            "c)\t195 J",
            "d)\t290 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ∆H = 5∫1029.dT = 29*5 = 145 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 679,
        "Question": "Ice having CP = 15 J/oC, is heated from -10oC to -4oC, what is the enthalpy change?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t30 J",
            "b)\t60 J",
            "c)\t90 J",
            "d)\t120 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ∆H = -10∫-415.dT = 15*6 = 90 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 680,
        "Question": "Steam having CP = 105 J/oC, is heated from 100oC to 104oC, what is the enthalpy change?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t210 J",
            "b)\t420 J",
            "c)\t630 J",
            "d)\t840 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ∆H = 100∫104105.dT = 105*4 = 420 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 681,
        "Question": "Cyclohexane having CP = 48 J/oC, is heated from 50oC to 55oC, what is the enthalpy change?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t240 J",
            "b)\t480 J",
            "c)\t720 J",
            "d)\t960 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ∆H = 50∫5548.dT = 48*5 = 240 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 682,
        "Question": "What is the value of CP – CV for ideal gases?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\tR/2",
            "c)\tR",
            "d)\t2R"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: For ideal gases CP = CV + R."
    },
    {
        "id": 683,
        "Question": "A mixture contains 20% O2 with CP = 15 J/oC and 80% CO2 with CP = 20 J/oC, what is the average CP of mixture?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3 J/oC",
            "b)\t9 J/oC",
            "c)\t16 J/oC",
            "d)\t19 J/oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Average CP = 0.2*15 + 0.8*20 = 19 J/oC."
    },
    {
        "id": 684,
        "Question": "A mixture contains 30% Ar with CP = 30 J/oC, 30% N2 with CP = 20 J/oC and 40% CH4 with CP = 10 J/oC, what is the average CP of mixture?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t7 J/oC",
            "b)\t12 J/oC",
            "c)\t19 J/oC",
            "d)\t26 J/oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Average CP = 0.3*30 + 0.3*20 + 0.4*10 = 19 J/oC."
    },
    {
        "id": 685,
        "Question": "A mixture contains 20% O2 with CP = 10 J/oC, 30% N2 with CP = 20 J/oC and 50% CO2 with CP= 40 J/oC, what is the average CP of mixture?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20 J/oC",
            "b)\t28 J/oC",
            "c)\t34 J/oC",
            "d)\t42 J/oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Average CP = 0.2*10 + 0.3*20 + 0.5*40 = 2 + 6 + 20 = 28 J/oC."
    },
    {
        "id": 686,
        "Question": "A mixture contains 20% SO2 with CP= 35 J/oC, 30% NO3 with CP = 20 J/oC and 50% CO2 with CP = 40 J/oC, what is the average CP of mixture?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12 J/oC",
            "b)\t17 J/oC",
            "c)\t25 J/oC",
            "d)\t33 J/oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Average CP = 0.2*35 + 0.3*20 + 0.5*40 = 7 + 6 + 20 = 33 J/oC."
    },
    {
        "id": 687,
        "Question": "Heat Capacity of CO2 is given by 12 + 3T + T2, what is the enthalpy change from 0oC to 6oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t169 J",
            "b)\t198 J",
            "c)\t244 J",
            "d)\t360 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ∆H = 0∫6 (12 + 3T + T2).dT = 12*6 + 3*36/2 + 63/3 = 198 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 688,
        "Question": "Heat Capacity of water is given by 4 + T2, what is the enthalpy change from 0oC to 3oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t7 J",
            "b)\t14 J",
            "c)\t21 J",
            "d)\t32 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ∆H = 0∫3 (4 + T2).dT = 4*3 + 33/3 = 21 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 689,
        "Question": "CP-T curve covers 10 J from 2oC to 10oC, what is the enthalpy change?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t20 J",
            "c)\t80 J",
            "d)\t100 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Enthalpy change is the area covered under CP-T curve."
    },
    {
        "id": 690,
        "Question": "CP-T curve of CO2 forms a rectangle of height 10 J/oC from 5oC to 10oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t50 J",
            "c)\t100 J",
            "d)\t250 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Enthalpy change is the area covered under CP-T curve = Area of rectangle = 10*(10 – 5) = 50 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 691,
        "Question": "CP-T curve of H2 forms a rectangle of height 20 J/oC from 4oC to 5oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20 J",
            "b)\t80 J",
            "c)\t100 J",
            "d)\t140 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Enthalpy change is the area covered under CP-T curve = Area of rectangle = 20*(5 – 4) = 20 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 692,
        "Question": "What is the work done by an open steady-state system if heat transferred to it is 10 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t-10 J",
            "c)\t10 J",
            "d)\tCannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In steady state system ∆E = 0, => Work done by the system = 10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 693,
        "Question": "In a closed system, change in internal energy is 10 J and heat transferred to it is 10 J what is the work done by the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t-20 J",
            "d)\t20 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ∆E = W + Q, => W = 10 – 10 = 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 694,
        "Question": "In an open system, what is the enthalpy change is heat taken from it is 10 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t-10 J",
            "c)\t10 J",
            "d)\tCannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For an open system, ∆H = Q, => ∆H = -10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 695,
        "Question": "In an open, steady state adiabatic process if the change in kinetic energy is 10 J and change in potential energy is 15 J, what is the work done by the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t15 J",
            "c)\t25 J",
            "d)\t-25 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: -W = ∆KE + ∆PE = 10 + 15 = 25, => W = -25 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 696,
        "Question": "In an open, steady state system if the heat transferred is 10 J and work done by the system is 5 J, what is the change in Potential energy (neglect kinetic energy)?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J",
            "b)\t-5J",
            "c)\t15 J",
            "d)\t-15 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: W + Q = ∆PE, => ∆PE = 10 – 5 = 5 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 697,
        "Question": "Which of the following is true for isothermal ideal gases?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t∆T = 0",
            "b)\t∆U = 0",
            "c)\t∆H = 0",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: For isothermal ideal gases, ∆T = 0, => ∆U = 0, => ∆H = 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 698,
        "Question": "If the system is insulated which of the following might the process be?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tIsothermal",
            "b)\tIsobaric",
            "c)\tIsochoric",
            "d)\tAdiabatic"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Since the system is insulated, => Q = 0, => Process is adiabatic."
    },
    {
        "id": 699,
        "Question": " What is the work done for an isochoric process?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tPositive",
            "b)\tNegative",
            "c)\tZero",
            "d)\tCannot say"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: W = -PdV, for isochoric process dV = 0, => W = 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 700,
        "Question": "What is the work done for an ideal gas isothermal process?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tZero",
            "b)\tEqual to heat transferred",
            "c)\tEqual to change in internal energy",
            "d)\tCannot say"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For ideal gas isothermal process ∆U = 0, => Work done is equal to heat transferred."
    },
    {
        "id": 701,
        "Question": "What is the work done for an isobaric process?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tP∆V",
            "b)\tV∆P",
            "c)\tPV",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For isobaric process ∆P = 0, => W = P∆V."
    },
    {
        "id": 702,
        "Question": "For an ideal gas isobaric process at pressure 1 Pa, the volume of the gas changes from 1 m3 to 5 m3, what is the work done by the gas?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 J",
            "b)\t4 J",
            "c)\t5 J",
            "d)\t10 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: W = P∆V = 1*(5 – 1) = 4 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 703,
        "Question": "For an ideal gas isothermal process what is the work done by the gas from 1 m3 to 2 m3 at 300 K?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.69 kJ",
            "b)\t1.24 kJ",
            "c)\t1.73 kJ",
            "d)\t2.45 kJ"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: W = RTln (V2/V1) = 8.314*300 ln (2/1) = 1.73 kJ."
    },
    {
        "id": 704,
        "Question": "For an ideal gas isothermal process what is the work done by the gas from 4 Pa to 1 Pa at 300 K?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1.22 kJ",
            "b)\t2.15 kJ",
            "c)\t2.83 kJ",
            "d)\t3.45 kJ"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: W = RTln (P1/P2) = 8.314*300 ln (4/1) = 3.45 kJ."
    },
    {
        "id": 705,
        "Question": "For an ideal gas isochoric process, what is the work done by the gas from 2 Pa to 1 Pa?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t1 J",
            "c)\t200 J",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since the process is isochoric, => W = 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 706,
        "Question": "For an ideal gas isobaric process what is the work done by the gas from 2 m3 to 0.5 m3 at 2 Pa?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-3 J",
            "b)\t3 J",
            "c)\t-5 J",
            "d)\t5 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Work done by the gas = 2*(0.5 – 2) = -3 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 707,
        "Question": "Enthalpy of a stream is which function of temperature and pressure?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tExplicit",
            "b)\tImplicit",
            "c)\tCannot say",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Enthalpy of a stream is an explicit function of temperature and pressure."
    },
    {
        "id": 708,
        "Question": "In a reaction, the feed is 10 moles of 0.1 glucose and 0.9 water, and another feed of 5 moles of 0.2 glucose and 0.8 water, what is the total moles of product?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5",
            "b)\t10",
            "c)\t15",
            "d)\t20"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Total moles of products = 10 + 5 = 15."
    },
    {
        "id": 709,
        "Question": "In a reaction the feed is 10 moles of 0.1 glucose and 0.9 water, and another feed of 5 moles of 0.4 glucose and 0.6 water, what is the fraction of glucose in the products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.2",
            "b)\t0.4",
            "c)\t0.6",
            "d)\t0.8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Total moles of products = 10 + 5 = 15, glucose balance: 0.1*10 + 0.4*5 = x*15, => x = 0.2."
    },
    {
        "id": 710,
        "Question": "In a reaction the feed is 10 moles of 0.1 glucose and 0.9 water, and another feed of 5 moles of 0.4 glucose and 0.6 water, what is the fraction of water in the products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.2",
            "b)\t0.4",
            "c)\t0.6",
            "d)\t0.8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Total moles of products = 10 + 5 = 15, water balance: 0.9*10 + 0.6*5 = x*15, => x = 0.8."
    },
    {
        "id": 711,
        "Question": "In a reaction the feed is 5 moles of 0.5 glucose and 0.5 sucrose, and another feed of 15 moles of 0.3 glucose and 0.7 sucrose, what is the fraction of glucose in the products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.35",
            "b)\t0.45",
            "c)\t0.75",
            "d)\t0.95"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Glucose balance: 5*0.5 + 15*0.3 = x*20, => x = 0.35."
    },
    {
        "id": 712,
        "Question": "Two feeds, F1 with H = 10 J/mole and F2 with H = 20 J/mole, and product 10 moles with H = 15 J/mole, what is the F1?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 mole",
            "b)\t10 mole",
            "c)\t15 mole",
            "d)\t20 mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Energy balance: 10*F1 + 20*F2 = 10*15, => F1 + F2 = 10, => F1 = 5 mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 713,
        "Question": "Two feeds, F1 with H = 10 J/mole and F2 with H = 25 J/mole, and product 15 moles with H = 15 J/mole, what is the F2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 mole",
            "b)\t10 mole",
            "c)\t15 mole",
            "d)\t20 mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Energy balance: 10*F1 + 25*F2 = 15*15, => F1 + F2 = 15, => F2 = 5 mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 714,
        "Question": "Two feeds, 10 moles with H = 10 J/mole and 5 with H = 25 J/mole, what is the enthalpy of products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J/mole",
            "b)\t10 J/mole",
            "c)\t15 J/mole",
            "d)\t20 J/mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Energy balance: 10*10 + 5*25 = 15*H, => H = 15 J/mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 715,
        "Question": "Two feeds, 15 moles with H = 10 J/mole and 10 with H = 20 J/mole, what is the enthalpy of products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t8 J/mole",
            "b)\t12 J/mole",
            "c)\t18 J/mole",
            "d)\t25 J/mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: 25*H = 15*10 + 10*20, => H = 18 J/mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 716,
        "Question": "Two feeds, F1 with H = 10 J/mole and 5 moles with H = 20 J/mole, if the mole of products is 10 what is the enthalpy of products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J/mole",
            "b)\t15 J/mole",
            "c)\t20 J/mole",
            "d)\t25 J/mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 10*5 + 5*20 = 10*H, => H = 15 J/mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 717,
        "Question": "Three feeds, 10 mole with H = 5 J/mole, 10 mole with H = 15 J/mole and 5 mole with 20 J/mole, what is the enthalpy of the products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J/mole",
            "b)\t12 J/mole",
            "c)\t15 J/mole",
            "d)\t24 J/mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 25*H = 10*5 + 10*15 + 5*20, => H = 12 J/mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 718,
        "Question": "Three feeds, 10 mole with H = 25 J/mole, 5 mole with H = 10 J/mole and 15 mole with 20 J/mole, what is the enthalpy of the products?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J/mole",
            "b)\t12 J/mole",
            "c)\t20 J/mole",
            "d)\t28 J/mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: 30*H = 10*25 + 5*10 + 15*20, => H = 20 J/mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 719,
        "Question": "Three feeds, 10 mole with H = 15 J/mole, 20 mole with H = 5 J/mole and F1 with 20 J/mole, if enthalpy of the products is H = 15 J/mole, what is the value of F1?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 mole",
            "b)\t20 mole",
            "c)\t30 mole",
            "d)\t40 mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: 10*15 + 20*5 + F1*20 = (30 + F1)*15, => F1 = 40 mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 720,
        "Question": "Two feeds, 10 mole with 5 J/mole and 20 mole with 15 J/mole, product contains two streams, 5 mole with 10 J/mole and P with 25 J/mole, what is the value of P?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 mole",
            "b)\t12 mole",
            "c)\t15 mole",
            "d)\t18 mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 10*5 + 20*15 = 5*10 + P*25, => P = 12 mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 721,
        "Question": "Two feeds, 5 mole with 25 J/mole and F with 5 J/mole, product contains two streams, 5 mole with 10 J/mole and 10 mole with 15 J/mole, what is the value of F?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 mole",
            "b)\t15 mole",
            "c)\t20 mole",
            "d)\t25 mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: 5*25 + F*5 = 5*10 + 10*15, => F = 25 mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 722,
        "Question": "What is the energy balance of a closed system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tMatter in the system is constant",
            "b)\tEnergy in the system is constant",
            "c)\tNeither energy nor matter is constant",
            "d)\tBoth of energy and matter are constant"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For closed system energy balance, matter in the system is constant."
    },
    {
        "id": 723,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred to the system, if a change in internal energy is 10 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t-10 J",
            "c)\t10 J",
            "d)\tCannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Q = ∆U = 10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 724,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred to the system, if change in enthalpy is 15 J and change in volume is 2 m3 at 5 Pa?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J",
            "b)\t8 J",
            "c)\t10 J",
            "d)\t12 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Q = ∆H – P∆V = 15 – 5*2 = 5 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 725,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred to the system, if a change in enthalpy is 25 J and change in pressure is 5 Pa at volume 3 m3?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t15 J",
            "d)\t20 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Q = ∆H – V∆P = 25 – 3*5 = 10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 726,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred to the system, if change in enthalpy is 30 J and pressure, volume changed from 8 Pa, 5 m3 to 4 Pa, 12 m3?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12 J",
            "b)\t15 J",
            "c)\t18 J",
            "d)\t22 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Q = ∆H – V∆P = 30 – (4*12 – 8*5) = 22 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 727,
        "Question": "The specific volume of SO2 is 10 m3/Kg, at 5 Pa, H = 100 J/Kg and at 10 Pa, H = 250 J/Kg, what is the heat transferred to the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t100 J/Kg",
            "b)\t150 J/Kg",
            "c)\t250 J/Kg",
            "d)\t350 J/Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Q = ∆H – V∆P = (250 – 100) – 10(10 – 5) = 100 J/Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 728,
        "Question": "The specific volume of a gas is 5 m3/Kg, at 10 Pa, H = 50 J/Kg and at 20 Pa, H = 100 J/Kg, what is the heat transferred to the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t50 J/Kg",
            "c)\t100 J/Kg",
            "d)\t150 J/Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Q = ∆H – V∆P = (100 – 50) – 5(20 – 10) = 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 729,
        "Question": "The specific volume of a gas is 5 m3/Kg, at 25 Pa, H = 40 J/Kg and at 40 Pa, H = 90 J/Kg, what is the heat transferred to the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-5 J/Kg",
            "b)\t5 J/Kg",
            "c)\t-25 J/Kg",
            "d)\t25 J/Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Q = ∆H – V∆P = (90 – 40) – 5(40 – 25) = -25 J/Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 730,
        "Question": "The specific volume of a gas is 2 m3/Kg, at 12 Pa, H = 30 J/Kg and at 15 Pa, H = 45 J/Kg, what is the heat transferred to the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t6 J/Kg",
            "b)\t9 J/Kg",
            "c)\t12 J/Kg",
            "d)\t15 J/Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Q = ∆H – V∆P = (45 – 30) – 2(15 – 12) = 15 – 6 = 9 J/Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 731,
        "Question": "The specific volume of a gas is 3 m3/Kg, at 6 Pa, H = 4 J/Kg and at 9 Pa, H = 14 J/Kg, what is the heat transferred to the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t1 J/Kg",
            "c)\t5 J/Kg",
            "d)\t25 J/Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Q = ∆H – V∆P = (14 – 4) – 3(9 – 6) = 1 J/Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 732,
        "Question": "What is the energy balance to open system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tEnergy in the system is constant",
            "b)\tMatter in the system is constant",
            "c)\tMatter is constant energy is variable",
            "d)\tBoth matter and energy are variable"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Both matter and energy are variable in an open system."
    },
    {
        "id": 733,
        "Question": "5 Kg of water is pumped to a height of 5 m, the enthalpy is changed by 10 J/Kg, and work done by the motor is 100 J/Kg, assuming system is insulated what is the change in internal energy of water?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t50 J",
            "b)\t100 J",
            "c)\t150 J",
            "d)\t200 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:  ∆U = Q + W – m (∆H + ∆PE + ∆KE), => ∆U = 0 + 100*5 – 5 (10 + 10*5) = 500 – 50 – 250 = 200 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 734,
        "Question": "10 Kg of water is pumped to a height of 2 m, the enthalpy is changed by 15 J/Kg, and work done by the motor is 50 J/Kg, assuming system is insulated what is the change in internal energy of water?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t50 J",
            "b)\t100 J",
            "c)\t150 J",
            "d)\t200 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ∆U = Q + W – m (∆H + ∆PE + ∆KE), => ∆U = 0 + 50*10 – 10*(15 + 10*2) = 500 – 350 = 150 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 735,
        "Question": "1 Kg of water is pumped to a height of 1 m, the enthalpy is changed by 5 J/Kg, and work done by the motor is 25 J/Kg, assuming a system is insulated what is the change in internal energy of water?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t25 J",
            "c)\t35 J",
            "d)\t50 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ∆U = Q + W – m (∆H + ∆PE + ∆KE), => ∆U = 0 + 25*1 – 1*(5 + 10*1) = 25 – 15 = 10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 736,
        "Question": "1 Kg of water is pumped to a height of 10 m, the enthalpy is changed by 50 J/Kg, and work done by the motor is 300 J/Kg, assuming a system is insulated what is the change in internal energy of water?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t100 J",
            "b)\t150 J",
            "c)\t200 J",
            "d)\t300 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ∆U = 0 + 300*1 – 1*(50 + 10*10) = 150 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 737,
        "Question": "2 Kg of water (CP = 0.15 J/KgoC) is pumped to a height of 0.1 m, work done by the motor is 10 J/Kg, and heat liberated by it is 5 J/Kg, what is the final temperature of water if the initial temperature was 27oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10oC",
            "b)\t19oC",
            "c)\t27oC",
            "d)\t37oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ∆U = Q + W – m (∆H + ∆PE + ∆KE), => 0 = – 5 + 10 – 2(∆H + 10*0.1), => ∆H = 1.5 J/Kg, => 1.5 = 0.15(T – 27), => T = 37oC."
    },
    {
        "id": 738,
        "Question": "1 Kg of water (CP = 0.5 J/KgoC) is pumped to a height of 0.5 m, work done by the motor is 40 J/Kg, and heat liberated by it is 10 J/Kg, what is the final temperature of water if the initial temperature was 10oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10oC",
            "b)\t30oC",
            "c)\t40oC",
            "d)\t60oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ∆U = Q + W – m (∆H + ∆PE + ∆KE), => 0 = – 10 + 40 – 1*(∆H + 10*0.4), => ∆H = 25 J/Kg, => 25 = 0.5(T – 10), => T = 60oC."
    },
    {
        "id": 739,
        "Question": "1 Kg of water (CP = 0.5 J/KgoC) is pumped to a height of 1 m, work done by the motor is 20 J/Kg, and heat liberated by it is 5 J/Kg, what is the final temperature of water if the initial temperature was 20oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20oC",
            "b)\t30oC",
            "c)\t40oC",
            "d)\t50oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ∆U = Q + W – m (∆H + ∆PE + ∆KE), => 0 = – 5 + 20 – 1*(∆H + 10*1), => ∆H = 5 J/Kg, => 5 = 0.5(T – 20), => T = 30oC."
    },
    {
        "id": 740,
        "Question": "1 Kg of water (CP = 0.4 J/KgoC) is pumped to a height of 2 m, work done by the motor is 50 J/Kg, and heat liberated by it is 10 J/Kg, what is the final temperature of water if the initial temperature was 25oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25oC",
            "b)\t45oC",
            "c)\t60oC",
            "d)\t75oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ∆U = Q + W – m (∆H + ∆PE + ∆KE), => 0 = – 10 + 50 – 1*(∆H + 10*2), => ∆H = 20 J/Kg, => 20 = 0.4(T – 20), => T = 75oC."
    },
    {
        "id": 741,
        "Question": "5 Kg of water (CP = 1 J/KgoC) is pumped to a height of 0.5 m, work done by the motor is 50 J/Kg, and heat liberated by it is 5 J/Kg, what is the final temperature of water if the initial temperature was 0oC?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2oC",
            "b)\t4oC",
            "c)\t6oC",
            "d)\t8oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ∆U = Q + W – m (∆H + ∆PE + ∆KE), => 0 = – 5 + 50 – 5*(∆H + 10*0.5), => ∆H = 6 J/Kg, => 6 = 1*(T – 0), => T = 6oC."
    },
    {
        "id": 742,
        "Question": "For exothermic reactions, what is the heat of reaction?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tPositive",
            "b)\tNegative",
            "c)\tZero",
            "d)\tCannot Say"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In exothermic reactions, heat leaves the system, so the heat of reaction is negative."
    },
    {
        "id": 743,
        "Question": "For endothermic reactions, what is the heat of reaction?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tPositive",
            "b)\tNegative",
            "c)\tZero",
            "d)\tCannot Say"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In endothermic reactions, heat comes into the system, so the heat of reaction is positive."
    },
    {
        "id": 744,
        "Question": "Enthalpy of reactants is 15 J/Kg and enthalpy of products is 40 J/Kg, what is the heat of reaction?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-10 J/Kg",
            "b)\t10 J/Kg",
            "c)\t-25 J/Kg",
            "d)\t25 J/Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 40 – 15 = 25 J/Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 745,
        "Question": "Enthalpy of reactants is 50 J/Kg and enthalpy of products is 25 J/Kg, what is the heat of reaction?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-10 J/Kg",
            "b)\t10 J/Kg",
            "c)\t-25 J/Kg",
            "d)\t25 J/Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 25 – 50 = -25 J/Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 746,
        "Question": "Enthalpy of reactants is 30 J/Kg and enthalpy of products is 10 J/Kg, what is the heat of reaction?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-20 J/Kg",
            "b)\t20 J/Kg",
            "c)\t-10 J/Kg",
            "d)\t10 J/Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 10 – 30 = -20 J/Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 747,
        "Question": "Heat of formations of A, B, C, and D, are 5 J, 10 J, 15 J, and 20 J respectively, what is the heat of reaction A + 4B -> 3C + D?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t20 J",
            "c)\t35 J",
            "d)\t45 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 20 + 3*15 – 4*10 – 5 = 20 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 748,
        "Question": "Heat of formations of A, B, C, and D, are 5 J, 8 J, 2 J, and 15 J respectively, what is the heat of reaction 3A + B -> 3C + 2D?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t9 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t13 J",
            "d)\t15 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 2*15 + 3*2 – 8 – 3*5 = 13 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 749,
        "Question": "Heat of formations of A, B, C, and D, are 1 J, 2 J, 3 J, and 4 J respectively, what is the heat of reaction 3A + 4B -> 2C + D?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-1 J",
            "b)\t1 J",
            "c)\t3 J",
            "d)\t6 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 4 + 2*3 – 4*2 – 3*1 = -1 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 750,
        "Question": "Heat of formations of A, B, C, and D, are 2 J, 5 J, 3 J, and 10 J respectively, what is the heat of reaction 4A + 5B -> 2C + 2D?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-10 J",
            "b)\t-7 J",
            "c)\t-5 J",
            "d)\t0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 2*10 + 2*3 – 5*5 – 4*2 = -7 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 751,
        "Question": "Heat of formations of A, B, C, and D, are 3 J, 5 J, 4 J, and 8 J respectively, what is the heat of reaction 2A + 2B -> 2C + D?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-5 J",
            "b)\t0",
            "c)\t5 J",
            "d)\t8 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 8 + 2*4 – 2*5 – 2*3 = 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 752,
        "Question": "In the reaction C + O2 -> CO2, if the heat liberated is 10 J, what is the heat of formation of CO2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-10 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t0",
            "d)\tCannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Heat of formation = -10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 753,
        "Question": "In the reaction 2H2 + O2 -> 2H2O, if the heat liberated is 50 J, what is the heat of formation of H2O?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-25 J",
            "b)\t25 J",
            "c)\t-50 J",
            "d)\t50 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Heat of formation = -50/2 = -25 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 754,
        "Question": "In the reaction 2N -> N2, if the heat liberated is 6 J, what is the heat of formation of N2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t– 6 J",
            "b)\t6 J",
            "c)\t0",
            "d)\tCannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Heat of formation = -6 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 755,
        "Question": "In the reaction 2C + O2-> 2CO, if the heat liberated is 10 J, what is the heat of formation of CO?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-5 J",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t-10 J",
            "d)\t10 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Heat of formation = -10/2 = -5 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 756,
        "Question": "In the reaction C + 2H2 -> CH4, if the heat liberated is -5 J, what is the heat of formation of CH4?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-5J",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t0 J",
            "d)\tCannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Heat of formation = – (-5) = 5 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 757,
        "Question": "The standard heat of reaction is a heat of reaction for how many moles of compound?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t1",
            "c)\t2",
            "d)\t3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The standard heat of reaction is a heat of reaction for one mole of compound."
    },
    {
        "id": 758,
        "Question": "What is the heat of reaction for CH4 + 2O2 -> CO2 + 2H2O, if heat of formation of CH4, O2, CO2 and H2O are 10 J, 5 J, 6 J, and 12 J respectively?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-10 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t-20 J",
            "d)\t20 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 2*12 + 6 – 2*5 – 10 = 10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 759,
        "Question": "What is the heat of reaction for 2H2 + O2 -> 2H2O, if heat of formation of H2, O2, and H2O are 2 J, 5 J, and 10 J respectively?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 J",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t8 J",
            "d)\t11 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 2*10 – 2*2 – 5 = 11 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 760,
        "Question": "What is the heat of reaction for C2H4 + 3O2 -> 2CO2 + 2H2O, if heat of formation of C2H4, O2, CO2, and H2O are 10 J, 5 J, 6 J and 2 J respectively?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-4 J",
            "b)\t-2 J",
            "c)\t0",
            "d)\t4 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 2*2 + 2*6 – 10 – 2*5 = -4 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 761,
        "Question": "What is the heat of reaction for C6H6 + 3H2 -> C6H12, if heat of formation of C6H6, H2, and C6H12 are 25 J, 5 J and 50 J respectively?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t20 J",
            "c)\t30 J",
            "d)\t35 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 50 – 3*5 – 25 = 10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 762,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy of reaction for C + O2 -> CO2, if the conversion of C is 50%, and heat of formation of C, O2, and CO2 are 0, 0 and 10 J.",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t15 J",
            "d)\t20 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 10*0.5 – 0 – 0 = 5 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 763,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy of reaction for CH4 + 2O2 -> CO2 + 2H2O, if the conversion of CH4 is 50%, and heat of formation of CH4, O2, CO2, and H2O are 10 J, 0, 6 J and 4 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t2 J",
            "c)\t4 J",
            "d)\t6 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 2*4*0.5 + 6*0.5 + 10*0.5 – 2*0 – 10 = 4 + 3 + 5 – 10 = 2 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 764,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy of reaction for C2H4 + 3O2 -> 2CO2+ 2H2O, if the conversion of CH4 is 50%, and heat of formation of CH4, O2, CO2, and H2O are 10 J, 0, 6 J and 4 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t2 J",
            "c)\t5 J",
            "d)\t10 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 2*4*0.5 + 2*6*0.5 + 10*0.5 – 0 – 10*0.5 = 10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 765,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy of reaction for CO2 + 4H2 -> 2H2O + CH4, if the conversion of CO2 is 50%, and heat of formation of CO2, H2, H2O, and CH4 are 6 J, 0, 4 J and 10 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 J",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t6 J",
            "d)\t9 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 10*0.5 + 2*4*0.5 + 6*0.5 – 6*0.5 = 9 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 766,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy of reaction forC6H6 -> 3C2H2, if the conversion of C6H6 is 80%, and heat of formation of C6H6, and C2H2 are 24 J, and 8 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t2.4 J",
            "c)\t4.8 J",
            "d)\t5.6 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 3*8*0.8 + 24*0.2 – 24*0.8 = 4.8 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 767,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy change of a reaction at 45oC, if the enthalpy of reactant at 45oC and 25oC are 10 J and 6 J, and enthalpy of product at 45oC and 25oC are 15 J and 8 J, and the enthalpy change of reaction at 25oC is 10 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t14 J",
            "b)\t21 J",
            "c)\t27 J",
            "d)\t34 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = (10 – 6) + (15 – 8) + 10 = 21 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 768,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy change of a reaction at 35oC, if the enthalpy of reactant at 35oC and 25oC are 18 J and 10 J, and enthalpy of product at 35oC and 25oC are 12 J and 8 J, and the enthalpy change of reaction at 25oC is 15 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t9 J",
            "b)\t14 J",
            "c)\t22 J",
            "d)\t27 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = (18 – 10) + (12 – 8) + 15 = 27 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 769,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy change of a reaction at 35oC, if the enthalpy of reactant at 35oC and 25oC are 22 J and 15 J, and enthalpy of product at 35oC and 25oC are 10 J and 5 J, and the enthalpy change of reaction at 25oC is 36 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12 J",
            "b)\t24 J",
            "c)\t36 J",
            "d)\t48 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = (22 – 15) + (10 – 5) + 36 = 7 + 5 + 36 = 48 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 770,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy change of a reaction at 30oC, if the enthalpy of reactant at 30oC and 25oC are 18 J and 15 J, and enthalpy of product at 30oC and 25oC are 10 J and 8 J, and the enthalpy change of reaction at 25oC is 45 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t25 J",
            "c)\t50 J",
            "d)\t100 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = (18 – 15) + (10 – 8) + 45 = 50 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 771,
        "Question": " What is the enthalpy change of a reaction at 90oC, if the enthalpy of reactant at 90oC and 25oC are 60 J and 25 J, and enthalpy of product at 90oC and 25oC are 80 J and 10 J, and the enthalpy change of reaction at 25oC is 5 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t50 J",
            "c)\t110 J",
            "d)\t150 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = (60 – 25) + (80 – 10) + 5 = 110 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 772,
        "Question": "How are enthalpies of streams calculated?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tRelative to the reference state",
            "b)\tAbsolutely",
            "c)\tDepends on the reaction",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Enthalpies of the streams are calculated relative to the reference state."
    },
    {
        "id": 773,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy of a reaction, if the standard heat of formation of a compound is 10 J and sensible heat of the compound is 5 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t10 J",
            "d)\t15 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Enthalpy of reaction = 10 + 5 = 15 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 774,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy of a reaction, if the standard heat of formation of a compound is 15 J and sensible heat of the compound is 25 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t15 J",
            "b)\t25 J",
            "c)\t40 J",
            "d)\t50 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Enthalpy of reaction = 15 + 25 = 40 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 775,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy of a reaction, if the standard heat of formation of a compound is 15 J, sensible heat of the compound is 25 J, and latent heat of the compound is 10 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25 J",
            "b)\t40 J",
            "c)\t50 J",
            "d)\t65 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Enthalpy of reaction = 15 + 25 + 10 = 50 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 776,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy of a reaction, if the standard heat of formation of a compound is 10 J, sensible heat of the compound is 30 J, and latent heat of the compound is 20 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t30 J",
            "c)\t40 J",
            "d)\t60 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Enthalpy of reaction = 10 + 30 + 20 = 60 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 777,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy of the reaction from 25oC to 40oC if CP = 10 J/oC, and the reference enthalpy is 10 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t80 J",
            "b)\t120 J",
            "c)\t160 J",
            "d)\t200 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Enthalpy of reaction = 10 + 25∫4010.dT = 10 + 10*15 = 160 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 778,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy of the reaction from 10oC to 15oC if CP = 5 J/oC, and the reference enthalpy is 25 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25 J",
            "b)\t50 J",
            "c)\t75 J",
            "d)\t100 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Enthalpy of reaction = 25 + 10∫155.dT = 25 + 5*5 = 50 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 779,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy of the reaction from 10oC to 25oC if CP = 2 J/oC, and the reference enthalpy is 20 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t50 J",
            "b)\t60 J",
            "c)\t75 J",
            "d)\t90 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Enthalpy of reaction = 20 + 10∫252.dT = 20 + 15*2 = 50 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 780,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy of the reaction from 15oC to 25oC if CP = 3 J/oC, and the reference enthalpy is 15 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t15 J",
            "b)\t30 J",
            "c)\t45 J",
            "d)\t60 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Enthalpy of reaction = 15 + 15∫253.dT = 15 + 3*10 = 45 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 781,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy of the reaction from 50oC to 52oC if CP = 15 J/oC, and the reference enthalpy is 25 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t35 J",
            "c)\t55 J",
            "d)\t65 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Enthalpy of reaction = 25 + 50∫5215.dT = 25 + 2*15 = 55 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 782,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred to the system if the enthalpy of the output is 10 J and input is 6 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4 J",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t6 J",
            "d)\t8 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Q = ∆Hout – ∆Hin = 10 – 6 = 4 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 783,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred to the system if the enthalpy of the output is 14 J and input is 8 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4 J",
            "b)\t6 J",
            "c)\t8 J",
            "d)\t10 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Q = 14 – 8 = 6 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 784,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred to the system if the enthalpy of the output is 15 J and input is 10 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 J",
            "b)\t2 J",
            "c)\t4 J",
            "d)\t5 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Q = 15 – 10 = 5 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 785,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred from the system if the enthalpy of the output is 5 J and input is 10 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-5 J",
            "b)\t-10 J",
            "c)\t-15 J",
            "d)\t5 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Heat transferred from the system = 10 – 5 = 5 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 786,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred from the system if the enthalpy of the output is 25 J and input is 10 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J",
            "b)\t-5 J",
            "c)\t15 J",
            "d)\t-15 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Heat transferred from the system = 10 – 25 = -15 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 787,
        "Question": "What is the heat of reaction if the heat of combustion of products is 10 J and heat of combustion of reactants is 5 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-5 J",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t10 J",
            "d)\tCannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 5 – 10 = -5 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 788,
        "Question": "What is the heat of reaction if the heat of combustion of products is 10 J and heat of combustion of reactants is 15 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-5 J",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t10 J",
            "d)\tCannot say"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 15 – 10 = 5 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 789,
        "Question": "What is the heat of reaction if the heat of combustion of products is 40 J and heat of combustion of reactants is 25 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t15 J",
            "d)\t-15 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 25 – 40 = -15 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 790,
        "Question": "What is the heat of reaction if the heat of combustion of products is 25 J and heat of combustion of reactants is 15 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-5 J",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t-10 J",
            "d)\t10 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 15 – 25 = -10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 791,
        "Question": "What is the heat of reaction if the heat of combustion of products is 2 J and heat of combustion of reactants is 10 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t8 J",
            "b)\t-8 J",
            "c)\t4 J",
            "d)\t-4 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 10 – 2 = 8 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 792,
        "Question": "What is the heating value of 10 Kg of coal with heat of combustion 10 J/Kg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-10 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t-100 J",
            "d)\t100 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Heating value = – Heat of combustion = -10*10 = -100 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 793,
        "Question": "What is the heating value of 2 Kg of coal with heat of combustion 15 J/Kg?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-15 J",
            "b)\t15 J",
            "c)\t-30 J",
            "d)\t30 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Heating value = – Heat of combustion = -15*2 = -30 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 794,
        "Question": "What is the difference between higher heating value and lower heating value if the product has 5 moles of H2O and Enthalpy of vaporization is 10 J/mole at standard conditions?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t-10 J",
            "c)\t50 J",
            "d)\t-50 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: HHV – LHV = 5*10 = 50 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 795,
        "Question": "What is the difference between lower heating value and higher heating value if the product has 2 moles of H2O and Enthalpy of vaporization is 40 J/mole at standard conditions?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-40 J",
            "b)\t40 J",
            "c)\t-80 J",
            "d)\t80 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: LHV – HHV = -2*40 = -80 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 796,
        "Question": "What is the value of higher heating value if the value of lower heating value is 10 J and the product has 5 moles of H2O and Enthalpy of vaporization is 4 J/mole at standard conditions?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t20 J",
            "c)\t30 J",
            "d)\t40 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: HHV = 10 + 5*4 = 30 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 797,
        "Question": "What is the heat of reaction for CH4 + 2O2 -> CO2 + 2H2O, if the heat of combustion of H2O = 5 J, CO2 = 10 J, O2 = 0, and CH4 = 25 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-5 J",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t-10 J",
            "d)\t10 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 25 + 0 – 10 – 2*5 = 5 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 798,
        "Question": "What is the heat of reaction for N2 + 3H2 -> 2NH3, if the heat of combustion of N2 = 5 J, H2 = 2 J, and NH3 = 15 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-5 J",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t-19 J",
            "d)\t19 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 3*2 + 5 – 15*2 = -19 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 799,
        "Question": "What is the heat of reaction for 2CO + O2 -> 2CO2, if the heat of combustion of CO = 20 J, O2 = 5 J, and CO2 = 25 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J",
            "b)\t-5 J",
            "c)\t15 J",
            "d)\t-15 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 20*2 + 5 – 2*25 = -5 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 800,
        "Question": "What is the heat of reaction for H2 + Cl2 -> 2HCl, if the heat of combustion of H2 = 2 J, Cl2 = 10 J, and HCl = 10 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-8 J",
            "b)\t8 J",
            "c)\t-10 J",
            "d)\t10 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 10 + 2 – 2*10 = -8 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 801,
        "Question": "What is the heat of reaction for C6H6 + 3H2 -> C6H12, if the heat of combustion of H2 = 2 J, C6H6= 30 J, and C6H12 = 25 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-6 J",
            "b)\t6 J",
            "c)\t-11 J",
            "d)\t11 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = 30 + 2*3 – 25 = 11 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 802,
        "Question": "What are the degrees of freedom?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tTotal variables in the process",
            "b)\tTotal species in the process",
            "c)\tTotal reactions in the process",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Degrees of freedom is the total number of variables involved in the process."
    },
    {
        "id": 803,
        "Question": "What are the total degrees of freedom if the number of species are 5, total streams are 2, stream temperature 2, stream pressure 2 and heat released 1?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t5",
            "c)\t6",
            "d)\t12"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Degrees of freedom = 5 + 2 + 2 + 2 + 1 = 12."
    },
    {
        "id": 804,
        "Question": "What are the total degrees of freedom if the number of species are 8, total streams are 3, stream temperature 3, stream pressure 3 and heat released 1, extent of reaction 2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t8",
            "b)\t12",
            "c)\t15",
            "d)\t17"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Degrees of freedom = 8 + 3 + 3 + 3 + 1 + 2 = 17."
    },
    {
        "id": 805,
        "Question": "What are the total degrees of freedom if the number of species are 4, total streams are 2, stream temperature 2, stream pressure 1 and heat released 1, extent of reaction 1?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4",
            "b)\t7",
            "c)\t11",
            "d)\t15"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Degrees of freedom = 4 + 2 + 2 + 1 + 1 + 1 = 11."
    },
    {
        "id": 806,
        "Question": "What are the total degrees of freedom if the number of species are 8, total streams are 4, stream temperature 2, stream pressure 2 and heat released 1, extent of reaction 3?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12",
            "b)\t16",
            "c)\t20",
            "d)\t24"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Degrees of freedom = 8 + 4 + 2 + 2 + 1 + 3 = 20."
    },
    {
        "id": 807,
        "Question": "In a reactor two stream are entering, one with CH4 at 10 atm and 27oC, and another with O2 at 10 atm and 0oC, producing CO2, CO, H2O, and O2 at 10 atm and 23oC, what are the total degrees of freedom?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12",
            "b)\t16",
            "c)\t18",
            "d)\t20"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Total species = 1 + 1 + 4 = 6, total stream flows = 3, stream pressures = 3, stream temperatures = 3, heat released = 1, and extent of reaction = 2, => degrees of freedom = 6 + 3 + 3 + 3 + 1 + 2 = 18."
    },
    {
        "id": 808,
        "Question": "In a reactor two stream are entering, one with H2 at 10 atm and 27oC, and another with O2 at 10 atm and 0oC, producing H2O2, H2O, and O2 at 10 atm and 23oC, what are the total degrees of freedom?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12",
            "b)\t17",
            "c)\t19",
            "d)\t23"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Total species = 1 + 1 + 3 = 5, total stream flows = 3, stream pressures = 3, stream temperatures = 3, heat released = 1, and extent of reaction = 2, => degrees of freedom = 5 + 3 + 3 + 3 + 1 + 2 = 17."
    },
    {
        "id": 809,
        "Question": "In a reactor two stream are entering, one with N2 at 10 atm and 27oC, and another with O2 at 10 atm and 0oC, producing NO, NO2, NO3, and O2 at 10 atm and 23oC, what are the total degrees of freedom?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12",
            "b)\t17",
            "c)\t19",
            "d)\t21"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Total species = 1 + 1 + 4 = 6, total stream flows = 3, stream pressures = 3, stream temperatures = 3, heat released = 1, and extent of reaction = 3, => degrees of freedom = 6 + 3 + 3 + 3 + 1 + 3 = 19."
    },
    {
        "id": 810,
        "Question": "In a reactor two stream are entering, one with S at 10 atm and 27oC, and another with O2 at 10 atm and 0oC, producing SO2, SO3, and O2 at 10 atm and 23oC, what are the total degrees of freedom?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10",
            "b)\t13",
            "c)\t15",
            "d)\t17"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Total species = 1 + 1 + 3 = 5, total stream flows = 3, stream pressures = 3, stream temperatures = 3, heat released = 1, and extent of reaction = 2, => degrees of freedom = 5 + 3 + 3 + 3 + 1 + 2 = 17."
    },
    {
        "id": 811,
        "Question": "In a reactor two stream are entering, one with H2 at 10 atm and 27oC, and another with O2 at 10 atm and 0oC, producing H2O at 10 atm and 23oC, what are the total degrees of freedom?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10",
            "b)\t14",
            "c)\t16",
            "d)\t19"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Total species = 1 + 1 + 1 = 3, total stream flows = 3, stream pressures = 3, stream temperatures = 3, heat released = 1, and extent of reaction = 1, => degrees of freedom = 3 + 3 + 3 + 3 + 1 + 1 = 14."
    },
    {
        "id": 812,
        "Question": "If the reactions are unknown, is it possible to determine the degrees of freedom?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tYes",
            "b)\tNo",
            "c)\tDepends on the type of reaction",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For degrees of freedom calculation, number of species are required for which the reactions should be known."
    },
    {
        "id": 813,
        "Question": "In a reactor two stream are entering, one with CH4 at 10 atm and 27oC, and another with O2 at 10 atm and 0oC, producing CO2 and H2O at 10 atm and 23oC, what are the total degrees of freedom?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10",
            "b)\t12",
            "c)\t15",
            "d)\t17"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Total species = 1 + 1 + 2 = 4, total stream flows = 3, stream pressures = 3, stream temperatures = 3, heat released = 1, and extent of reaction = 1, => degrees of freedom = 4 + 3 + 3 + 3 + 1 + 1 = 15."
    },
    {
        "id": 814,
        "Question": "In a reactor two stream are entering, one with C6H6 at 10 atm and 27oC, and another with H2 at 10 atm and 0oC, producing C6H12 and H2 at 10 atm and 23oC, what are the total degrees of freedom?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10",
            "b)\t15",
            "c)\t20",
            "d)\t23"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Total species = 1 + 1 + 2 = 4, total stream flows = 3, stream pressures = 3, stream temperatures = 3, heat released = 1, and extent of reaction = 1, => degrees of freedom = 4 + 3 + 3 + 3 + 1 + 1 = 15."
    },
    {
        "id": 815,
        "Question": "In a reactor two stream are entering, one with C6H6 at 10 atm and 27oC, and another with H2 at 10 atm and 0oC, producing C6H6, C6H12, and H2 at 10 atm and 23oC, what are the total degrees of freedom?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10",
            "b)\t12",
            "c)\t15",
            "d)\t16"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Total species = 1 + 1 + 3 = 5, total stream flows = 3, stream pressures = 3, stream temperatures = 3, heat released = 1, and extent of reaction = 1, => degrees of freedom = 5 + 3 + 3 + 3 + 1 + 1 = 16."
    },
    {
        "id": 816,
        "Question": "In a reactor two stream are entering, one with CO2 at 10 atm and 27oC, and another with H2O at 10 atm and 0oC, producing CH4, CO2, H2O, and O2 at 10 atm and 23oC, what are the total degrees of freedom?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10",
            "b)\t15",
            "c)\t17",
            "d)\t21"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Total species = 1 + 1 + 4 = 6, total stream flows = 3, stream pressures = 3, stream temperatures = 3, heat released = 1, and extent of reaction = 1, => degrees of freedom = 6 + 3 + 3 + 3 + 1 + 1 = 17."
    },
    {
        "id": 817,
        "Question": "What is the sensible heat of a reaction if the enthalpy of outputs is 15 J, and enthalpy of inputs is 5 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3 J",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t10 J",
            "d)\t15 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Q = ∆Houtput – ∆Hinput = 15 – 5 = 10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 818,
        "Question": "What is the sensible heat of a reaction if the enthalpy of outputs is 5 J, and enthalpy of inputs is 10 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-5 J",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t-10 J",
            "d)\t10 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Q = ∆Houtput – ∆Hinput = 5 – 10 = -5J."
    },
    {
        "id": 819,
        "Question": "What is the heat of reaction if enthalpy of inputs and outputs at 25oC are 10 J and 20 J, the enthalpy of input and outputs at given temperature are 25 J and 30 J, enthalpy change of the reaction is 50 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t45 J",
            "b)\t50 J",
            "c)\t55 J",
            "d)\t60 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = (25 – 10) – (30 – 20) + 50 = 55 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 820,
        "Question": "What is the heat of reaction if enthalpy of inputs and outputs at 25oC are 5 J and 8 J, the enthalpy of input and outputs at given temperature are 12 J and 15 J, enthalpy change of the reaction is 25 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20 J",
            "b)\t25 J",
            "c)\t30 J",
            "d)\t35 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = (12 – 5) – (15 – 8) + 25 = 25 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 821,
        "Question": "What is the heat of reaction if enthalpy of inputs and outputs at 25oC are 10 J and 8 J, the enthalpy of input and outputs at given temperature are 5 J and 20 J, enthalpy change of the reaction is 30 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t13 J",
            "b)\t22 J",
            "c)\t28 J",
            "d)\t35 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Heat of reaction = (5 – 10) – (20 – 8) + 30 = 13 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 822,
        "Question": "Theoretical flame temperature is defined for which process?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tIsothermal",
            "b)\tAdiabatic",
            "c)\tIsobaric",
            "d)\tIsochoric"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Theoretical flame temperature is defined for adiabatic processes."
    },
    {
        "id": 823,
        "Question": "What is the heat for the process for which theoretical flame temperature is defined?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tPositive",
            "b)\tNegative",
            "c)\tZero",
            "d)\tCannot say"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Theoretical flame temperature is defined for adiabatic processes, => Q = 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 824,
        "Question": "How much the limiting reactant reacts in the process for which theoretical flame temperature is defined?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tCompletely",
            "b)\tPartially",
            "c)\tDoes not react",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The limiting reactant reacts completely in the process for which theoretical flame temperature is defined."
    },
    {
        "id": 825,
        "Question": "What are other effects occur in the process for which theoretical flame temperature is defined?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tElectrical effects",
            "b)\tFree radical formation",
            "c)\tIonization",
            "d)\tNo other effects"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: No other effect occurs in the process for which theoretical flame temperature is defined."
    },
    {
        "id": 826,
        "Question": "If the temperature of the reaction is 25oC what will be the temperature of the products of the reaction for which theoretical flame temperature is defined?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25oC",
            "b)\t45oC",
            "c)\t75oC",
            "d)\t100oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: For the reaction in which theoretical flame temperature is defined temperature of the products is same as the temperature of the reaction."
    },
    {
        "id": 827,
        "Question": "If the temperature of the reaction is 50oC what will be the temperature of the products of the reaction for which theoretical flame temperature is defined?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25oC",
            "b)\t50oC",
            "c)\t75oC",
            "d)\t100oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For the reaction in which theoretical flame temperature is defined temperature of the products is same as the temperature of the reaction."
    },
    {
        "id": 828,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred for a 10 mole unsteady state closed system, if a change in internal energy is 5 J/mole?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t50 J",
            "d)\t100 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Q = ∆U = 10*5 = 50 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 829,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred for a 10 mole unsteady state closed system, if initial internal energy is 6 J/mole and final internal energy is 10 J/mole?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t40 J",
            "d)\t60 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Q = Uf – Ui = 10(10 – 6) = 40 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 830,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred for an unsteady state closed system, if a change in enthalpy is 5 J, and change in pressure is 10 Pa at constant volume 5 m3?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5 J",
            "b)\t50 J",
            "c)\t55 J",
            "d)\t85 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Q = 5 + 10*5 = 55 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 831,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred for an unsteady state closed system, if change in enthalpy is 15 J, and change in volume is 2 m3 at constant pressure 5 Pa?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t15 J",
            "c)\t20 J",
            "d)\t25 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Q = 15 + 2*5 = 25 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 832,
        "Question": "How long would it take for a reversible process to complete?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tInstant",
            "b)\tInfinite",
            "c)\tDepends on the process",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It takes infinite time for a reversible process to complete."
    },
    {
        "id": 833,
        "Question": "How long would it take for an irreversible process to complete?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tInstant",
            "b)\tFinite",
            "c)\tInfinite",
            "d)\tCannot say"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It takes a finite time for an irreversible process to complete."
    },
    {
        "id": 834,
        "Question": "Reversible process can be reversed by differential change in which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tTemperature",
            "b)\tPressure",
            "c)\tVolume",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Differential change in driving potential (dP, dV, dT, etc) can reverse a reversible process."
    },
    {
        "id": 835,
        "Question": "Which of the following a reversible process will involve?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tDissipative effects",
            "b)\tFriction",
            "c)\tEquilibrium transfer of energy",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Reversible process involves equilibrium transfer of energy."
    },
    {
        "id": 836,
        "Question": "Which of the following does both of the reversible and irreversible processes involve?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tIncrease molecular disorder",
            "b)\tDissipative effects",
            "c)\tFriction",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Both reversible and irreversible processes increases molecular disorder."
    },
    {
        "id": 837,
        "Question": "Free expansion of gas with frictionless piston is an example which process?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tReversible",
            "b)\tIrreversible",
            "c)\tCannot say",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Free expansion of gas is reversible process."
    },
    {
        "id": 838,
        "Question": "Free expansion of gas against piston having friction is an example of which process?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tReversible",
            "b)\tIrreversible",
            "c)\tCannot say",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Free expansion of gas against piston having friction is irreversible process."
    },
    {
        "id": 839,
        "Question": "Mixing of dissimilar substances is an example of which process?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tReversible",
            "b)\tIrreversible",
            "c)\tCannot say",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Mixing of dissimilar substances is an irreversible process."
    },
    {
        "id": 840,
        "Question": "Change in phase is an example of which process?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tReversible",
            "b)\tIrreversible",
            "c)\tCannot say",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Change in phase is an irreversible process."
    },
    {
        "id": 841,
        "Question": "Fluid flow through pipe is an example of which process?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tReversible",
            "b)\tIrreversible",
            "c)\tCannot say",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Fluid flow through pipe is an irreversible process."
    },
    {
        "id": 842,
        "Question": "What is the work done by saturated water which evaporates to 10 kPa atmosphere to form 1 m3 of water vapor?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 kJ",
            "b)\t-1 kJ",
            "c)\t10 kJ",
            "d)\t-10 kJ"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Work done = -p∆V = -10*1 = -10 kJ."
    },
    {
        "id": 843,
        "Question": "What is the work done by saturated water which evaporates to 20 kPa atmosphere to form 1.5 m3 of water vapor?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20 kJ",
            "b)\t-20 kJ",
            "c)\t30 kJ",
            "d)\t-30 kJ"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Work done = -p∆V = -20*1.5 = -30 kJ."
    },
    {
        "id": 844,
        "Question": "What is the work done by saturated water which evaporates to 1 kPa atmosphere to form 2 m3 of water vapor?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-2 kJ",
            "b)\t2 kJ",
            "c)\t-1 kJ",
            "d)\t1 kJ"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Work done = -p∆V = -1*2 = -2 kJ."
    },
    {
        "id": 845,
        "Question": "What is the work done by 0.1 m3 saturated ethanol which evaporates to 10 kPa atmosphere to form 1 m3 of water vapor?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t9 kJ",
            "b)\t-9 kJ",
            "c)\t10 kJ",
            "d)\t-10 kJ"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Work done = -p∆V = -10*(1 – 0.1) = -9 kJ."
    },
    {
        "id": 846,
        "Question": "What is the work done by 0.5 m3 saturated ethanol which evaporates to 20 kPa atmosphere to form 2 m3 of water vapor?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20 kJ",
            "b)\t-20 kJ",
            "c)\t30 kJ",
            "d)\t-30 kJ"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Work done = -p∆V = -20*(2 – 0.5) = -30 kJ."
    },
    {
        "id": 847,
        "Question": "Energy out and Energy in of a system are 10 J and 25 J respectively, what is the efficiency of the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t40%",
            "c)\t50%",
            "d)\t80%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Efficiency = 10/25*100 = 40%."
    },
    {
        "id": 848,
        "Question": "Energy out and Energy in of a system are 5 J and 25 J respectively, what is the efficiency of the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20%",
            "b)\t40%",
            "c)\t60%",
            "d)\t80%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Efficiency = 5/25*100 = 20%."
    },
    {
        "id": 849,
        "Question": "Energy out and Energy in of a system are 10 J and 20 J respectively, what is the efficiency of the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20%",
            "b)\t30%",
            "c)\t40%",
            "d)\t50%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Efficiency = 10/20*100 = 50%."
    },
    {
        "id": 850,
        "Question": "Energy out and Energy in of a system are 40 J and 25 J respectively, what is the efficiency of the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t40%",
            "b)\t80%",
            "c)\t160%",
            "d)\t200%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Efficiency = 40/25*100 = 160%."
    },
    {
        "id": 851,
        "Question": "Energy out and Energy in of a system are 15 J and 25 J respectively, what is the efficiency of the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t40%",
            "b)\t60%",
            "c)\t80%",
            "d)\t110%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Efficiency = 15/25*100 = 60%."
    },
    {
        "id": 852,
        "Question": "What is the efficiency of the system, if the actual work output from the process is 10 J and work output for a reversible process is 40 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t25%",
            "c)\t40%",
            "d)\t65%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Efficiency = 10/40*100 = 25%."
    },
    {
        "id": 853,
        "Question": "What is the efficiency of the system, if the actual work output from the process is 20 J and work output for a reversible process is 25 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t20%",
            "c)\t40%",
            "d)\t80%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Efficiency = 20/25*100 = 80%."
    },
    {
        "id": 854,
        "Question": "What is the efficiency of the system, if the actual work output from the process is 15 J and work output for a reversible process is 20 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25%",
            "b)\t50%",
            "c)\t75%",
            "d)\t100%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Efficiency = 15/20*100 = 75%."
    },
    {
        "id": 855,
        "Question": "What is the efficiency of the system, if the actual work input from the process is 10 J and work input for a reversible process is 20 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20%",
            "b)\t50%",
            "c)\t100%",
            "d)\t200%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Efficiency = 20/10*100 = 200%."
    },
    {
        "id": 856,
        "Question": "What is the efficiency of the system, if the actual work input from the process is 20 J and work input for a reversible process is 25 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20%",
            "b)\t80%",
            "c)\t125%",
            "d)\t150%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Efficiency = 25/20*100 = 125%."
    },
    {
        "id": 857,
        "Question": "What is the efficiency of a heat engine with heat input 10 J and work output 7 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t30%",
            "b)\t70%",
            "c)\t100%",
            "d)\t140%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Efficiency = 7/10*100 = 70%."
    },
    {
        "id": 858,
        "Question": "What is the efficiency of a heat engine with heat input 20 J and work output 5 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25%",
            "b)\t50%",
            "c)\t75%",
            "d)\t100%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Efficiency = 5/20*100 = 25%."
    },
    {
        "id": 859,
        "Question": "What is the efficiency of a heat engine with heat input 5 J and work output 8 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t40%",
            "b)\t80%",
            "c)\t160%",
            "d)\t200%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Efficiency = 5/8*100 = 160%."
    },
    {
        "id": 860,
        "Question": "What is the coefficient of performance of a system, if its work input is 50 J and heat removed is 35 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t35%",
            "b)\t50%",
            "c)\t70%",
            "d)\t95%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Coefficient of performance = 35/50*100 = 70%."
    },
    {
        "id": 861,
        "Question": "What is the coefficient of performance of a system, if its work input is 75 J and heat removed is 45 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20%",
            "b)\t40%",
            "c)\t60%",
            "d)\t80%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Coefficient of performance = 45/75*100 = 60%."
    },
    {
        "id": 862,
        "Question": "Mechanical energy satisfy which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tCompletely Convertible",
            "b)\tNon-convertible",
            "c)\tPartially convertible",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Mechanical energy is completely convertible by an ideal engine."
    },
    {
        "id": 863,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an example of mechanical energy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tKinetic energy",
            "b)\tPotential energy",
            "c)\tInternal energy",
            "d)\tWork"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Internal energy is not a mechanical energy."
    },
    {
        "id": 864,
        "Question": "Which of the following allows complete conversion of mechanical energy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tFrictionless process",
            "b)\tDissipative process",
            "c)\tMixing of components",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A frictionless process is reversible so it allows complete conversion of mechanical energy."
    },
    {
        "id": 865,
        "Question": "Which process allows complete conversion of mechanical energy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tIrreversible",
            "b)\tReversible",
            "c)\tReversible & Irreversible",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Reversible process so it allows complete conversion of mechanical energy."
    },
    {
        "id": 866,
        "Question": "The mechanical energy balance is the product of the equation of motion and which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tMass",
            "b)\tVelocity",
            "c)\tVolume",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The mechanical energy balance is the product of the equation of motion and velocity."
    },
    {
        "id": 867,
        "Question": "Bernoulli equation is valid for which process?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tReversible",
            "b)\tIrreversible",
            "c)\tReversible & Irreversible",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Bernoulli equation is valid for the process in which loss of mechanical energy is zero, which is reversible."
    },
    {
        "id": 868,
        "Question": "What is the height difference of the water (density = 1000 Kg/m3), if the change in velocity is 2 m/s and change in pressure is 100 Pa?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.21 m",
            "b)\t0.42 m",
            "c)\t0.56 m",
            "d)\t0.84 m"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ∆h = (100/1000 + 22/2)/10 = 0.21 m."
    },
    {
        "id": 869,
        "Question": "What is the height difference of the water (density = 1000 Kg/m3), if the change in velocity is 10 m/s and change in pressure is 500 Pa?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1.01 m",
            "b)\t5.05 m",
            "c)\t10.1 m",
            "d)\t20.2 m"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ∆h = (500/1000 + 102/2)/10 = 5.05 m."
    },
    {
        "id": 870,
        "Question": "What is the height difference of the water (density = 1000 Kg/m3), if the change in velocity is 10 m/s and change in pressure is 1000 Pa?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1.4 m",
            "b)\t2.9 m",
            "c)\t4.2 m",
            "d)\t5.1 m"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ∆h = (1000/1000 + 102/2)/10 = 5.05 m."
    },
    {
        "id": 871,
        "Question": "What is the height difference of the water (density = 1000 Kg/m3), if the change in velocity is 6 m/s and change in pressure is 2000 Pa?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1.2",
            "b)\t2.0",
            "c)\t3.6",
            "d)\t4.4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ∆h = (2000/1000 + 62/2)/10 = 2.0 m."
    },
    {
        "id": 872,
        "Question": "What is the reversible work done if 5 m3 of an ideal gas is compressed isothermally from 1 Pa to 5 Pa?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4.41 J",
            "b)\t8.01 J",
            "c)\t10.20 J",
            "d)\t14.18 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: V2 = 1*5/5 = 1 m3, => W = –5∫1pdv = –5∫1 (5/v) dv = 5 ln5 = 8.04 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 873,
        "Question": "What is the reversible work done if 4 m3 of an ideal gas is compressed isothermally from 2 Pa to 8 Pa?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2.01 J",
            "b)\t6.11 J",
            "c)\t8.56 J",
            "d)\t11.09 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: V2 = 2*4/8 = 1 m3, => W = –4∫1pdv = –4∫1 (8/v) dv = 8 ln4 = 11.09 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 874,
        "Question": "What is the reversible work done if 8 m3 of an ideal gas is compressed isothermally from 4 Pa to 16 Pa?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12.48 J",
            "b)\t28.55 J",
            "c)\t44.36 J",
            "d)\t56.96 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: V2 = 8*4/16 = 2 m3, => W = –8∫2pdv = –8∫2 (32/v) dv = 32 ln4 = 44.36 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 875,
        "Question": "What is the reversible work done if 4 m3 of an ideal gas is compressed adiabatically pV1.5 = K from 2 Pa to 16 Pa?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4 J",
            "b)\t16 J",
            "c)\t24 J",
            "d)\t56 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: V2 = (2*41.5/16)1/1.5 = 1 m3, => W = –4∫1pdv = –4∫1 (16/v1.5) dv = 16 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 876,
        "Question": "What is the reversible work done if 4 m3 of an ideal gas is compressed adiabatically pV2.5 = K from 1 Pa to 32 Pa?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t18.6 J",
            "b)\t20.4 J",
            "c)\t24.6 J",
            "d)\t26.2 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: V2 = (1*42.5/32)1/2.5 = 1 m3, => W = –4∫1pdv = –4∫1 (32/v2.5) dv = 18.6 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 877,
        "Question": "A mixture contains 20% of A with Heat Capacity 10 J/oC and 80% of B with Heat Capacity 5 J/oC, what is the Heat Capacity of mixture?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t6 J/oC",
            "b)\t7 J/oC",
            "c)\t8 J/oC",
            "d)\t9 J/oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Heat capacity of mixture = 0.2*10 + 0.8*5 = 2 + 4 = 6 J/oC."
    },
    {
        "id": 878,
        "Question": "A mixture contains 40% of A with Heat Capacity 15 J/oC and 60% of B with Heat Capacity 10 J/oC, what is the Heat Capacity of mixture?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t11 J/oC",
            "b)\t12 J/oC",
            "c)\t13 J/oC",
            "d)\t14 J/oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Heat capacity of mixture = 0.4*15 + 0.6*10 = 6 + 6 = 12 J/oC."
    },
    {
        "id": 879,
        "Question": "A mixture contains 50% of A with Heat Capacity 10 J/oC and 50% of B with Heat Capacity 20 J/oC, what is the Heat Capacity of mixture?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12 J/oC",
            "b)\t15 J/oC",
            "c)\t17 J/oC",
            "d)\t18 J/oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Heat capacity of mixture = 0.5*10 + 0.5*20 = 15 J/oC."
    },
    {
        "id": 880,
        "Question": "A mixture contains 20% of A with Heat Capacity 25 J/oC, 30% of B with Heat Capacity 20 J/oC, and 50% of C with Heat Capacity 10 J/oC, what is the Heat Capacity of mixture?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J/oC",
            "b)\t14 J/oC",
            "c)\t16 J/oC",
            "d)\t20 J/oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Heat capacity of mixture = 0.2*25 + 0.3*20 + 0.5*10 = 16 J/oC."
    },
    {
        "id": 881,
        "Question": "A mixture contains 30% of A with Heat Capacity 10 J/oC, 30% of B with Heat Capacity 20 J/oC, and 40% of C with Heat Capacity 35 J/oC, what is the Heat Capacity of mixture?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t14 J/oC",
            "b)\t17 J/oC",
            "c)\t19 J/oC",
            "d)\t23 J/oC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Heat capacity of mixture = 0.3*10 + 0.3*20 + 0.4*35 = 23 J/oC."
    },
    {
        "id": 882,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy of a mixture having 10% of A with enthalpy 10 J, and 90% of B with enthalpy 20 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t15 J",
            "c)\t18 J",
            "d)\t19 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Heat capacity of mixture = 0.1*10 + 0.9*20 = 19 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 883,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy of a mixture having 20% of A with enthalpy 15 J, and 80% of B with enthalpy 25 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t17 J",
            "b)\t19 J",
            "c)\t23 J",
            "d)\t28 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Heat capacity of mixture = 0.2*15 + 0.8*25 = 23 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 884,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy of a mixture having 40% of A with enthalpy 50 J, and 60% of B with enthalpy 25 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t30 J",
            "b)\t35 J",
            "c)\t40 J",
            "d)\t45 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Heat capacity of mixture = 0.4*50 + 0.6*25 = 35 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 885,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy of a mixture having 20% of A with enthalpy 20 J, 30% of B with enthalpy 40 J, and 50% of C with enthalpy 20 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t26 J",
            "b)\t29 J",
            "c)\t31 J",
            "d)\t34 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Heat capacity of mixture = 0.2*20 + 0.3*40 + 0.5*20 = 26 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 886,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy of a mixture having 10% of A with enthalpy 10 J, 30% of B with enthalpy 30 J, and 60% of C with enthalpy 25 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t21 J",
            "b)\t25 J",
            "c)\t27 J",
            "d)\t28 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Heat capacity of mixture = 0.1*10 + 0.3*30 + 0.6*25 = 1 + 9 + 15 = 25 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 887,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy change of solution if the enthalpy change of solute is 10 J, and enthalpy of solvent is 15 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t15 J",
            "c)\t25 J",
            "d)\t40 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ∆Hsolution = ∆Hsolute +∆Hsolvent = 10 + 15 = 25 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 888,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy change of 8 mole solution if the enthalpy change of 5 mole solute is 10 J/mole, and enthalpy of 2 mole solvent is 15 J/mole?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J/mole",
            "b)\t12 J/mole",
            "c)\t13 J/mole",
            "d)\t15 J/mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ∆Hsolution = ∆Hsolute +∆Hsolvent, => ∆Hsolution = (10*5 + 15*2)/8 = 10 J/mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 889,
        "Question": "What is the heat evolved when a gaseous solute is mixed with liquid solvent?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tHeat of solution",
            "b)\tHeat of mixing",
            "c)\tHeat of dissolution",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When Gas is mixed with liquid the heat evolved is called heat of solution."
    },
    {
        "id": 890,
        "Question": "What is the heat evolved when a liquid solute is mixed with liquid solvent?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tHeat of solution",
            "b)\tHeat of mixing",
            "c)\tHeat of dissolution",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When liquid is mixed with liquid the heat evolved is called heat of mixing."
    },
    {
        "id": 891,
        "Question": "Heat of solution of a mixture is 10 J, what is the heat dissolution?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-10 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t0",
            "d)\tCannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Heat of dissolution = – Heat of solution = -10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 892,
        "Question": "What is the heat of solution in the energy balance?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tHeat of dissolution",
            "b)\tHeat of reaction",
            "c)\tHeat of formation",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Heat of solution in the energy balance is the heat of reaction."
    },
    {
        "id": 893,
        "Question": "What is required in the calculation of heat of reaction in the energy balance of mixing?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tHeat of formation",
            "b)\tSensible Heat",
            "c)\tLatent heat",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Heat of formation is required in the calculation of heat of reaction in the energy balance of mixing."
    },
    {
        "id": 894,
        "Question": "How is the graph of the heat of solution and dilution?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tStraight Line",
            "b)\tCurve with finite heat of solution at infinite dilution",
            "c)\tCurve with Infinite heat of solution at infinite dilution",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Heat of solution is a finite curve at infinite dilution."
    },
    {
        "id": 895,
        "Question": "Which of the following is required for the calculation of heat of reaction in the energy balance?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tHeat of solution at reference state",
            "b)\tHeat of dissolution at reference state",
            "c)\tHeat of formation",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Heat of solution at reference state, Heat of dissolution at reference state and heat of formation all are required in the calculation of Heat of reaction."
    },
    {
        "id": 896,
        "Question": "What is the heat of dissolution if the heat of reaction is 10 J in the energy balance?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-10 J",
            "b)\t10 J",
            "c)\t0",
            "d)\tCannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Heat of dissolution = – Heat of solution = – Heat of reaction = -10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 897,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred from the system if the output sensible heat is 10 J, input sensible heat is 15 J, and heat of solution is 20 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t15 J",
            "c)\t20 J",
            "d)\t25 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Q = ∆Hout,sensible – ∆Hin,sensible + ∆Hsolution = 10 – 15 + 20 = 15 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 898,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred from the system if the output sensible heat is 5 J, input sensible heat is 25 J, and heat of solution is 20 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t10 J",
            "d)\t15 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Q = ∆Hout,sensible – ∆Hin,sensible + ∆Hsolution = 5 – 15 + 20 = 15 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 899,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred from the system if the output sensible heat is 5 J, input sensible heat is 20 J, and heat of solution is 10 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-10 J",
            "b)\t-5 J",
            "c)\t0",
            "d)\t10 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Q = ∆Hout,sensible – ∆Hin,sensible + ∆Hsolution = 5 – 20 + 10 = -5 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 900,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred from 5 mole of the system if the output sensible heat is 1 J/mole, input sensible heat is 3 J/mole, and heat of solution is 4 J/mole?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t10 J",
            "d)\t20 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Q = ∆Hout,sensible – ∆Hin,sensible + ∆Hsolution = 5*(1 – 3 + 4) = 10 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 901,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred from 2 mole of the system if the output sensible heat is 3 J/mole, input sensible heat is 2 J/mole, and heat of solution is 2 J/mole?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 J",
            "b)\t3 J",
            "c)\t5 J",
            "d)\t6 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Q = ∆Hout,sensible – ∆Hin,sensible + ∆Hsolution = 2*(3 – 2 + 2) = 6 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 902,
        "Question": "Enthalpy-Concentration diagram represents which type of solution?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tBinary",
            "b)\tTertiary",
            "c)\tQuaternary",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Enthalpy-Concentration diagram represents binary solutions."
    },
    {
        "id": 903,
        "Question": "What is the final enthalpy of the solution made by mixing 100 grams of 10% NaOH having enthalpy 40 J with 300 grams of 90% NaOH having enthalpy 20 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t15 J",
            "c)\t25 J",
            "d)\t40 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Final enthalpy = 0.25*40 + 0.75*20 = 10 + 15 = 25 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 904,
        "Question": "What is the final enthalpy of the solution made by mixing 10 grams of solution A having enthalpy 10 J with 40 grams of solution B having enthalpy 30 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t14 J",
            "b)\t18 J",
            "c)\t22 J",
            "d)\t26 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Final enthalpy = 0.2*10 + 0.8*30 = 26 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 905,
        "Question": "What is the final enthalpy of the solution made by mixing 20 grams of solution A having enthalpy 5 J with 5 grams of solution B having enthalpy 10 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 J",
            "b)\t4 J",
            "c)\t6 J",
            "d)\t7 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Final enthalpy = 0.8*5 + 0.2*10 = 4 + 2 = 6 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 906,
        "Question": "What is the final enthalpy of the solution made by mixing 5 grams of solution A having enthalpy 20 J with 15 grams of solution B having enthalpy 40 J?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t20 J",
            "c)\t25 J",
            "d)\t35 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Final enthalpy = 0.25*20 + 0.75*40 = 5 + 30 = 35 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 907,
        "Question": "What is the specific humidity, if the mass of water is 10 g and mass of bone dry air is 20 g?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t30%",
            "c)\t50%",
            "d)\t80%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: H = 10/20*100 = 50%."
    },
    {
        "id": 908,
        "Question": "What is the specific humidity, if the mass of water is 15 g and mass of bone dry air is 25 g?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t30%",
            "c)\t40%",
            "d)\t60%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Specific humidity = 15/25*100 = 60%."
    },
    {
        "id": 909,
        "Question": "What is the specific humidity, if pressure of water is 5 atm and total pressure is 10 atm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25%",
            "b)\t50%",
            "c)\t75%",
            "d)\t100%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Specific humidity = 5/(10 – 5)*100 = 100%."
    },
    {
        "id": 910,
        "Question": "What is the specific humidity, if pressure of water is 2 atm and total pressure is 12 atm?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20%",
            "b)\t40%",
            "c)\t50%",
            "d)\t80%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Specific humidity = 2/(12 – 2)*100 = 20%."
    },
    {
        "id": 911,
        "Question": "What is the specific humidity, if moles of water are 4 and total moles are 5?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20%",
            "b)\t80%",
            "c)\t200%",
            "d)\t400%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Specific Humidity = 4/(5 – 4)*100 = 400%."
    },
    {
        "id": 912,
        "Question": "What is the humid heat of a mixture of air (CP = 10 J) with water vapor (CP = 20 J), if the humidity is 25%?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t15 J",
            "c)\t20 J",
            "d)\t25 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: CS = 10 + 20*0.25 = 15 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 913,
        "Question": "What is the humid heat of a mixture of air (CP = 20 J) with water vapor (CP = 30 J), if the humidity is 40%?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t24 J",
            "b)\t32 J",
            "c)\t38 J",
            "d)\t44 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: CS = 20 + 30*0.4 = 32 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 914,
        "Question": "What is the humid heat of a mixture of air (CP = 10 J) with water vapor (CP = 15 J), if the humidity is 40%?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t16 J",
            "b)\t20 J",
            "c)\t24 J",
            "d)\t32 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: CS = 10 + 15*0.4 = 16 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 915,
        "Question": "What is the humid heat of a mixture of air (CP = 10 J) with water vapor (CP = 15 J), if the humidity is 60%?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t14 J",
            "c)\t19 J",
            "d)\t23 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: CS = 10 + 15*0.6 = 19 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 916,
        "Question": "What is the humid heat of a mixture of air (CP = 10 J) with water vapor (CP = 25 J), if the humidity is 20%?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t15 J",
            "b)\t20 J",
            "c)\t25 J",
            "d)\t30 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: CS = 10 + 25*0.2 = 15 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 917,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the summation of a volume of 1 Kg of dry air and the water vapor in the air?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tHumid volume",
            "b)\tPartial volume",
            "c)\tDry volume",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Humid volume is the summation of a volume of 1 Kg of dry air and the water vapor in the air."
    },
    {
        "id": 918,
        "Question": "What is the humid volume of the system at 100oF with humidity 20%?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t18.6 ft3/lb",
            "b)\t22.4 ft3/lb",
            "c)\t26.5 ft3/lb",
            "d)\t29.4 ft3/lb"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: V = (0.73T + 336)(1/29 + H/18) = (0.73*100 + 336)(1/29 + 0.2/18) = 18.6 ft3/lb."
    },
    {
        "id": 919,
        "Question": "What is the humid volume of the system at 200oF with humidity 40%?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t14.2 ft3/lb",
            "b)\t23.4 ft3/lb",
            "c)\t29.5 ft3/lb",
            "d)\t31.6 ft3/lb"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: V = (0.73*200 + 336)(1/29 + 0.4/18) = 31.6 ft3/lb."
    },
    {
        "id": 920,
        "Question": "What is the humid volume of the system at 150oF with humidity 50%?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t12.4 ft3/lb",
            "b)\t19.5 ft3/lb",
            "c)\t27.7 ft3/lb",
            "d)\t36.1 ft3/lb"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: V = (0.73*150 + 336)(1/29 + 0.5/18) = 27.7 ft3/lb."
    },
    {
        "id": 921,
        "Question": "What is the humid volume of the system at 300oF with humidity 30%?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t15.5 ft3/lb",
            "b)\t28.4 ft3/lb",
            "c)\t39.8 ft3/lb",
            "d)\t55.2 ft3/lb"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: V = (0.73*300 + 336)(1/29 + 0.3/18) = 28.4 ft3/lb."
    },
    {
        "id": 922,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the humidity chart?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tPsychrometric chart",
            "b)\tPsychometric chart",
            "c)\tPsychological chart",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Humidity chart is also called a Psychrometric chart."
    },
    {
        "id": 923,
        "Question": "Humidity chart relates which of the following balances?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tMomentum and energy balance",
            "b)\tMaterial and energy balance",
            "c)\tMaterial and momentum balance",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Humidity chart relates material and energy balance."
    },
    {
        "id": 924,
        "Question": "In the humidity chart, what does the horizontal axis represent?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tAir temperature",
            "b)\tDry-Bulb temperature",
            "c)\tWet-Bulb temperature",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The horizontal axis of humidity chart is dry-bulb temperature."
    },
    {
        "id": 925,
        "Question": "Wet-bulb temperature is based on the equilibrium between rates of energy transfer to the bulb and which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tEvaporation of water",
            "b)\tSaturation of water",
            "c)\tFreezing of water",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Wet-bulb temperature is based on the equilibrium between rates of energy transfer to the bulb and evaporation of water."
    },
    {
        "id": 926,
        "Question": "To plot the web-bulb line one information is wet-bulb temperature, what can be the other information?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tRelative humidity",
            "b)\tDry-bulb temperature",
            "c)\tHumidity",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Relative humidity, Dry-bulb temperature, or Humidity any of these can be the other information."
    },
    {
        "id": 927,
        "Question": "Which of the following is also called adiabatic cooling?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tHumidification",
            "b)\tHumidity",
            "c)\tHumid temperature",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Humidification is also called adiabatic cooling."
    },
    {
        "id": 928,
        "Question": "What is the humidity at the point of intersection of the dew point curve and wet-bulb line?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tDry-bulb Humidity",
            "b)\tWet-bulb Humidity",
            "c)\tSpecific Humidity",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The humidity at the point of intersection of the dew point curve and wet-bulb line is called the wet-bulb humidity."
    },
    {
        "id": 929,
        "Question": "What is the heat transferred from the system in the humidification process?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tPositive",
            "b)\tNegative",
            "c)\tZero",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Humidification is the adiabatic cooling process which means no heat exchange."
    },
    {
        "id": 930,
        "Question": "What happens to water in the humidification process?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tEvaporates",
            "b)\tFreezes",
            "c)\tSaturated",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Water evaporates during the humidification process."
    },
    {
        "id": 931,
        "Question": "What is the temperature of the point of intersection of adiabatic cooling line and specific humid volume line?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tWet-bulb temperature",
            "b)\tDry-bulb temperature",
            "c)\tDew point temperature",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The temperature of the point of intersection of adiabatic cooling line and specific humid volume line is the dry-bulb temperature."
    },
    {
        "id": 932,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy change of the mixture if the enthalpy change of air is 10 J, enthalpy change of water vapor is 15 J, and the humidity is 40%?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10 J",
            "b)\t12 J",
            "c)\t14 J",
            "d)\t16 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ∆H = ∆Hair + ∆Hwater(h) = 10 + 15*0.4 = 16 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 933,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy change of 15oC system if the heat capacity of air at 20oC is 10 J/oC and heat capacity of water vapor at 20oC is 20 J/oC, enthalpy of vaporization is 20 J, and the humidity is 50%?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t50 J",
            "b)\t60 J",
            "c)\t80 J",
            "d)\t110 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ∆H = 10(20 – 15) + 0.5*[20(20 – 15) + 20] = 50 + 60 = 110 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 934,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy change of 10oC system if the heat capacity of air at 20oC is 5 J/oC and heat capacity of water vapor at 20oC is 15 J/oC, enthalpy of vaporization is 10 J, and the humidity is 40%?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t58 J",
            "b)\t84 J",
            "c)\t114 J",
            "d)\t135 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ∆H = 5(20 – 10) + 0.4*[15(20 – 10) + 10] = 50 + 64 = 114 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 935,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy change of 20oC system if the heat capacity of air at 25oC is 5 J/oC and heat capacity of water vapor at 25oC is 10 J/oC, enthalpy of vaporization is 10 J, and the humidity is 20%?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25 J",
            "b)\t37 J",
            "c)\t44 J",
            "d)\t51 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ∆H = 5(25 – 20) + 0.2*[10(25 – 20) + 10] = 25 + 12 = 37 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 936,
        "Question": "What is the enthalpy change of 30oC system if the heat capacity of air at 38oC is 5 J/oC and heat capacity of water vapor at 38oC is 10 J/oC, enthalpy of vaporization is 10 J, and the humidity is 60%?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t14 J",
            "b)\t39 J",
            "c)\t65 J",
            "d)\t94 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ∆H = 5(38 – 30) + 0.6*[10(38 – 30) + 10] = 40 + 54 = 94 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 937,
        "Question": "What is the work of drying process?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tDecreases the moisture content",
            "b)\tVaporizes water",
            "c)\tIncreases the moisture content",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Drying decreases the moisture content of air."
    },
    {
        "id": 938,
        "Question": "What is the work of the humidification process?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tVaporization",
            "b)\tFreezing",
            "c)\tCondensing",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Humidification vaporizes liquid water to moist air."
    },
    {
        "id": 939,
        "Question": "In condensation, moist air is cooled below its which temperature?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tDew-point temperature",
            "b)\tDry-bulb temperature",
            "c)\tWet-bulb temperature",
            "d)\tSaturation temperature"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In condensation, moist air is cooled below its saturation temperature."
    },
    {
        "id": 940,
        "Question": "What is added to the moist air in the combustion process?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tWater",
            "b)\tCarbon dioxide",
            "c)\tOxygen",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Water is added to the moist air in the combustion process."
    },
    {
        "id": 941,
        "Question": "In air conditioning process, what has to be done first to the moist air?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tHeating",
            "b)\tCooling",
            "c)\tHeating & Cooling",
            "d)\tNone of mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In air conditioning process, moist air is heated and then cooled."
    },
    {
        "id": 942,
        "Question": "Enthalpy of air is 15 J and enthalpy of water vapor is 20 J, if the total enthalpy of the system is 20 J, what is the humidity of the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t25%",
            "b)\t50%",
            "c)\t75%",
            "d)\t100%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: 20 = 15 + 20*H, => H = 0.25 = 25%."
    },
    {
        "id": 943,
        "Question": "Enthalpy of air is 5 J and enthalpy of water vapor is 10 J, if the total enthalpy of the system is 25 J, what is the humidity of the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t50%",
            "b)\t100%",
            "c)\t150%",
            "d)\t200%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: 25 = 5 + 10*H, => H = 2, => H = 200%."
    },
    {
        "id": 944,
        "Question": "Enthalpy of air is 10 J and enthalpy of water vapor is 15 J, if the total enthalpy of the system is 25 J, what is the humidity of the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t20%",
            "b)\t50%",
            "c)\t100%",
            "d)\t180%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: 25 = 10 + 15*H, => H = 1, => H = 100%."
    },
    {
        "id": 945,
        "Question": "Enthalpy of air is 15 J and enthalpy of water vapor is 20 J, if the total enthalpy of the system is 25 J, what is the humidity of the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t50%",
            "c)\t100%",
            "d)\t200%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 25 = 15 + 20*H, => H = 0.5, => H = 50%."
    },
    {
        "id": 946,
        "Question": "Enthalpy of air is 20 J and enthalpy of water vapor is 6 J, if the total enthalpy of the system is 23 J, what is the humidity of the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t10%",
            "b)\t20%",
            "c)\t40%",
            "d)\t50%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: 23 = 20 + 6*H, => H = 0.5, => H = 50%."
    },
    {
        "id": 947,
        "Question": "The humidity at dry-bulb temperature of 20oC is 40% and the humidity at dry-bulb temperature of 25oC is 25%, what is the slope of adiabatic cooling line?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0.03",
            "b)\t-0.03",
            "c)\t0.05",
            "d)\t-0.05"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Slope of adiabatic cooling line = (0.4 – 0.25)/(20 – 25) = -0.03."
    },
    {
        "id": 948,
        "Question": "The humidity at dry-bulb temperature of 23oC is 30% and the humidity at dry-bulb temperature of 28oC is 25%, what is the slope of adiabatic cooling line?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-0.01",
            "b)\t-0.02",
            "c)\t-0.03",
            "d)\t-0.05"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Slope of adiabatic cooling line = (0.3 – 0.25)/(23 – 28) = -0.01."
    },
    {
        "id": 949,
        "Question": "The humidity at dry-bulb temperature of 20oC is 30% and the humidity at dry-bulb temperature of 22oC is 24%, what is the slope of adiabatic cooling line?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-0.01",
            "b)\t-0.02",
            "c)\t-0.03",
            "d)\t-0.05"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Slope of adiabatic cooling line = (0.3 – 0.24)/(20 – 22) = -0.03."
    },
    {
        "id": 950,
        "Question": "The humidity at dry-bulb temperature of 20oC is 10% and the humidity at dry-bulb temperature of 23oC is 4%, what is the slope of adiabatic cooling line?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-0.01",
            "b)\t-0.02",
            "c)\t-0.03",
            "d)\t-0.05"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Slope of adiabatic cooling line = (0.1 – 0.04)/(20 – 23) = -0.02."
    },
    {
        "id": 951,
        "Question": "The humidity at dry-bulb temperature of 20oC is 12% and the humidity at dry-bulb temperature of 23oC is 3%, what is the slope of adiabatic cooling line?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-0.01",
            "b)\t-0.02",
            "c)\t-0.03",
            "d)\t-0.05"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Slope of adiabatic cooling line = (0.12 – 0.03)/(20 – 23) = -0.03."
    },
    {
        "id": 952,
        "Question": "What are the number of degrees of freedom if the number of variables and number of equations are 10 and 8 respectively?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2",
            "b)\t8",
            "c)\t10",
            "d)\t18"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Number of degrees of freedom = 10 – 8 = 2."
    },
    {
        "id": 953,
        "Question": "What are the number of degrees of freedom if the number of variables and number of equations are 15 and 10 respectively?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5",
            "b)\t10",
            "c)\t15",
            "d)\t25"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Number of degrees of freedom = 15 – 10 = 5."
    },
    {
        "id": 954,
        "Question": "What are the number of degrees of freedom if the number of variables and number of equations are 15 and 5 respectively?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t5",
            "b)\t10",
            "c)\t15",
            "d)\t20"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Number of degrees of freedom = 15 – 5 = 10."
    },
    {
        "id": 955,
        "Question": "What are the number of degrees of freedom if the number of variables and number of equations are 18 and 7 respectively?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t7",
            "b)\t9",
            "c)\t11",
            "d)\t15"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Number of degrees of freedom = 18 – 7 = 11."
    },
    {
        "id": 956,
        "Question": "What are the number of degrees of freedom if the number of variables and number of equations are 21 and 9 respectively?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t7",
            "b)\t9",
            "c)\t10",
            "d)\t12"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Number of degrees of freedom = 21 – 9 = 12."
    },
    {
        "id": 957,
        "Question": "Degrees of freedom calculation treat which kind of variables?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tIntensive",
            "b)\tExtensive",
            "c)\tBoth",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Degrees of freedom calculation treat intensive variables."
    },
    {
        "id": 958,
        "Question": "Which of the following cannot be treated as a variable for degrees of freedom calculation?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tTemperature",
            "b)\tPressure",
            "c)\tVolume",
            "d)\tWork"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Since Volume is an extensive variable, it cannot be treated as a variable for degrees of freedom calculation."
    },
    {
        "id": 959,
        "Question": "Which of the following cannot be treated as a variable for degrees of freedom calculation?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tSpecific enthalpies",
            "b)\tHeat",
            "c)\tExtent of reaction",
            "d)\tEntropy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Since entropy is an extensive variable, it cannot be treated as a variable for degrees of freedom calculation."
    },
    {
        "id": 960,
        "Question": "What are the number of variables associated with a process stream, if the number of species in the stream are 2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Nv = Nsp + 2 = 2 + 2 = 4."
    },
    {
        "id": 961,
        "Question": "What are the number of compositions associated with a process stream, if the number of species in the stream are 2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Number of compositions = Nsp – 1 = 2 – 1 = 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 962,
        "Question": "What is the number of compositions associated with a process stream, if the number of species in the stream is 4?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t2",
            "c)\t3",
            "d)\t4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Number of compositions = Nsp – 1 = 4 – 1 = 3."
    },
    {
        "id": 963,
        "Question": "What are the number of variables associated with a process stream, if the number of species in the stream are 5?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1",
            "b)\t3",
            "c)\t5",
            "d)\t7"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Nv = Nsp + 2 = 5 + 2 = 7."
    },
    {
        "id": 964,
        "Question": "What are the number of equations associated with 3 process stream, if the number of species in the stream are 2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t3",
            "b)\t4",
            "c)\t6",
            "d)\t12"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Number of equations = 3(2 + 2) = 12."
    },
    {
        "id": 965,
        "Question": "What are the number of equations associated with 2 process stream, if the number of species in the stream are 3?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2",
            "b)\t3",
            "c)\t5",
            "d)\t10"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Number of equations = 2(3 + 2) = 10."
    },
    {
        "id": 966,
        "Question": "What are the number of equations associated with 4 process stream, if the number of species in the stream are 2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t4",
            "b)\t8",
            "c)\t16",
            "d)\t24"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Number of equations = 4(2 + 2) = 12."
    },
    {
        "id": 967,
        "Question": "What are the solution of appropriate process material and energy balances?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tFlow sheeting",
            "b)\tFlow processing",
            "c)\tFlow Solving",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Flow sheeting is the solution of appropriate process material and energy balances."
    },
    {
        "id": 968,
        "Question": "What is the computer code used in flow sheeting?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tProcess simulator",
            "b)\tProcess settler",
            "c)\tProcess developer",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Process simulator is the computer code used in flow sheeting."
    },
    {
        "id": 969,
        "Question": "What is the fundamental of the flow sheeting codes?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tCalculation of mass balance",
            "b)\tCalculation of momentum balance",
            "c)\tCalculation of force balance",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Calculation of mass balance is the fundamental of flow sheeting codes."
    },
    {
        "id": 970,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not found in process simulators?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tHeat exchangers",
            "b)\tCompressors",
            "c)\tSplitters",
            "d)\tNone of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Heat exchangers, Compressors, Splitters all are found in process simulators."
    },
    {
        "id": 971,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a feature of process simulator?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tEquipment sizing functions",
            "b)\tImport and export data",
            "c)\tScheduling of batch operations",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: All the options are the features of process simulator."
    },
    {
        "id": 972,
        "Question": "For solving a process simulation which of the following is required?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tMaterial balances",
            "b)\tEquilibrium relations",
            "c)\tEnergy balances",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: All the options are required for solving process simulator."
    },
    {
        "id": 973,
        "Question": "What does the interconnections between the unit modules represent?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tInformation flow",
            "b)\tMaterial flow",
            "c)\tEnergy flow",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The interconnections between the unit modules represents all of the options."
    },
    {
        "id": 974,
        "Question": "The interconnection equations are for which model?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\tMixing",
            "b)\tSplitting",
            "c)\tProcess",
            "d)\tAll of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Mixing model is for interconnection equations."
    },
    {
        "id": 975,
        "Question": "The input mass in a process simulator is 10 Kg, what will be the output mass?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t5 Kg",
            "c)\t8 Kg",
            "d)\t10 Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Mass balance, product mass = feed mass = 10 Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 976,
        "Question": "The input mass in a process simulator is 5 Kg, what will be the output mass?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t0",
            "b)\t5 Kg",
            "c)\t8 Kg",
            "d)\t10 Kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Mass balance, product mass = feed mass = 5 Kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 977,
        "Question": "The feed of a process simulator is 10 J, the heat input is 5 J, and the work performed is 3 J, what will be the product enthalpy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 J",
            "b)\t5 J",
            "c)\t8 J",
            "d)\t12 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Energy balance, H = 10 + 5 – 3 = 12 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 978,
        "Question": "The feed of a process simulator is 15 J, the heat input is 8 J, and the work performed is 10 J, what will be the product enthalpy?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t-3 J",
            "b)\t13 J",
            "c)\t15 J",
            "d)\t17 J"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Energy balance, H = 15 + 8 – 10 = 13 J."
    },
    {
        "id": 979,
        "Question": "The feed of a process simulator is 10 mole with enthalpy 2 J/mole, the heat input is 15 J, and the work performed is 10 J, what will be the product enthalpy if mole of the product are 5?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t2 J/mole",
            "b)\t3 J/mole",
            "c)\t4 J/mole",
            "d)\t5 J/mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Energy balance, 5*H = 10*2 + 15 – 10 = 25, => H = 5 J/mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 980,
        "Question": "The feed of a process simulator is 5 mole with enthalpy 3 J/mole, the heat input is 15 J, and the work performed is 20 J, what will be the product enthalpy if a mole of the product are 2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 J/mole",
            "b)\t2 J/mole",
            "c)\t3 J/mole",
            "d)\t5 J/mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Energy balance, 2*H = 5*3 + 15 – 20 = 10, => H = 5 J/mole."
    },
    {
        "id": 981,
        "Question": "The feed of a process simulator is 2 mole with enthalpy 4 J/mole, the heat input is 6 J, and the work performed is 10 J, what will be the product enthalpy if a mole of the product are 2?",
        "Options": [
            "a)\t1 J/mole",
            "b)\t2 J/mole",
            "c)\t3 J/mole",
            "d)\t5 J/mole"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Energy balance, 2*H = 2*4 + 6 – 10 = 4, => H = 2 J/mole."
    }
]